<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Identosphere Identity Blogcatcher: Personal</title>
    <link>https://identosphere.com</link>
    <description>Personal blogs of individuals working in decentralized identity.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>llm-gemini 0.9</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/22/llm-gemini/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-gemini 0.9 
This new release of my llm-gemini plugin adds support for two new experimental models: 
 
 learnlm-1.5-pro-experimental is &quot;an experimental task-specific model that has been trained to align with learning science principles when following system instructions for teaching and learning use cases&quot; - more here. 
 
 gemini-2.0-flash-thinking-exp-01-21 is a brand new version of the Gemin</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 04:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T04:32:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run DeepSeek R1 or V3 with MLX Distributed</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/22/mlx-distributed/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Run DeepSeek R1 or V3 with MLX Distributed 
Handy detailed instructions from Awni Hannun on running the enormous DeepSeek R1 or v3 models on a cluster of Macs using the distributed communication feature of Apple's MLX library. 
 DeepSeek R1 quantized to 4-bit requires 450GB in aggregate RAM, which can be achieved by a cluster of three 192 GB M2 Ultras ($16,797 will buy you three 192GB Apple M2 Ult</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 04:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T04:15:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six short video demos of LLM and Datasette projects</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/22/office-hours-demos/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Last Friday Alex Garcia and I hosted a new kind of Datasette Public Office Hours session, inviting members of the Datasette community to share short demos of projects that they had built. The session lasted just over an hour and featured demos from six different people. 
 We broadcast live on YouTube, but I've now edited the session into separate videos. These are listed below, along with project </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 02:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T02:09:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s developer tools roots</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/microsofts-developer-tools-roots</link>
      <description>Big Tech and startups, from the inside. Highly relevant for software engineers and managers, useful for those working in tech.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 17:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T17:24:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI mistakes are very different from human mistakes</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/21/ai-mistakes-are-very-different-from-human-mistakes/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> AI mistakes are very different from human mistakes 
An entertaining and informative read by Bruce Schneier and Nathan E. Sanders. 
 
 If you want to use an AI model to help with a business problem, it’s not enough to see that it understands what factors make a product profitable; you need to be sure it won’t forget what money is. 
 


     Tags: bruce-schneier, llms, ai, generative-ai </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 15:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T15:12:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Laurie Voss</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/21/laurie-voss/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Is what you're doing taking a large amount of text and asking the LLM to convert it into a smaller amount of text? Then it's probably going to be great at it. If you're asking it to convert into a roughly equal amount of text it will be so-so. If you're asking it to create more text than you gave it, forget about it.  
 — Laurie Voss 

     Tags: laurie-voss, llms, ai, generative-ai, rag </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 12:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T12:42:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andreessen and Horowitz’s Debrief On Their Fairshake PAC and Sunny Days Ahead For “Little Tech” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/20/andreessen-and-horowitzs-debrief-on-their-fairshake-pac-and-sunny-days-ahead-for-little-tech-under-trump/</link>
      <description>I took notes on Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz’s post-election discussion of their Fairshake pro-crypto Pac and the coming Trump presidency about two months ago, but set them aside and other topics took precedence. Given the rising craziness in the crypto space around the inauguration, I thought it was a good time to put them [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T03:58:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeking trans-friendly employers who sponsor visas</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/seeking-trans-friendly-employers-who-sponsor-visas</link>
      <description> 
   Nobody should have to move to another country to be themselves.  However, I’ve spoken to multiple people who feel they need to move away from the US in order to avoid harms caused by the new administration’s executive orders that target trans people. Exactly how to do this is sometimes opaque and feels difficult.  If you are actively hiring for positions in a company that is friendly to transg</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 02:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T02:50:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek-R1 and exploring DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-8B</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/20/deepseek-r1/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> DeepSeek are the Chinese AI lab who dropped the best currently available open weights LLM on Christmas day, DeepSeek v3. That model was trained in part using their unreleased R1 &quot;reasoning&quot; model. Today they've released R1 itself, along with a whole family of new models derived from that base. 
 There's a whole lot of stuff in the new release. 
 DeepSeek-R1-Zero appears to be the base model. It's </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T15:20:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Jack Clark</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/20/jack-clark/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  [Microsoft] said it plans in 2025 “to invest approximately $80 billion to build out AI-enabled datacenters to train AI models and deploy AI and cloud-based applications around the world.” 
 For comparison, the James Webb telescope cost $10bn, so Microsoft is spending eight James Webb telescopes in one year just on AI. 
 For a further comparison, people think the long-in-development ITER fusion re</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 14:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T14:19:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T07:34:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The next four years</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-next-four-years</link>
      <description> 
   The last time this man was in power we wound up with one of the largest civil rights movements ever conducted in the United States. There is so much light; so much bravery; so much fairness and equity and rebellion in so many. Those are the people I believe in. That's what I'm holding onto.  People who seek to strip the identities of vulnerable people, to deport people and break up families, t</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 05:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T05:05:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blame Game</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/19/the-blame-game/</link>
      <description>Twenty-third in the News Commons series Disaster coverage tends to go through four stages: Live reporting. TV stations stop all advertising and go into round-the-clock coverage. Radio stations drop the feeds from elsewhere and go wall-to-wall with live reports. Newspapers drop their paywalls. Coverage by the best of them ranges from good to heroic. As […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 17:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T17:08:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rogan Misses The Mark: How Zuck’s Misdirection On Gov’t Pressure Goes Unchallenged</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/rogan-misses-the-mark-how-zucks-misdirection-on-govt-pressure</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mike Masnick at TechDirt]  On Zuckerberg's claims about why he's changing Meta's fact-changing policy:   &quot;If you only remember two things about the government pressure campaign to influence Mark Zuckerberg’s content moderation decisions, make it these: Donald Trump directly threatened to throw Zuck in prison for the rest of his life, and just a couple months ago FCC Commission</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 15:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T15:36:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Is No Longer the Home of the Free Internet</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/america-is-no-longer-the-home-of-the-free-internet</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Ethan Zuckerman in The Atlantic]  I completely agree with the points Ethan makes here. The TikTok ban was a spectacular own-goal for all kinds of reasons. In particular:   &quot;[...] This is a depressing moment for anyone who cherishes American protections for speech and access to information. In 1965, while the Cold War shaped the U.S. national-security environment, the Supreme C</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 15:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T15:08:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So how, exactly, did blogging help my career?</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/so-how-exactly-did-blogging-help-my-career</link>
      <description> 
 I’ve written a few times about how blogging has been the single most important accelerant in my career. I mentioned this when I asked more of you to blog, in remarks about other peoples’ posts on blogging, and so on. But I’ve never actually explained how.  The arc of this journey is simple: I was a complete outsider with no money or connections, living in Scotland. Blogging allowed me to found t</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T14:04:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let’s talk about AI and end-to-end encryption</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/lets-talk-about-ai-and-end-to-end-encryption</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Matthew Green]  I think this is the most important discussion with respect to AI:   &quot;[...] I would say that AI is going to be the biggest privacy story of the decade. Not only will we soon be doing more of our compute off-device, but we’ll be sending a lot more of our private data. This data will be examined and summarized by increasingly powerful systems, producing relatively</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 04:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T04:20:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'm very interested to see how this plays out.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/very-interested-to-see-how-this-plays-out</link>
      <description> 

          
 </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 03:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T03:38:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Downloading every video for a TikTok account</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/19/til-downloading-every-video-for-a-tiktok-account/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> TIL: Downloading every video for a TikTok account 
TikTok may or may not be banned in the USA within the next 24 hours or so. I figured out a gnarly pattern for downloading every video from a specified account, using browser console JavaScript to scrape the video URLs and yt-dlp to fetch each video. As a bonus, I included a recipe for generating a Whisper transcript of every video with mlx-whisper</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 02:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-19T02:05:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek API Docs: Rate Limit</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/18/deepseek-api-docs-rate-limit/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> DeepSeek API Docs: Rate Limit 
This is surprising: DeepSeek offer the only hosted LLM API I've seen that doesn't implement rate limits: 
 
 DeepSeek API does NOT constrain user's rate limit. We will try out best to serve every request. 
 However, please note that when our servers are under high traffic pressure, your requests may take some time to receive a response from the server. 
 
 Want to ru</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 18:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T18:24:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From Red Teaming 100 Generative AI Products</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/18/lessons-from-red-teaming/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Lessons From Red Teaming 100 Generative AI Products 
New paper from Microsoft describing their top eight lessons learned red teaming (deliberately seeking security vulnerabilities in) 100 different generative AI models and products over the past few years. 
 
 The Microsoft AI Red Team (AIRT) grew out of pre-existing red teaming initiatives at the company and was officially established in 2018. At</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 18:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T18:13:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Dance, Oscillation, And Going “Inside”</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/18/trump-dance-oscillation-and-going-inside/</link>
      <description>In this morning’s video I somehow missed the fact that the inauguration coincides with MLK Day, which is an interesting sync with the “melanin as optical material” lens. I’m going to drop a few links to old blog posts that touch on the YMCA and “out of school time learning” as as well as my [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T17:06:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The Interview’: Curtis Yarvin Says Democracy is Done</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-interview-curtis-yarvin-says-democracy-is-done</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [David Marchese in The New York Times]  This profile of Curtis Yarvin in the New York Times (paywalled, probably for the best) is far softer than it should have been, with far less formal fact-checking. It is of the moment, though: this guy’s writing is highly influential to the political class that’s about to land in power, as well as to prominent VCs and other tech luminaries</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T14:59:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How extreme car dependency is driving Americans to unhappiness</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/how-extreme-car-dependency-is-driving-americans-to-unhappiness</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Oliver Milman in The Guardian]  Car culture isn't just physically bad for us, it affects us mentally too:   &quot;The car is firmly entrenched as the default, and often only, mode of transport for the vast majority of Americans, with more than nine in 10 households having at least one vehicle and 87% of people using their cars daily. Last year, a record 290m vehicles were operated </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T14:34:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ratify the Equal Rights Amendment already</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/ratify-the-equal-rights-amendment-already</link>
      <description> 
 If ever there was a litmus test about who to avoid, it’s the people who see the language of the Equal Rights Amendment in the 21st Century and think, “oh, that’s problematic”.  Here is the full text:  SECTION 1. Equality of rights under the law shall not be denied or abridged by the United States or by any State on account of sex.  SEC. 2. The Congress shall have the power to enforce, by appropr</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T13:38:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Don't Need More Cynics. We Need More Builders.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/we-dont-need-more-cynics-we-need-more-builders</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Joan Westenberg]  An absolutely spot-on call to action:   &quot;Cynicism is the cheap seats. It’s the fast food of intellectual positions. Anyone can point at something and say it’s broken, corrupt, or destined to fail. The real challenge? Building something better.  [...] Cynicism comes with hidden taxes. Every time we default to assuming the worst, we pay in missed opportunities,</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T15:09:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Thiel Dreams of Empire</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/peter-thiel-dreams-of-empire</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Dave Karpf at Tech Policy Press]  Peter Thiel and other tech oligarchs are seeking to weaponize US foreign policy as a way to enforce their corporate agendas:   &quot;Thiel is developing a blueprint for putting Big Tech’s policy agenda at the center of US foreign policy. Australia’s social media ban is bad for American social media companies. The European Union’s Digital Services A</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T14:18:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look Up Private School Demographics With ProPublica’s New Database</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/look-up-private-school-demographics-with-propublicas-new-database</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Sergio Hernández, Nat Lash, Brandon Roberts and Ken Schwencke at ProPublica]  Private schools in the US are much whiter than public schools. My colleagues over in the newsroom at ProPublica explored this data while illuminating the ongoing extent of segregation academies in the south:   &quot;Our analysis of that survey revealed, among other things, Amite County, Mississippi, where</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T12:42:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestalt, Quakers and Carbon Trading – Do You See Faces Or A Vase?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/17/gestalt-quakers-and-carbon-trading-do-you-see-faces-or-a-vase/</link>
      <description>In this video I draw connections between Gestalt theory and organizational development as applied to digital groupthink in the context of Christiana Figueres, a leader in the development of carbon trading, who trained at the Gestalt Institute of Cleveland. As a young woman, she attended Swarthmore College, a Quaker institution. The first wife of her [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T06:06:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Greg Brockman</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/16/greg-brockman/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Manual inspection of data has probably the highest value-to-prestige ratio of any activity in machine learning.  
 — Greg Brockman, OpenAI, Feb 2023 

     Tags: machine-learning, openai, ai </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 22:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T22:38:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting gwern</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/16/gwern/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  [...] much of the point of a model like o1 is not to deploy it, but to generate training data for the next model. Every problem that an o1 solves is now a training data point for an o3 (eg. any o1 session which finally stumbles into the right answer can be refined to drop the dead ends and produce a clean transcript to train a more refined intuition).  
 — gwern 

     Tags: o1, generative-ai, in</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T19:21:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Datasette Public Office Hours Application</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/16/datasette-public-office-hours/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Datasette Public Office Hours Application 
We are running another Datasette Public Office Hours event on Discord tomorrow (Friday 17th January 2025) at 2pm Pacific / 5pm Eastern / 10pm GMT / more timezones here. 
 The theme this time around is lightning talks - we're looking for 5-8 minute long talks from community members about projects they are working on or things they have built using the Data</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T18:38:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #120: What does Salesforce’s software engineering hiring freeze mean?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-120</link>
      <description>Also: how an hour-long GitHub outage is a reminder of the real cost of reliability, what Cloudflare’s recruiting statistics say about the job market, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T17:54:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving GitHub Issues (public preview)</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/16/evolving-github-issues/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Evolving GitHub Issues (public preview) 
GitHub just shipped the largest set of changes to GitHub Issues I can remember in a few years. As an Issues power-user this is directly relevant to me. 
 The big new features are sub-issues, issue types and boolean operators in search. 
 Sub-issues look to be a more robust formalization of the existing feature where you could create a - [ ] #123 Markdown li</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T17:41:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Alex Albert</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/16/alex-albert/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  We've adjusted prompt caching so that you now only need to specify cache write points in your prompts - we'll automatically check for cache hits at previous positions. No more manual tracking of read locations needed.  
 — Alex Albert, Anthropic 

     Tags: alex-albert, prompt-caching, anthropic, claude, generative-ai, ai, llms </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T16:14:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Is Laying the Narrative Groundwork for Trump’s Mass Deportations</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/meta-is-laying-the-narrative-groundwork-for-trumps-mass-deportations</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Joseph Cox at 404 Media]  Not just obeying in advance but actively collaborating:   &quot;Multiple speech and content moderation experts 404 Media spoke to drew some parallels between these recent changes and when Facebook contributed to a genocide in Myanmar in 2017, in which Facebook was used to spread anti-Rohingya hate and the country’s military ultimately led a campaign of mur</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T15:07:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100x Defect Tolerance: How Cerebras Solved the Yield Problem</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/16/cerebras-yield-problem/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> 100x Defect Tolerance: How Cerebras Solved the Yield Problem 
I learned a bunch about how chip manufacture works from this piece where Cerebras reveal some notes about how they manufacture chips that are 56x physically larger than NVIDIA's H100. 
 The key idea here is core redundancy: designing a chip such that if there are defects the end-product is still useful. This has been a technique for dec</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T00:38:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Coding Machine” at Meta with Michael Novati</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-coding-machine-at-meta</link>
      <description>In today’s episode, I’m joined by Michael Novati, Co-founder and CTO of Formation. Michael spent eight years at Meta, where he was recognized as the top code committer company-wide for several years.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T20:46:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Geoffrey Litt</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/15/geoffrey-litt/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Today's software ecosystem evolved around a central assumption that code is expensive, so it makes sense to centrally develop and then distribute at low marginal cost. 
 If code becomes 100x cheaper, the choices no longer make sense! Build-buy tradeoffs often flip. 
 The idea of an &quot;app&quot;—a hermetically sealed bundle of functionality built by a team trying to anticipate your needs—will no longer b</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T16:15:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make America More Like Europe (please)</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/make-america-more-like-europe-please</link>
      <description> 
 I realized some time ago that all the ways I want America to change just bring it closer to being Europe. Like, what if we had this can-do attitude and all the good parts without the guns and with universal healthcare, real education, unprocessed food without sugar in it, a real safety net, and integrated public transit instead of car culture.  Maybe the easier path is if we all, like, move to A</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T14:25:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T08:18:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT reveals the system prompt for ChatGPT Tasks</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/15/chatgpt-tasks/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> ChatGPT reveals the system prompt for ChatGPT Tasks 
OpenAI just started rolling out Scheduled tasks in ChatGPT, a new feature where you can say things like &quot;Remind me to write the tests in five minutes&quot; and ChatGPT will execute that prompt for you at the assigned time. 
 I just tried it and the reminder came through as an email (sent via MailChimp's Mandrill platform). I expect I'll get these as </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T01:40:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&quot;I have fired Meta as a client.&quot;</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/i-have-fired-meta-as-a-client</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mark Lemley on LinkedIn]  Meta's lawyer in its AI case has fired them as a client, and is not beating around the bush as to why:   &quot;I have struggled with how to respond to Mark Zuckerberg and Facebook's descent into toxic masculinity and Neo-Nazi madness. While I have thought about quitting Facebook, I find great value in the connections and friends I have here, and it doesn't</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 20:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T20:50:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Configuration Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/01/14/the-configuration-crisis/</link>
      <description>Perhaps, even though they are not themselves explainable, AIs can help us engineer explainable systems. But I’m not optimistic. It feels like we’re on a path to keep making systems harder for humans to configure, and we keep expanding our reliance on superhuman intelligence to do that for us. The Configuration Crisis and Developer Dependency … Continue reading The Configuration Crisis</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:23:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day An Evangelical Christian Convinced ChatGPT I Was A Hippy, Schwab-Aligned Sociopathic Magician</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/14/the-day-an-evangelical-christian-convinced-chatgpt-i-was-a-hippy-schwab-aligned-sociopathic-magician/</link>
      <description>What will come of large language models when they mirror unsettled psyches defined by religious hero complexes into the cloud? We do ourselves and future generations a profound disservice when we choose not to make time to comprehend and interrogate how emerging technologies and narrative flows are being deployed to steer psychological states individually and [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:00:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Facts Matter</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/14/how-facts-matter/</link>
      <description>Twenty-second in the News Commons series. Facts don’t matter, or they matter much less than people think—Daniel Kahnemann Facts don’t matter. What matters is how much we hate the person talking—Scott Adams But facts do matter when life and death are on the line. Or when one is recovering from a life-changing situation. To help […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T17:37:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-platform mobile development</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/cross-platform-mobile-development</link>
      <description>A deep dive into the most popular frameworks: React Native, Flutter, native-first, and web-based technologies, and how to pick the right approach</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T17:32:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US finalizes rule to effectively ban Chinese vehicles, which could include Polestar</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/us-finalizes-rule-to-effectively-ban-chinese-vehicles-which-could</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Andrew J. Hawkins at The Verge]  I think this is the wrong kind of protectionism:   &quot;The Biden administration finalized a new rule that would effectively ban all Chinese vehicles from the US under the auspices of blocking the “sale or import” of connected vehicle software from “countries of concern.” The rule could have wide-ranging effects on big automakers, like Ford and GM,</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T17:16:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simon Willison And SWYX Tell Us Where AI Is In 2025</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/14/where-ai-is-in-2025/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Simon Willison And SWYX Tell Us Where AI Is In 2025 
I recorded this podcast episode with Brian McCullough and swyx riffing off my Things we learned about LLMs in 2024 review. We also touched on some predictions for the future - this is where I learned from swyx that Everything Everywhere All at Once used generative AI (Runway ML) already. 
 The episode is also available on YouTube: 
  


      Ta</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T16:10:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Alex Komoroske</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/13/alex-komoroske/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  LLMs shouldn't help you do less thinking, they should help you do more thinking. They give you higher leverage. Will that cause you to be satisfied with doing less, or driven to do more?  
 — Alex Komoroske, Bits and bobs 

     Tags: llms, ai, generative-ai, alex-komoroske </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T22:55:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codestral 25.01</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/13/codestral-2501/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Codestral 25.01 
Brand new code-focused model from Mistral. Unlike the first Codestral this one isn't (yet) available as open weights. The model has a 256k token context - a new record for Mistral. 
 The new model scored an impressive joint first place with Claude 3.5 Sonnet and Deepseek V2.5 (FIM) on the Copilot Arena leaderboard.  
 Chatbot Arena announced Copilot Arena on 12th November 2024. Th</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T21:33:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/explaining-verifiable-credentials-and-open-badges-3-0-34ae898b98b2?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Part 2: Issuing&amp;nbsp;Badges  In part one of this series, we discussed how the trust model of Open Badges 3.0 differs from earlier versions. Credentials issued as Open Badges 3.0 are based on the W3C Verifiable Credentials data model which describes how claims made online can be&amp;nbsp;proven.  To explore this trust model, let’s explore the story of Olivia who has been taking classes at a local commu</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T15:28:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Our Feeds</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/free-our-feeds</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Free Our Feeds]  The non-profit social media foundation space is really heating up. Which is not a bad thing!  Enter Free our Feeds:   &quot;It will take independent funding and governance to turn Bluesky’s underlying tech—the AT Protocol—into something more powerful than a single app. We want to create an entire ecosystem of interconnected apps and different companies that have pe</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T14:22:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The people should own the town square</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-people-should-own-the-town-square</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mastodon]  Mastodon is growing up:   &quot;Simply, we are going to transfer ownership of key Mastodon ecosystem and platform components (including name and copyrights, among other assets) to a new non-profit organization, affirming the intent that Mastodon should not be owned or controlled by a single individual.  [...] We are in the process of a phased transition. First we are est</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T12:31:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Content Policy on the Social Web</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/content-policy-on-the-social-web</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Social Web Foundation]  The Social Web Foundation's statement about Meta's moderation changes is important:   &quot;Ideas matter, and history shows that online misinformation and harassment can lead to violence in the real world.  [...] Meta is one of many ActivityPub implementers and a supporter of the Social Web Foundation. We strongly encourage Meta’s executive and content teams</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T02:22:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ben Hylak</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/12/ben-hylak/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  I was using o1 like a chat model — but o1 is not a chat model. 
 If o1 is not a chat model — what is it? 
 I think of it like a “report generator.” If you give it enough context, and tell it what you want outputted, it’ll often nail the solution in one-shot.  
 — Ben Hylak 

     Tags: o1, generative-ai, openai, ai, llms </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T22:02:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DoJ releases its Tulsa race massacre report over 100 years after initial review</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/doj-releases-its-tulsa-race-massacre-report-over-100-years</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Adria R Walker at The Guardian]  A full century after the Bureau of Investigation blamed the Tulsa race massacre on Black men and claimed that the perpetrators didn't break the law, the DoJ has issued an update:   &quot;“The Tulsa race massacre stands out as a civil rights crime unique in its magnitude, barbarity, racist hostility and its utter annihilation of a thriving Black comm</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T17:36:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is anybody out there?</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/is-anybody-out-there.html</link>
      <description> Is blogging still a thing?  If you’re reading this, please comment or like it so I know.     I am, at heart, still the XDI Guy. My passion for robust, secure, and scalable distributed data management hasn’t waned. Building one of the first XDI implementations (shout-out to Markus Sabadello, who might have built the only other one), I learned a lot about the challenges and opportunities of distribu</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T16:20:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The indie web should be a universe of discovery</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-indie-web-should-be-a-universe-of-discovery</link>
      <description> 
   In Oxford, my hometown, the flagship Blackwell’s bookshop looks like any ordinary bookstore at ground level. But if you go down a set of stairs, you find yourself in&amp;nbsp;the Norrington Room: one of the largest rooms full of books in the world. The shelves expand out around you to encompass almost every possible subject: three miles of bookshelves, holding hundreds of thousands of books.  As i</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T15:22:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Ignorance Bliss?</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/is-ignorance-bliss</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Jared White]  I've been thinking about this paragraph since I read it:   &quot;In times past, we would worry about singular governmental officials such Joseph Goebbels becoming a master of propaganda for their cause. Today’s problem is massively scaled out in ways Goebbels could only dream of: now everyone can be their own Goebbels. Can someone please tell me what the difference is</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T15:05:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI – The Power and the Glory</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/12/generative-ai-the-power-and-the-glory/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Generative AI – The Power and the Glory 
Michael Liebreich's epic report for BloombergNEF on the current state of play with regards to generative AI, energy usage and data center growth. 
 I learned so much from reading this. If you're at all interested in the energy impact of the latest wave of AI tools I recommend spending some time with this article. 
 Just a few of the points that stood out to</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T01:51:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECDSAに対応したゼロ知識証明の論文がGoogleから出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/ecdsagoogle.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  AAMVAのモバイル運転免許証のガイドラインでも触れましたが、mdocやSD-JWTのリンク可能性へ対応するためには今後ゼロ知識証明が大切になります。  年末にGoogleの研究者が  Anonymous credentials from ECDSA  というタイトルでペーパーを出しています。  https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/2010    AIでイラスト生成すると色々とおかしなことになって面白いですねw    アブストラクトの中からポイントを抜粋すると、従来のBBS+では暗号スイートへの対応に関する要件が厳しかったのでレガシーで対応できるようにECDSAでもできるようにしたよ、ということのようですね。   Part of the difficulty arises because schemes in the literature,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T00:23:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Are Stories?</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/11/what-are-stories/</link>
      <description>Twenty-first in the New Commons series. Several generations ago, my pal Jerry and I were cutting a hole between the ceiling joists of a rented house in Durham, North Carolina. This was our first step toward installing a drop-down stairway to an attic space that had been closed since the house, a defunct parsonage for […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 23:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T23:54:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agents</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/11/agents/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Agents 
Chip Huyen's 8,000 word practical guide to building useful LLM-driven workflows that take advantage of tools. 
 Chip starts by providing a definition of &quot;agents&quot; to be used in the piece - in this case it's LLM systems that plan an approach and then run tools in a loop until a goal is achieved. I like how she ties it back to the classic Norvig &quot;thermostat&quot; model -  where an agent is &quot;anythi</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T17:50:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aviation vs. Fire</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/11/aviation-vs-fire/</link>
      <description>3:22pm—Hats off to Miles Archer for the links below, one of which goes here— —showing all the aircraft and their paths at once. You can start here at https://globe.adsbexchange.com/, which is kind of your slate that’s blank except for live aircraft over the Palisades Fire: Meanwhile all the media are reporting one home loss, in […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T16:52:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an open web that protects us from harm</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/building-an-open-web-that-protects-us-from-harm-40a95da1d82f?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s not enough to be neutral. We must be allies.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T15:58:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an open web that protects us from harm</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/building-an-open-web-that-protects-us-from-harm</link>
      <description> 
 We live in a world where right-wing nationalism is on the rise and many governments, including the incoming Trump administration, are promising mass deportations. Trump in particular has discussed building camps as part of mass deportations. This question used to feel more hypothetical than it does today.  Faced with this reality, it’s worth asking: who would stand by you if this kind of authori</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T15:58:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good, The Bad, And The Stupid In Meta’s New Content Moderation Policies</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-good-the-bad-and-the-stupid-in-metas-new</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mike Masnick in TechDirt]  Mark Zuckerberg is very obviously running scared from the incoming Trump administration:   &quot;Since the election, Zuckerberg has done everything he can possibly think of to kiss the Trump ring. He even flew all the way from his compound in Hawaii to have dinner at Mar-A-Lago with Trump, before turning around and flying right back to Hawaii. In the last</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T14:52:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI RAG with LlamaIndex, Local Embedding, and Ollama Llama 3.1 8b</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-rag-with-llamaindex-local-embedding-and-ollama-llama-3-1-8b-b0620116a715?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> In this post, I cover using LlamaIndex LlamaParse in auto mode to parse a PDF page containing a table, using a Hugging Face local embedding model, and using local Llama 3.1 8b via Ollama to perform naive Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). That’s a mouthful. I won’t go into how to setup Ollama and Llama 3.1 8b; this post assumes it is&amp;nbsp;running.  First off, you can find the code for this in m</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T14:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palisades Fire on the Ridge</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/10/palisades-fire-on-the-ridge/</link>
      <description>10:15pm—Here is a Google Earth Pro view of the Palisades fire crossing the wilderness north of Pacific Palisades and south of “Dry Mulholland”—the dirt road that serves as a firebreak along the ridge of the mountains south of the San Fernando Valley: The large squares are MODIS satellite fire detections. The smaller ones are VIIRS. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T06:26:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phi-4 Bug Fixes by Unsloth</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/11/phi-4-bug-fixes/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Phi-4 Bug Fixes by Unsloth 
This explains why I was seeing weird &amp;lt;|im_end|&amp;gt; suffexes during my experiments with Phi-4 the other day: it turns out the Phi-4 tokenizer definition as released by Microsoft had a bug in it, and there was a small bug in the chat template as well. 
 Daniel and Michael Han figured this out and have now published GGUF files with their fixes on Hugging Face.

      Vi</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T01:20:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Los Angeles Media Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/10/the-los-angeles-media-dashboard/</link>
      <description>Twentieth in the News Commons series. That collection of tabs is my dashboard of major media that inform my writing about the #LAfires. There are tabs for five TV stations, one radio station, and one newspaper: KNBC/4 “4 Los Angeles” KTLA/5 “LA’s Very Own” KABC/7&amp;nbsp; “7 Eyewitness News” KCAL/9 “KCAL NEWS CBS Los Angeles” KTTV/11 […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T19:08:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gregg Braden Led Me To Share My Thoughts on Quantum Coherence, Collective Computing, and Tokenized Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/10/how-gregg-braden-led-me-to-share-my-thoughts-on-quantum-coherence-collective-computing-and-tokenized-spirituality/</link>
      <description>This is a video I posted yesterday. And a follow up to clarify certain points. Sorry, I guess the youtube AI choose the “hands up” screenshot for the preview image. I do talk a lot with my hands. Here is a link to Joseph Gonzalez’s blog post on emergent information communication systems. Here are two [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T06:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My AI/LLM predictions for the next 1, 3 and 6 years, for Oxide and Friends</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/10/ai-predictions/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> The Oxide and Friends podcast has an annual tradition of asking guests to share their predictions for the next 1, 3 and 6 years. Here's 2022, 2023 and 2024. This year they invited me to participate. I've never been brave enough to share any public predictions before, so this was a great opportunity to get outside my comfort zone! 
 We recorded the episode live using Discord on Monday. It's now ava</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 01:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T01:43:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorization Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/authorization-matters</link>
      <description>In 2013, poor authorization practices led to one of the largest data breaches in history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T19:36:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-keyed Caching: How Browser Cache Partitioning Changed the Web</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/9/browser-cache-partitioning/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Double-keyed Caching: How Browser Cache Partitioning Changed the Web 
Addy Osmani provides a clear explanation of how browser cache partitioning has changed the landscape of web optimization tricks. 
 Prior to 2020, linking to resources on a shared CDN could provide a performance boost as the user's browser might have already cached that asset from visiting a previous site. 
 This opened up privac</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T19:00:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #119: Are LLMs making StackOverflow irrelevant?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-119</link>
      <description>Also: Apple fires staff over fake charities scam, AI models just keep improving, a middle manager burnout possibly on the horizon, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 17:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T17:26:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Los Angeles Fires and Aftermath</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/09/los-angeles-fires-and-aftermath/</link>
      <description>Nineteenth in the News Commons series 6:50am Friday, January 10, 2025—I will now shift my blogging about the #LAFires from the kind of continuous coverage I’ve done for the last three days to what we might call coverage of coverage. Or something beyond that: shifting to a new kind of news model: grounded in facts […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 15:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T15:24:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sqitch 1.5.0</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/sqitch-1.5.0/</link>
      <description>Sqitch v1.5.0: out now in all the usual places!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T02:30:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>microsoft/phi-4</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/8/phi-4/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> microsoft/phi-4 
Here's the official release of Microsoft's Phi-4 LLM, now officially under an MIT license. 
 A few weeks ago I covered the earlier unofficial versions, where I talked about how the model used synthetic training data in some really interesting ways. 
 It benchmarks favorably compared to GPT-4o, suggesting this is yet another example of a GPT-4 class model that can run on a good lap</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T17:57:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of a Big Tech recruiter</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/confessions-of-a-big-tech-recruiter</link>
      <description>In today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by Blake Stockman, former tech recruiter at Google, Meta, Uber, and YC.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T17:07:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Los Angeles Wildfires</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/08/on-los-angeles-wildfires/</link>
      <description>Eighteenth in the News Commons series 8:02pm It appears that water dropped on the Sunset Fire has mostly contained it within a perimeter absent of houses. Good that the winds were not too high to allow that work. I also no longer see the Chinook operating on FlightRadar24, which may mean its air tanker work […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T16:18:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hockey Trivia</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/08/hockey-trivia/</link>
      <description>  

 As I just registered for a new season of beer league hockey starting this weekend, I thought about an episode of C’est comme ça que je t’aime I recently watched which is set in 1974 Sainte-Foy, Quebec City.  Nearly all the 1974 Quebec cultural references are new to me and in this episode, there is an adventure in a hockey arena and you can pause the video in a few places and see signage in the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T16:03:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Andriy Burkov</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/8/andriy-burkov/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  One agent is just software, two agents are an undebuggable mess.  
 — Andriy Burkov 

     Tags: ai-agents, ai </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T13:47:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OYO AI</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/01/oyo-ai.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;With over 1000 AI communities deployed in 2024, the next AI cohort begins..                                   Coding, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence, Entrepreneurial Skill Development, Teacher PD,&amp;nbsp;  With mentor support of all learners, students and teachers. Unlimited learning by design: (own root)&amp;nbsp;  OYO®&amp;nbsp; AI&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;by kidOYO®&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;at OYOclass.com, Educati</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T12:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Palisades and Eaton Fires</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/07/on-the-palisades-and-eaton-fires/</link>
      <description>Seventeenth in the News Commons series We’re watching KABC/7 from Los Angeles, live on our Roku TV (which has it among hundreds of “Live TV” channels), and in a browser on this laptop. One screen grab: KABC/7 live coverage of the Palisades fire, and the new one a Eaton Canyon in Altadena.Fire.ca.gov has much information, […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T04:28:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are my live regions not working?</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/8/why-are-my-live-regions-not-working/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Why are my live regions not working? 
Useful article to help understand ARIA live regions. Short version: you can add a live region to your page like this: 
 &amp;lt;div id=&quot;notification&quot; aria-live=&quot;assertive&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
 
 Then any time you use JavaScript to modify the text content in that element it will be announced straight away by any screen readers - that's the &quot;assertive&quot; part. Using &quot;poli</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T03:54:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 books</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/46-books-5f8c47016bb2?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Every book is a portal out of here.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-07T23:29:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bug management that works (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/bug-management-that-works-part-2</link>
      <description>Making time for bug fixing, dedicated ‘goalies’, preventing bugs, and how to create a culture quality-focused culture which minimizes them</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-07T18:10:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/06/goodbye-cruel-world-im-leaving.html</link>
      <description>  </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-06T18:15:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Health Care Mess</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/06/the-health-care-mess/</link>
      <description>My wife and I are moving upward through The Final Demographic. Productively: working, traveling, doing stuff. But we are dealing with some of the usual infirmities required by aging, which means we are intimately involved (mostly in very slow motion) with what we generously call U.S. health care system. And, of course, discussions about it. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-06T16:30:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/on-a-purge-roll-good.html</link>
      <description> 🔗🎙️… on a purge roll. Good podcasts. 
 Time Is Way Weirder Than You Think - Ezra Klein 
 We are all going to die, but not from AI - Emad Mostaque 
 Being human in the age of AI - Sean Illing 
 The case for not killing yourself - Sean Illing 
 Rob Long - Delusional and Arrogant 
 Rob Long - Adjacent </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-06T00:16:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/cloud-station-kn-travel-center.html</link>
      <description> Cloud Station ⚭ KN#33 travel center 
 🔗 📼 This one is AI - but MESMERIZING (Sorry - Facebook) </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-06T00:05:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/live-steampunk-germany-posted-years.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 📼 Live SteamPunk - Germany - Posted 5 Years ago - and I only just saw it! 
 🔗 📼 The Channel </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-06T00:01:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/the-case-for-the-executive.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 The Case for the Executive Chair 
 I annotated this in the middle of 2024 with the intention to share, it’s pretty damming. 
 
 Only one or two directors on the typical 11-member board say they understand industry economics and how the company makes money. Two or three say they have little or no understanding. 
 
 Exactly in line with my observations - failure to understand leads to a focus on h</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 23:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T23:55:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carry-On, 2024 - ★★★</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/carryon.html</link>
      <description>    I like both actors - so despite the warnings of ‘the new diehard’ I ploughed ahead. it was a fine movie - but both actors have substantially better performances and films/shows on their cv. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 20:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T20:58:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/scorsese-takes-aim-at-streamings.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 Scorsese Takes Aim at Streaming’s Lack of Curation … and more … including ‘content’ 
 
 the art of cinema is being systematically devalued, sidelined, demeaned, and reduced to its lowest common denominator” by conceptualization of films as “content. 
 
 🖇️ 🔍 You might recall - the ‘content thing’ has been a drum beat of mine for a while now. 
 As always delighted to find more people jumping on t</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T17:19:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/05/how-a-mole-infiltrated-the.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 🍿 How a Mole Infiltrated the Highest Ranks of American Militias — ProPublica </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T17:16:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI-assisted coding will change software engineering: hard truths</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-ai-will-change-software-engineering</link>
      <description>A field guide that also covers why we need to rethink our expectations, and what software engineering really is. A guest post by software engineer and engineering leader Addy Osmani</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 16:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T16:29:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/04/confusion-will-be-my-epitaph.html</link>
      <description> Confusion will be my epitaph 
 As I crawl a cracked and broken path 
 If we make it we can all sit back and laugh 
 But I fear tomorrow I’ll be crying </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T06:35:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/04/a-quote-from-ethan-mollick.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 A quote from Ethan Mollick 
 Which reminds me. 
 When you engage with your LLM of choice, do you say ‘good morning’, ‘thankyou’, ‘please’ … all that nicety stuff? 
 Bonus question .. regardless of your answer have you tried doing it the other way? 
 Do the results seem better or worse? </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T06:23:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/04/tonights-desert-sunset-intense-which.html</link>
      <description> Tonight’s Desert Sunset. 

 Intense. 

 Which way to look? 

 Even the non intense bits are beautiful. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 01:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-05T01:44:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-llamaindex-part-1-openai-e96b3efa699a?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI  I have started to experiment with LlamaIndex for use in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) document parsing and indexing. My results were mixed on the simple page provided. This is part 1, where I make a short post on LlamaIndex with OpenAI as the LLM component. I expect part 2 to be LlamaIndex with Ollama and Llama3–8b as the LLM components.  This is a very sho</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T21:15:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/04/behind-the-big-names-theres.html</link>
      <description> Behind the big names - there’s always another (just as important - but not as famous ) name. 
 On the whole they were the ‘tech’. 
 Gates and Allen (RIP) 
 Jobs and Woz 
 and of course 
 Larry and Bob (RIP) 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T20:11:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/04/just-call-me-sisyphus.html</link>
      <description> Just call me ‘Sisyphus’. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T17:21:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Second Candidate Recommendation for Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2603</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group published the Snapshot Second Candidate Recommendation of the Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE specification just before the holidays. This was one of five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group at the same time, including for the Verifiable Credentials Data Model 2.0, which I’m also an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-03T04:57:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should URI::mysql Switch to DBD::MariaDB?</title>
      <link>https://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=11163487</link>
      <description>Should Sqitch and URI::mysql use DBD::MariaDB instead of DBD::mysql? If so,
what are the implications for Sqitch deployment and usage?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T22:47:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/01/occams-aside-knowing-nothing-but.html</link>
      <description> Occams aside .. -!: knowing nothing .. but I’m predicting that this was a specific act conducted to ‘send a message’ to a couple o’ billionaires. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T22:27:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New JSONPath Feature: SelectLocated</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/jsonpath-located/</link>
      <description>New in the jsonpath Go package and Playground: “Located” results that pair
selected values with normalized paths to their locations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:43:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/01/been-reading-headlines-like-this.html</link>
      <description> Been reading headlines like this 
 🔗 Trump coverage needs to change and here’s how - Press Watch 
 since at least 2020 - like this one from … checking … 2020. 
 🔗 Journalism fails miserably at explaining what is really happening to America 
 More maybe should be written like this one … 
 🔗 Ruth Ben-Ghiat Explains Trump’s Fascism </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:17:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/01/an-a-to-z-of.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 An A to Z of predictions for 2025 </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:15:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/01/wondering-if-we-are-years.html</link>
      <description> Wondering if we are 500 years early. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:05:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/01/nine-years-ago-remembering-eleven.html</link>
      <description> Nine years ago - remembering eleven years before that - and I still miss him. 
 🔗 🪦Harry Fenik - it happened 20 years ago this month. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T18:49:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/01/01/i-just-know-that-there.html</link>
      <description> I just KNOW that there are more posts … 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T15:54:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wishing All A Resonant New Year – May We Have The Blessings Of New Learnings And Chances To Grow In 2025</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/01/wishing-all-a-resonant-new-year-may-we-have-the-blessings-of-new-learnings-and-chances-to-grow-in-2025/</link>
      <description>We don’t always get to choose what happens during the course of our lives, but we DO get to choose how we incorporate the unexpected into our stories. Here’s to seeing the value of complementary energies that keep this “reality” going even during times when the mixture makes us queasy. May we learn to navigate [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T06:07:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intention Economyその後</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/intention-economy.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    年末にDoc SearlsがIntention Economyについて「The Real Intention Economy」というポストをしています。かなり重要なポストだと思うので読んでおいた方が良さそうです。     https://doc.searls.com/2024/12/30/the-real-intention-economy/     彼の著書は日本語にも翻訳されていますね。  https://amzn.to/3C2PX9n        さて、今回のDocのポストに戻ると、彼がIntention Economyの考え方を発表してからもう直ぐ20年が経とうとしている現在、生成AIの文脈も相まって、Intention Economy自体が脅威となりつつある、という話です。     Intention Economyで検索すると結構ヤバ目の結果が返</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T03:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2024/12/31/of-all-people-dejus-might.html</link>
      <description> Of all people @dejus might have an opinion  on this .. who knows - he might have done the trip? 
 Palm Springs to Ashland 
 
 not on the 5 
 Not on the 101 
 Not on the 1 
 
 Over on the ‘other side’ 
 Longer journey, for sure. Should be more interesting … but in January? 
 Anyone and everyone - please weigh in. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 23:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T23:19:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2024/12/31/not-thought-about-kiwi-polish.html</link>
      <description> 📸 Not thought about ‘Kiwi Polish’ for decades .. but as a kid there was a lot of it around in our house. Just wondering now if it actually originated in Aotearoa or if it was just a name. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 23:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T23:08:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2024/12/31/art-possibly-somewhere-i-would.html</link>
      <description> Art? Possibly. Somewhere I would want to live? Nope. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 23:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T23:04:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2024/12/31/im-not-sayin-this-is.html</link>
      <description> I’m not sayin’ this is a scalable solution to develop income .. but worth a shot? Buy stuffed bird under glass cover for 10 bucks. Replace bird with bundles of those odd floppies you’ve got lying around the house. 
 Charge $1500. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 23:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T23:00:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2024/12/31/only-that-seems-high-to.html</link>
      <description> 💬 Only? That seems high to me. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T22:54:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2024/12/31/peak-mastodon.html</link>
      <description> Peak Mastodon? 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T22:53:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL/JSON Path Playground Update</title>
      <link>https://theory.github.io/sqljson/</link>
      <description>The Go SQL/JSON Playground has been updated with a fresh design and PostgreSQL
17 compatibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T20:40:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tintin and the fascists</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/tintin-and-the-fascists-90241c93b3c6?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    The boy reporter has a fascist origin. But something new is possible.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T16:46:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for tech, 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/predictions-for-tech-2025-4046a6331cb9?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s going to be a hard year.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T15:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>366/366 !!!</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/366366.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  ついにこの日が来ました。           去年の正月休みに某猫とのチキンレースが始まってしまったので収まりがつかなくなって惰性で描き続けていましたが気がついたら本当に1年経ってしまいました。  ↓某猫のポスト 
  ふじえさん、やっぱりやっとるな！ 毎日記事を書く366チャレンジや！ これ絶対やっとるぞ！ — 👹秋田の猫🐱 (@ritou) January 4, 2024  
    最初のうちは割と実装してみよう！的なポストが多かったのですが、中盤〜後半は忙しくなりすぎたこともあり読んでみようシリーズが大半を占めてしまったのは反省です。  ということで振り返ってみましょう。  1月のポストはこんな感じです。     この頃は結構作ってますね。まぁ、冬休みが暇だったので実装し始めたのがきっかけだったので。  あとは1月はOpenID Summit Tokyo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T23:11:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soll ich der elektronischen Patientenakte widersprechen und wie geht das?</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/soll-ich-der-elektronischen-patientenakte-widersprechen-und-wie-geht-das/</link>
      <description> Wenn du gesetzlich krankenversichert bist, wird deine Krankenkasse bis 15. Januar 2025 eine elektronische Patientenakte für dich einrichten – es sei denn, du widersprichst. Das gilt auch für private Krankenversicherungen, die … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T10:32:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑧</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01040135091.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだまだプライバシーの章が続きます。  4.5.&amp;nbsp;DELETING MDL INFORMATION FROM A DEVICE   An mDL holder must have the capability to delete the mDL holder’s mDL from the mDL holder’s device. Such deletion:      Must delete all mDL information, log information, and any metadata (e.g. settings) that could impart information </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-29T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑦</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_02108542609.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     引き続き4章のプライバシーの部分を読んでいきます。  4.3.&amp;nbsp;PROTECTING DATA   It is up to Issuing Authorities to ensure that all mDL data stored on the mDL holder’s device is adequately protected. As standards in this respect are still under development, each Issuing Authority should take great care to ensure that the design of its</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>世界のデジタルIDと認証技術の最新トレンド：12月28日版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6635/</link>
      <description>Block、分散型デジタルIDのオープンソース技術をDIFに移管 Blockは、子会社であるTBDを閉鎖したことを受けて、分散型デジタルIDのために開発したオープンソースコンポーネントを分散型アイデンティティ財団（DIF）に引き継ぐことを発表しました。 発表によると、DIDメソッ…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T16:15:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑥</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_28.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        ようやく4章の「PRIVACY AND SECURITY」に入ります。4章も結構長いんですよね。。。ただ、結構重要な章なので細かくみていきたいと思います。     4.1.&amp;nbsp;INTRODUCTION   The privacy of an mDL holder has been paramount in the mDL design process from the start. Care was and is being taken in all the work to ensure that methods and means are available to protect mDL h</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T21:57:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a framework for living well</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/creating-a-framework-for-living-well-4aafe427c74b?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Drawing upa North Star for building my life  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T17:06:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 Foundation: SDO Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/26/web-7-0-foundation-sdo-accreditation/</link>
      <description>The Web 7.0 Foundation is a relatively new organization, incorporated in Canada on May 1, 2023². It focuses on developing specifications and standards for a unified software and hardware ecosystem aimed at building resilient, trusted, and decentralized systems¹³. Source: Conversation … Continue reading →</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T23:05:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑤</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0938402867.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだ３章が続きますが今回で３章は終わりです。     3.6.&amp;nbsp;IACA ROOT CERTIFICATE   In Table B.1 of ISO/IEC 18013-5, on the table row for the “ISSUER” certificate component, replace:     stateOrProvinceName is optional. If this element is present, the element shall also be present in the end-entity certificates and hold the same va</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む④</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01062834414.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        引き続き３章を読んでいきます。  3-3.&amp;nbsp;PORTRAIT IMAGE   The portrait image is the primary means by which an mDL is matched to the person presenting the mDL in an attended transaction. The portrait image therefore needs to be of suitable quality for this purpose. ISO/IEC 18013-5 requires the portrait to comply with Ann</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-25T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む③</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0833807043.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は３章のISO/IEC 18013-5 QUALIFICATIONSです。  3.1. INTRODUCTION   Issuing authorities electing to follow the guidance in this document must adhere to ISO/IEC 18013-5, including as qualified in this document.    本文書のガイダンスに従うことを選択した発行局は、本文書で修飾されている場合を含め、ISO/IEC 18013-5 を遵守しなければならない。   3.2.&amp;nbsp;AAMVA MDL DATA ELEMEN</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-24T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む②</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_24.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は２章のmDL Solution Overviewを見ていきます。   An mDL can be described as leveraging a mobile device to transfer (or cause to be transferred) driver’s license information to an mDL verifier, who cryptographically authenticates the information using the Issuing
Authority’s public key. A visual rendering of a DL on a mo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-23T22:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む①</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日、用語を見たついでにAAMVAが出しているMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいこうと思います。          こちらが原文です。     まずはIntroductionから。   The AAMVA Joint Mobile Driver’s License (mDL) Working Group (WG) has been active around mobile identification since 2012. As the mDL evolves, the mDL WG continues to identify and address topics on which guidance to Issuing Authorities can be helpful. T</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSONTree Module and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/12/jsontree/</link>
      <description>I’m happy to announce the release of the JSONTree Go module and Wasm-powered
in-browser playground.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 21:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T21:33:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Sovereign Identity: Over before it started?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/self-sovereign-identity-over-before-it-started-661b4b0dbdc6?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Web security, symbolized Monty Pythons parrot sketch is an all time classic because it plays on a very human experience of being defenseless when someone is just blatantly refusing to acknowledge the obvious. Shared reality is a matter of perception, not objective observation. Supported also by various mental biases, including the sunk cost fallacy, and the desire to agree with people we perceive a</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T19:13:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID for Verifiable Credentials IssuanceのPublic Review期間が始まりました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/openid-for-verifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日のOpenID for Verifiable Presentationにつづき、いよいよ始まりました。ついにOpenID for Verifiable Credential Issuanceも2nd Implementer's Draftです。        https://openid.net/public-review-period-for-proposed-second-implementers-draft-of-openid-for-verifiable-credential-issuance/  こんなスケジュールです。    Implementer's Draft public review period: Friday, December 20, 2024 to Sunday, February 2, 2025 (45 days)  Imple</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T01:04:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ついに発売へ。デジタルアイデンティティのすべて</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post_21.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    週末に家に帰ったら先行して届いていました。12月27日に発売になる「デジタルアイデンティティのすべて」です。  原著と比べると少しだけ大きいですね。        こちらから予約注文できますのでどうぞ。  https://amzn.to/3P9KS2e        ついでにSoftware Designの最新号も届いていましたし、年末年始はアイデンティティとパスキーざんまいですね！        1月末には「パスキーのすべて」も発売されますので、体（頭）をあっためておきましょう。  https://amzn.to/3ZHQohg    </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-21T09:58:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Water is Death</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/12/20/no-water-is-death/</link>
      <description>

 “Extermination &amp;amp; Acts of Genocide”: Human Rights Watch on Israel Deliberately Depriving Gaza of Water 

 AMY GOODMAN: So, can I ask you, Bill Van Esveld, is this the first time that Human Rights Watch is accusing Israel of genocide in Gaza? 

 BILL VAN ESVELD: This is the first time that we’ve made a finding of genocidal acts in Gaza. It is not an accusation that we level lightly. We have no</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-20T15:06:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Foundatiion の理事選挙(2025)に立候補しました</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6631/</link>
      <description>先程、OpenID Foundatiion の理事選挙(2025)に立候補いたしました。メンバーの各位におかれましては、ぜひ推薦 (second)お願いできればと思います。 選挙のページは https://openid.net/foundation/members/electio…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-20T08:50:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>モバイル運転免許証に関する用語を見ていきます</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    こちらにも書いた通り、11月にAAMVAからMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelineの1.4がでました。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/mobile-drivers-licensemdl.html          読んでいてそういえば一般的じゃない言葉ばっかり使ってるよなぁ、と思うのでまずはTerminologyを見ておきましょう。         そもそも論のAAMVAです。    American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators   の略ですね。米国自動車管理者協会と訳されるようです。この辺の資料によると。&amp;nbsp;     EDL。enhanced driver licenseの略ですね。日本語だと</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-19T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wrapped: The Pragmatic Engineer in 2024</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/wrapped-the-pragmatic-engineer-in</link>
      <description>The year’s most-read articles, some personal favorites, and a look back at a busy year in tech</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-19T16:55:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDに関するグローバルの動向</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/id.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    OpenID FoundationのブログでElizabethが各国のデジタルIDに関する最近のトピックスを取り上げていますので紹介したいと思います。もちろん日本も含まれています。  https://openid.net/digital-identity-news-round-up-13-dec-2024/             キプロス   デジタル・シチズンとして知られるモバイル・デジタルIDアプリを開始した。  このアプリでは、バイオメトリクスIDカード、運転免許証、自動車の路上使用適格性証明書などのデジタル文書をモバイルで保持することができる。また、QRコードを使ってデジタル認証することもできる  https://www.biometricupdate.com/202412/cyprus-launches-digital-citizen-mobile</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shipping projects at Big Tech with Sean Goedecke</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/shipping-projects-at-big-tech-with</link>
      <description>In today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by Sean Goedecke, Staff Software Engineer at GitHub.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T17:05:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JIPDEC、トラステッド・サービス登録（電子契約サービス）の登録基準を作成し、公開</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6627/</link>
      <description>わたしも客員研究員を努めさせていただいているJIPDECでは、電子契約サービスの信頼性向上のため、「JIPDECトラステッド・サービス登録（電子契約サービス）」の登録基準を作成し、公開いたしました。 本基準は、電子契約サービスの安全性確保に必要な項目を定めており、安心して電子契約…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T07:59:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPI2.0の最終化に向けたPublic Reviewが始まります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/fapi20public-review.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  FAPI2.0のSecurity Profile and Attacker Modelに関する仕様の最終化に関するPublic Review期間が始まっていますね。  https://openid.net/public-review-for-proposed-final-fapi-2-0-specifications/        今後はこんなスケジュールで進むようです。    Final Specification public review period: Monday, December 9, 2024 to Friday, February 7, 2025 (60 days)  Final Specification vote announcement: Saturday, January 25, 2025  Final Specification e</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T00:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Shopify Built Its Live Globe for Black Friday</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/shopify-black-friday</link>
      <description>Shopify has built a surprisingly fun and engaging Black Friday / Cyber Monday visual tracker, simulating a spaceship's interior. A deepdive in how this experience was built with the dev team behind it</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-17T17:17:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumでの登壇内容を紹介します</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/taiwan-digital-identity-wallet.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先週はTaiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumで登壇してきましたので、キーノートとしてお話した内容をメモしておきたいと思います。  イベントについてはこちら  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/11/taiwan-digital-wallet-international.html          自己紹介は置いておいて、テーマは相互運用性でした。    As you know, the Digital Identity Wallet has recently become an emerging topic in the digital identity space. For example, the European Committee has started im</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph from Wikipedia in Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/building-a-knowledge-graph-from-wikipedia-in-neo4j/</link>
      <description>https://guides.neo4j.com/wiki https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/cats.csv?raw=true https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/rels.csv?raw=true</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T18:06:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Songwriter/Performer Use Case: DID Method Candidates</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/toronto-songwriter-performer-use-case-did-method-candidates/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 10:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T10:02:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>年明けはデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WG：活動報告会から</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/wg.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     年明け1/14はデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WGの活動報告会があります。  https://openid.connpass.com/event/339259/       例の本が年末に販売されることもあり、翻訳を担当したメンバーから苦労話など聞ける良い機会になると思いますのでぜひご来場ください。    </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-15T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>今年もKim Cameronアワードのノミネートが始まっています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/kim-cameron.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  これまで何度かポストした、Kim CameronアワードやVittorio Bertocciアワードですが、今年もKim Cameronアワードのノミネートが始まりました。  https://digitalidadvancement.org/awards-and-grants/kim/2025-kca/           今後のスケジュールはこんな感じなので、我こそは！という方は申請してみてはいかがでしょうか？    December 11: Call for Applications Opens  January 21: Call for Applications Closes  January 31: Awardees Notified  February 7: Awardee Confirmation of Acceptance Due  30 Days</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-14T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth Security Workshopの参加登録が始まっています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/oauth-security-workshop.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日お知らせした通り次回のOAuth Security Workshopはアイスランドで開催です。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/09/oauth-security-workshop.html     ということで参加登録が開始されていますので申し込みましょう！  https://oauth.secworkshop.events/osw2025     なお、11月後半にレイキャビクの近くで火山の噴火があったようです。Danielに聞いたら大丈夫、との話でしたが様子を見つつ参加することになりそうですね。  一応大使館のページをみると12/9に収束した、という宣言は出ていますし。  https://www.is.emb-japan.go.jp/itpr_ja/volcano.html             </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-13T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The open social web is the future of the internet. Here’s why I’m excited.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-open-social-web-is-the-future-of-the-internet-heres-why-i-m-excited-e03e3d96ad3c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It gives you back control.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 03:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-13T03:26:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Googleが公開している「４分でパスキーを理解する」動画が素晴らしい件</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/google.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     昨日はFIDO東京セミナーでしたね。私は台北にいたので参加できませんでしたが・・・  ということで悔しいので #fido でXを追いかけていましたが、えーじさんのパート（だと思う）で触れられていたっぽい「４分でパスキーを理解する」動画が素晴らしくわかりやすいかったのでメモしておこうというポストです。     ざっくりシナリオはこんな感じでした。    長らくパスワードを使ってきたけど、難しいパスワードは覚えられないし、同じパスワードの使い回しが起きるので危ないよね  そんなあなたにGoogleはパスワードマネージャを提供しているよ！  デバイスを跨いで同期されるのでとっても便利！  でも全員がパスワードマネージャに頼っているわけじゃないよね  その前にそもそもパスワードってセキュアじゃないよ  2段階認証はセキュリティ強度を上げるけど面倒だしなぁ  そんな</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-12T20:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #118: OpenAI shows why it’s the AI leader</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-118</link>
      <description>Also: Devin doubles down on “AI software engineer” branding, court orders Automattic to undo unethical actions against WP Engine, and a possible middle manager burnout around the corner</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-12T17:01:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIDI HubワシントンD.Cサミットのレポートが出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/sidi-hubdc.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日、東京サミットのレポートが出た、という話を書いた段階ではまだワシントンDCレポートが出ていなかったので順番が逆になっちゃたなぁ、みたいなことを思っていたのですが、ポストを公開した直後にワシントンDCのレポートも公開されました。     他のレポートと同じく、こちらのページからダウンロードできますので、おいおい読んでいこうと思います。  https://sidi-hub.community/summits/    </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-11T23:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notion: going native on iOS and Android</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/notion-going-native-on-ios-and-android</link>
      <description>In today’s exciting episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I am joined by two members of the Notion mobile apps team, Austin Louden and Karn Saheb.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-11T18:31:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSFの相互運用イベントがGartnerサミットと並列で行われています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/ssfgartner.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    今週私は台湾にいるわけですが、USではGartnerサミットが開催されています。  その場でShare Signals Frameworkの相互運用検証に関するイベント（実際に実装を持ち寄って繋いでみる）が行われています。        https://openid.net/oidf-returns-to-gartner-to-showcase-shared-signals-interoperability/     過去にも何度か実施されており、非常に良い結果が出ていますので、今回も色々な実装を繋いだ結果が出てくることを楽しみにしています。  特にSSFのような仕組みは複数の事業者の実装が相互に接続できないと何の意味もないものなので、良い取り組みだと思います。     そういえば、Identity Dance Advent Calendarの中でGoogle</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-10T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why my new audiobook “The Software Engineer's Guidebook” is everywhere except on Audible</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/software-engineers-guidebook-audiobook</link>
      <description>The new audiobook of my latest title is published today, and it’s available almost everywhere – but not on the world’s biggest audiobook platform. Let me explain why…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-10T17:37:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024年第4四半期ID関連ニュース総振り返り</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6608/</link>
      <description>早いもので2024年も終わりですね。慶応大学の林さんと2024年第4四半期のID関連ニュースの振り返りを行いたいと思います。 日時：12月17日 20:00〜場所：YouTube Live @55id対象とするニュース一覧：https://www.sakimura.org/202…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-10T10:47:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID for Verifiable Presentationsの投票期間が間も無く始まります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/openid-for-verifiable-presentations.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     先日投稿した、OpenID for Verifiable PresentationsのImplementers DraftのPublic Review期間が終わり、Vote期間に入ります。       https://openid.net/notice-of-vote-for-proposed-implementers-draft-of-openid-for-openid-for-verifiable-presentations/     12月17日〜24日の間が投票期間ですので、メンバーの方は忘れずに投票しましょう。  （公式な投票期間は上記ですが、実際は12月10日から投票は開始されます）       </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-09T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra External ID with an Auth0 OpenID Connect identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/12/09/using-entra-external-id-with-an-auth0-openid-connect-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at implementing an Open ID Connect identity provider in Microsoft Entra External ID. Auth0 is used as the identity provider and an ASP.NET Core application is used to test the authentication. Microsoft Entra External ID federates to Auth0. Client code: https://github.com/damienbod/EntraExternalIdCiam Microsoft Entra External ID supports federation using OpenID Connect and was […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-09T05:39:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIDI Hub東京サミットのレポートが公開されています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/sidi-hub_0508965680.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日東京で開催されたSIDI Hub Summitのレポートが早くも出ています。（ワシントンDCより先に発表されてしまいました）        事前に私も書いたものをElizabethに連携してあったので早めに作ってくれた気がします。良かった。  https://sidi-hub.community/summits/     まぁ、そのうち見ていきたいと思います。 </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-08T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【スライド掲載】第11回 FIDO東京セミナー 　～パスワードのいらない世界へ～</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6603/</link>
      <description>来る１２月１２日、第11回FIDO東京セミナーで僭越ながらクロージングキーノートをさせていただきますました。 タイトルは「デジタルアイデンティティのグローバルランドスケープ」 プログラム&amp;amp;スピーカーは以下の通り。チケットは公式サイトよりお求めいただけます。どうぞお誘い合わ…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 16:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-08T16:10:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrity Properties for Federations</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2597</link>
      <description>I’m writing to highly recommend the article “How to link an application protocol to an OpenID Federation 1.0 trust layer” by Vladimir Dzhuvinov. In it, he defines two kinds of integrity for Federations, and describes how to achieve them: Federation Integrity, which is defined as: This ensures mutual trust between two entities is established always […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 02:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-07T02:08:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #117: AWS gets serious about GenAI</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-117</link>
      <description>Also: OpenAI exploring ads and military contracts, Vercel buys one-person code search startup, How the commercial sector regained lead in computing over the military, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-05T16:56:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software architecture with Grady Booch</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/software-architecture-with-grady-booch</link>
      <description>Today, I’m thrilled to be joined by Grady Booch, a true legend in software development. Grady is the Chief Scientist for Software Engineering at IBM, where he leads groundbreaking research in embodied cognition.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-04T17:16:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUデジタルIDウォレットの規則が官報に掲載</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6583/</link>
      <description>採択したとのニュースから、いつ来るかと待っていましたが、本日官報に掲載されました。NRIセキュアの古川さんに教えていただきました。 具体的プロトコルなどは 2024/2979のAnnexに書いてあります。 Pseudonym Provider には、ドイツなどから別の方式の提案が…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 06:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-04T06:01:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>世界のデジタルIDと認証技術の最新トレンド：12月3日版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6581/</link>
      <description>英国：バス事業者が学生向けデジタルID導入 National Express West Midlandsは、デジタルID企業のYotiと提携し、バスでのデジタル学生証の受け入れを開始しました。学生は無料の学生IDをダウンロードし、West MidlandsとCoventryのNa…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 04:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-04T04:04:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of “Wicked” The Movie – Prophecy, Quantum Dance, Self-Actualization, and the Tao in Pink and Green</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2024/12/03/review-of-wicked-the-movie-prophecy-quantum-dance-self-actualization-and-the-tao-in-pink-and-green/</link>
      <description>This movie outing was a post-Thanksgiving indulgence for a gal who rarely goes out. After seeing it, I empathize with principled, strong Elphaba and can’t help but picture her waif counterpart, queen bee Galinda (Glinda), as having a bright post-Shiz University career as a savvy but manipulative social impact investor. This particular episode will work [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-03T20:09:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How GenAI is reshaping tech hiring</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-genai-changes-tech-hiring</link>
      <description>Large language models are forcing tech hiring managers to adapt software engineering interview processes, fast. We look into how this is happening, and what to expect in the near future</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-03T18:11:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using ASP.NET Core with Azure Key Vault</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/12/02/using-asp-net-core-with-azure-key-vault/</link>
      <description>This article looks at setting up an ASP.NET Core application to use Azure Key Vault. When deployed to Azure, it works like in the Azure documentation but when working on development PCs, some changes are required for a smooth developer experience. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/UsingAzureKeyVaultInDevelopment I develop using Visual Studio and manage multiple accounts and test environments. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-02T06:34:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My OKRs for 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/my-okrs-for-2025-aa6e286ef038?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Using Objectives and Key Results to get through a difficult year  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T23:07:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Informed Consent Even Possible When Most Agents Have No Interest In Building Their Own Scaffold?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2024/12/01/is-informed-consent-even-possible-when-most-agents-have-no-interest-in-building-their-own-scaffold/</link>
      <description>With the lens I have been using (harnessed consciousness through Web3 token engineering, perhaps for the purposes of individual and group consensus divination) the ideas I am talking about in this video and the beginning of the previous one are actually quite important. If you want to write me off as simply being angry, you’ve [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 17:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T17:16:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three New Specs Enhancing OpenID Federation and New Contributors</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2592</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect working group recently adopted three new specifications that build upon and provide new capabilities to OpenID Federation. But I’m not only happy about these because of the engineering benefits they bring. I’m particularly happy because they bring new active contributors to the work, specifically Michael Fraser and Łukasz Jaromin, as well as […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 06:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T06:50:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Austin Indieweb at Radio Coffee</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/30/austin-indieweb-at-radio-coffee/</link>
      <description> On Wednesday 12/04 at 7pm, the Austin Indieweb Meetup returns to Radio Coffee and Beer.  Count me in. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 13:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-30T13:19:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Titus Impersonates Jackie Gleason in Smokey And The Bandit II For Catherine Austin Fitts</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2024/11/29/john-titus-impersonates-jackie-gleason-in-smokey-and-the-bandit-ii-for-catherine-austin-fitts/</link>
      <description>Today’s “Black Friday” video is shared below. To skip forward to my analysis of the Solari Report’s recent short on “Bitcoin Billionaires” go to timestamp 25 minutes. But the first part is kind of fun if you want to take some time to think about how we think, alone and together, and what it might [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-30T00:34:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>欧州委員会、新たに5つのデジタルウォレット関連の実施法案を公表</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/11/6566/</link>
      <description>現地時間11月29日、EUデジタルアイデンティティウォレットに必要な厳格な法的仕様を概説する実施法案が、パブコメにかけられました。 今年夏にはすでに5件の実施法案が公表され、欧州委員会によって採択されており、欧州デジタルアイデンティティ・フレームワークの下での欧州デジタルアイデン…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T14:16:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 37. Multi-dimensional Overton Olive (MuDOO) as an ADKAR-enabled Change Management Framework (MuDOO-ADKAR)</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/29/model-37-multi-dimensional-overton-olive-mudoo-as-anadkar-enabled-change-management-framework-mudoo-adkar/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Also Checkout:</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T13:21:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 36. Overton Visual Taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/28/model-36-overton-visual-taxonomy/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Model 36. Overton Visual Taxonomy Additional Information:</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T01:18:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>欧州委員会、デジタルアイデンティティウォレット(EUDIW)の実施規則を採択</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/11/6563/</link>
      <description>現地時間11月28日、欧州委員会は欧州デジタルアイデンティティ（eID）ウォレットに関するコア機能と認証の規則を欧州デジタルアイデンティティ・フレームワークの下で採択しました。これは、加盟国が自国のウォレットを構築し、2026年末までにリリースするための重要な一歩です。 4つの実…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-28T13:49:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working Notes On Ghayat al-Hakim (The Picatrix) and Possible Intersections Between Web3 and Mystical Islam</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2024/11/27/working-notes-on-ghayat-al-hakim-the-picatrix-and-possible-intersections-between-web3-and-mystical-islam/</link>
      <description>Because I need to head out to dig the last of my garden beds before frost sets in, I am making a rather fragmented placeholder post to hold links I recently shared with online colleagues. I’m going to use this as a reference for my future self, but perhaps others will also find it to [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 23:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T23:51:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 35. Overton Olive Digital Twin (#OvertonOlive #DigitalTwin)</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/27/overton-olive-overtonolive/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Model 35. #OvertonOlive #DigitalTwin (click the diagram to enlarge it) Progressive Improvement through Continuous Transformation For more background on the #OvertonOlive:</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T21:51:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadening the Definition of Identity Practitioner</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2024/11/broadening-the-definition-of-identity-practitioner.html</link>
      <description>One of the wonderful, yet also daunting, aspects of being in the Identity industry is realizing just how far-reaching and all-encompassing its scope and boundaries are. It’s why we need more than just technologists and standards wonks engaged in driving the future of this industry. I’ve been on stage at Identiverse and other conferences for […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T15:49:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDEs with GenAI features that Software Engineers love</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/ide-that-software-engineers-love</link>
      <description>AI-first IDEs like Cursor, WindSurf, Zed and others, are challenging Visual Studio Code’s dominance. What’s making devs switch over?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-26T17:23:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RFC: Extension Packaging &amp;amp; Lookup</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/rfc-extension-packaging-lookup/</link>
      <description>A proposal to modify the PostgreSQL core so that all files required for an
extension live in a directory named for the extension, along with a search
path to find extension directories.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-25T19:14:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The social cost of mediated experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/11/24/the-social-cost-of-mediated-experience/</link>
      <description>The first time I heard a critique of mediated experience, the critic was my dad. He was an avid photographer who, during our family’s year in India, when I was a young child, used his 35mm Exacta to capture thousands of photos that became carousels of color slides we viewed for many years thereafter. It … Continue reading The social cost of mediated experience</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 04:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-25T04:25:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Toni Price</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/23/rip-toni-price/</link>
      <description>

 We made a roadtrip one last time to Wimberly to see her perform at the Devil’s Backbone Tavern in August 2023. 

 There was no one like Toni Price. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 16:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-23T16:59:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #116: Netflix sets live streaming world record with boxing match</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-116</link>
      <description>Also: why some late-stage companies don’t want to go public, possible crackdown on low-output remote engineers, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 18:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-21T18:37:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear: move fast with little process (with first engineering manager Sabin Roman)</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/linear-move-fast-with-little-process</link>
      <description>On today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by fellow Uber alum, Sabin Roman, now the first Engineering Manager at Linear.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-20T13:02:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDと認証技術の最新トレンド：11月19日・25日合併版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/11/6575/</link>
      <description>欧州：IDnowが認定信頼サービスプロバイダーを設立 IDnowが、EU規則910/2014（eIDAS）に基づく認定信頼サービスプロバイダー（QTSP）として「IDnow Trust Services AB」を設立しました。この新会社は、2024年初頭にストックホルムでIDno…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 03:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-19T03:13:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core BFF using OpenID Connect and Vue.js</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/11/18/asp-net-core-bff-using-openid-connect-and-vue-js/</link>
      <description>This article shows how to implement a secure web application using Vue.js and ASP.NET Core. The web application implements the backend for frontend security architecture (BFF) and deploys both technical stacks as one web application. HTTP only secure cookies are used to persist the session. OpenIddict is used as the identity provider and the token […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-18T07:07:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I want from Mozilla</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/what-i-want-from-mozilla-703cf5ce06fb?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    A people-first, safe, independent web.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 18:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-15T18:49:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye Twitter</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/bye-twitter/</link>
      <description>I finally deleted all my Twitter accounts, notably @theory. If you see that
username, it’s not me.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 23:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-14T23:47:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ein Jahr Absage an die Chatkontrolle</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/ein-jahr-absage-an-die-chatkontrolle/</link>
      <description> Heute vor einem Jahr haben wir im Ausschuss für bürgerliche Freiheiten, Justiz und Inneres (LIBE) des EU-Parlaments eine fraktionsübergreifende Position gegen anlasslose Chatkontrolle beschlossen. Damit haben wir den wahnwitzigen Überwachungsplänen … </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-14T20:02:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 / TDW Decentralized Identifier (DID Method) Clusters Model 0.1: Specification Development Framework</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/11/catergories-of-decentralized-identifiers-dids/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2018-2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode To learn how to join the did-methods DIF Working Group, click https://github.com/decentralized-identity/did-methods. 0. Prime Objective/Directive #Chickens, #Eggs, and #Roosters: A #NorthStar for the Global Decent</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 22:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-11T22:47:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webfinger in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/08/webfinger-in-the-wild/</link>
      <description> Today, a post in my feed included a mention and its webfinger verification threw a WebFinger::BadRequest exception: 

  Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  WebFinger::BadRequest (Bad Request):
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM 
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:79:in `fetch_and_create_mastodon_account'
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:367:in `block in create_status!'
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:36</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-08T15:50:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Identity Workshop XXXIX Report</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/internet-identity-workshop-xxxix</link>
      <description>The 39th edition of the Internet Identity Workshop wrapped up last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-08T14:39:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A hypothesis about the Democrats</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/a-hypothesis-about-the-democrats-8a783f70924a?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>  Have they been culturally outmaneuvered?  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-07T15:04:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We can still rise</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/we-can-still-rise-44cac5cd144a?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    The election was bleak. But we have a future.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-06T14:58:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indieweb Meetup Austin today</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/06/indieweb-meetup-austin-today/</link>
      <description> After some time off IndieWeb Meetup Austin is back at Mozart’s Coffee tonight at 7pm.  I guess a few things have transpired since the last meeting so I’m looking forward to learning about what’s going on again. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 11:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-06T11:41:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing RFC 9535 Go JSONPath and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/go-jsonpath-playground/</link>
      <description>I’ve made a RFC 9535 JSONPath JSONPath Go package, and compiled it into Wasm to
build an in-browser playground for it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T18:23:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYTimes Tech Guild on Strike</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/nytimes-tech-guild-on-strike/</link>
      <description>My former colleagues in the New York Times Tech Guild have gone on strike in response to a number of unfair labor practice violations and management’s inability to bargain in good faith.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T16:20:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agents Craft Hackathon and Inspiration Block</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/agents-craft-hackathon-and-inspiration-block-88c1481d3043?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> When you want to do a hackathon but am missing the perfect&amp;nbsp;idea. Compliments of Flux.1&amp;nbsp;Schnell You likely know the saying, “Don’t let the perfect be the enemy of the good/done.” Sometimes, I have a hard time living that, and an existing effort is one example. I have registered for an AI agent hackathon, Agents Craft Hackathon. I don’t plan to be competitive but I doubt that is the goal o</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T13:18:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My IETF 121 Agenda</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2024/11/04/7/ietf-121</link>
      <description>Here's where you can find me at IETF 121 in Dublin!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T09:18:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core and Angular BFF using a YARP downstream API protected using certificate authentication</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/11/04/asp-net-core-and-angular-bff-using-a-yarp-downstream-api-protected-using-certificate-authentication/</link>
      <description>This article demonstrates how to implement a downstream API protected by certificate authentication using Microsoft YARP reverse proxy in an ASP.NET Core web application. The application uses Angular for its UI and secures both the UI and the ASP.NET Core backend through a backend-for-frontend security architecture. The downstream API is secured with certificate authentication and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T06:43:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Create Software Diagrams With ChatGPT and Claude</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/11/02/how-to-create-software-diagrams-with-chatgpt-and-claude/</link>
      <description>Earlier efforts to diagram software with LLM assistance weren’t fruitful, but this time around things went really well. I ended up with exactly what I needed to explain the architecture of a browser extension, and along the way I learned a lot about a couple of formats — Mermaid and Graphviz — as well as … Continue reading How To Create Software Diagrams With ChatGPT and Claude</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-02T15:18:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VSCode and Debugging Python in Virtual Environments</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/vscode-and-debugging-python-in-virtual-environments-d975125b455c?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>AI generated image of a&amp;nbsp;beetle This post is really for me more than anyone else. I will be able to come back here and find it. If it helps you as well, then&amp;nbsp;great.  I have historically not been a Python programmer. Additionally, I have historically used Visual Studio versus VSCode. Lately, I have been doing Python in VSCode. I need to learn my way&amp;nbsp;around.  I recently found how to deb</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-01T12:40:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Presentations at October 2024 OpenID Workshop and IIW plus New Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2584</link>
      <description>I gave the following presentation on work in the OpenID Connect working group at the Monday, October 28, 2024 OpenID Workshop at Microsoft: OpenID Connect Working Group Update (PowerPoint) (PDF) I also gave this invited “101” session presentation at the Internet Identity Workshop (IIW) on Tuesday, October 29, 2024: Introduction to OpenID Connect (PowerPoint) (PDF) […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 05:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-30T05:25:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGConf &amp;amp; Extension Ecosystem Summit EU 2024</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/10/pgconf-extension-summit-eu/</link>
      <description>Notes and links from the Extension Ecosystem Summit EU 2024 and my first time
at PGConf EU. Plus thoughts and photos from ancient sites and archeological
museums I visited.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 22:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-29T22:04:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Voting Secure?</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/is-voting-secure</link>
      <description>I'm fairly certain that what I write here won't change the minds that need changing. But I feel like I need to make a statement anyway: your vote is secure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-28T21:41:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrewAI, Simple Enough but It Once Made 100 API Calls Instead of 1</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/crewai-simple-enough-but-it-once-made-100-api-calls-instead-of-1-0e316da4a25c?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>AI generated crew image. Note that some folks are backwards.&amp;nbsp;:-) I continued my experimentation with CrewAI this weekend. To see the code, take a look at the following repo and path: Starter CrewAI Series and the day_04 folder specifically. In the day_04 package, I created a simple custom tool, one that uses Tavily. The two agent, two task package queries for news information on CrewAI and the</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-28T11:46:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earth Data Rescue 2025</title>
      <link>https://cybersocialstructure.org/2024/10/26/earth-data-rescue-2025/</link>
      <description>2016 was a different election: 2024 is so much more important The election of a climate-change denying US president in 2016 gave rise to the potential for administrative policies that would obstruct the public’s use of government-held Earth data. Very soon after taking office, the Trump administration instructed that government websites be scrubbed of climate … Continue reading Earth Data Rescue&amp;nb</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 16:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-26T16:21:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Claude and ChatGPT can see on your screen</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/10/25/what-claude-and-chatgpt-can-see-on-your-screen/</link>
      <description>“If you work with these cloud platforms every day, you have doubtless forgotten that you ever had questions like these. But every newcomer does. And on a continuing basis, we are all newcomers to various aspects of applications and services. In so many ways, the experience boils down to: I am here, what do I … Continue reading What Claude and ChatGPT can see on your screen</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 16:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-25T16:35:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPJ Head Condemns Israel's Deadly War on Journalists</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/10/24/cpj-head-condemns-israels-deadly-war-on-journalists/</link>
      <description>

 Jodie Ginsberg, CPJ’s chief executive officer: 

 
   No journalist from outside Gaza has been allowed in since the start of that war, and that’s highly unusual. I speak to lots of war correspondents who’s covered many, many wars over decades, and all of them talk about how unprecedented this is to not have any access whatsoever. And that, of course, puts additional pressure on these journalists</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 23:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-24T23:14:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LM Studio and CrewAI with Llama</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-lm-studio-and-crewai-with-llama-8f8e712e659b?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> I was recently experimenting with CrewAI, but in one experiment I wanted to use a local LLM hosted by LM Studio. Why LMStudio? Well… because that was the experiment. I wanted to see how I’d use LMStudio to host my model versus Ollama and then use it from CrewAI. Below is a very simple setup for doing&amp;nbsp;this.  It’s good to point out that CrewAI uses LiteLLM under the hood as a sort of proxy. Thi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-21T12:34:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement security headers for an ASP.NET Core API supporting OpenAPI Swagger UI</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/10/21/implement-security-headers-for-an-api-supporting-openapi-swagger-ui/</link>
      <description>This article shows how to implement security headers for an application supporting an API and a swagger UI created from a open API in .NET 9. The security headers are implemented using the NetEscapades.AspNetCore.SecurityHeaders Nuget packages from Andrew Lock. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/WebApiOpenApi Deploying a web application which supports both an API and a UI have different […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 07:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-21T07:26:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata Specification in RFC Editor Queue</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2582</link>
      <description>I’m pleased to report that the “OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata” specification has been approved by the IESG and is now in the RFC Editor queue. The version approved by the IESG and sent to the RFC Editor is: https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-oauth-resource-metadata-13.html It joins OAuth 2.0 Security Best Current Practice and JWT Response for OAuth Token Introspection, […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-17T19:05:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Greatly Exaggerated Demise of SSI: A Rebuttal to Premature Eulogies</title>
      <link>https://decentralgabe.xyz/the-greatly-exaggerated-demise-of-ssi-a-rebuttal-to-premature-eulogies/</link>
      <description>   💡  This is written in response to a post titled &quot;Why Verifiable Credentials Aren't Widely Adopted &amp;amp; Why Trinsic Pivoted&quot;   A forewarning—there will be no tears here and, please, no hugging. credit, XKCD https://xkcd.com/386/ The post I'm responding to </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 04:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-16T04:32:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Verifiable Credentials Aren’t Widely Adopted &amp; Why Trinsic Pivoted</title>
      <link>https://rileyparkerhughes.medium.com/why-verifiable-credentials-arent-widely-adopted-why-trinsic-pivoted-aee946379e3b?source=rss-bd548551c0bf------2</link>
      <description>A presentation I gave at IIW38, in April&amp;nbsp;2024. At the Internet Identity Workshop 38, I announced my talk with a description something like&amp;nbsp;this:  Five years ago at this conference, Trinsic’s first product (our self-sovereign identity wallet app) was launched. Today, I’m hosting a session called “SSI didn’t work. Trinsic is pivoting.”  I knew it was a provocative title — and I fully consid</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-15T16:49:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI “its got legs”</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-its-got-legs-49f6f3f54aea?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>Compliments of FLUX&amp;nbsp;schnell This last week I spoke with two folks on AI intersection within their work and how their work intersects with one another. One was a CPO for a startup that is bringing AI into their life sciences products in a forefront way. The other was a compliance manager for a pharma company. The second happens to be my wife. For me, their work intersects. They both certainly g</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 14:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-13T14:33:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/social/2024/10/12/77276/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 21:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-12T21:27:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mix Human Expertise With LLM Assistance for Easier Coding</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/10/10/mix-human-expertise-with-llm-assistance-for-easier-coding/</link>
      <description>There are plenty of ways to use LLMs ineffectively. For best results, lean into your own intelligence, experience, and creativity. Delegate the boring and routine stuff to closely supervised assistants whose work you can easily check. Mix Human Expertise With LLM Assistance for Easier Coding Part of the LLM series at The New Stack.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-10T23:37:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNAP: A Conversation of Authorization</title>
      <link>https://justinsecurity.medium.com/gnap-a-conversation-of-authorization-5b603d850fe9?source=rss-ce3fbf1372f2------2</link>
      <description> After five years of standardization work, GNAP is now officially RFC9635! This long and intense process actually started a few years prior to that, when I was talking with a lot of folks in the security industry about some of the shortcomings of OAuth 2.0, and what we could do about them as an industry. These conversations led to the XYZ proposal (and implementations) which eventually led to the f</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 19:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T19:50:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We fix the fucking networks</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/10/09/we-fix-the-fucking-networks/</link>
      <description>

 “A lot of us remember what it was like to live and work on an Internet that was deeply flawed but not systematically designed to burn our emotions and time and safety for fuel.” </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T18:45:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGXN v2 Update</title>
      <link>https://tembo.io/blog/pgxn-v2-update</link>
      <description>A lot has happened in he five months since the last PGXN v2 update. The time
has been used for continuing community discussions, planning, designs, and the
start of implementation. Read on for a full accounting.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 17:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T17:14:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGXN Certifications RFC</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/10/pgxn-certifications-rfc/</link>
      <description>A request for comments on a new PGXN RFC for signing releases, plus a link to
an initial implementation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 16:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T16:26:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>⛰️ Postgres Ecosystem Summit EU</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/10/postgres-ecosystem-summit-eu/</link>
      <description>The sequel to the successful PGConf.dev event, the Extension Ecosystem Summit
EU will showcases some exemplary extension use cases.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 15:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T15:27:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes It’s All About The Chunking</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/sometimes-its-all-about-the-chunking-a36eededa0ff?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> As I continue my study and experimentation with coding up AI solutions, and especially, at the moment, with Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), I decided to work with a post from the Metadocs blog titled “Simple Agentic RAG for Multi Vector stores with LangChain and LangGraph”. It seemed it would cover two areas of interest, agentic operations and RAG. Little did I expect to learn a valuable les</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-08T10:14:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The lessons learned in building a secure, scalable, and reliable identity platform @ DevRev</title>
      <link>https://medium.facilelogin.com/the-lessons-learned-in-building-a-secure-scalable-and-reliable-identity-platform-devrev-df62e52e89ad?source=rss----ed6963ed5bbe---4</link>
      <description>Image credits: https://www.networkrailmediacentre.co.uk/resources/ap-0409 At DevRev, we are building an API-first dev-centric platform that gives you one unified view of your customers and products by connecting your data, teams, and users to our AgentOS platform and app experiences. This blog post shares some insights into how we built (and keep evolving) a secure, scalable, and reliable identity </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 22:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-07T22:19:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/explaining-verifiable-credentials-and-open-badges-3-0-5bf2f482b383?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Part 1: The Trust Model of Open&amp;nbsp;Badges  When the Open Badges v 0.5 specification was first launched by the Mozilla Foundation in 2012, the intention was to recognize learning that happens at any time, anywhere, and any how. The trust of the badges was based on 1) the persistent hosting of the credential data and 2) the content of the credential in the context it was being evaluated (including</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 20:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-07T20:36:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Entra ID App-to-App security architecture</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/10/07/microsoft-entra-id-app-to-app-security-architecture/</link>
      <description>This article looks at the different setups when using App-to-App security with Microsoft Entra ID (OAuth client credentials). Microsoft Entra App registrations are used to configure the OAuth clients and resources. For each tenant, an Enterprise application is created for the client App registration when the consent is granted. The claims in the access token […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-07T07:25:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geothermal power in the North Bay</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/10/05/geothermal-power-in-the-north-bay/</link>
      <description>I was aware of The Geysers, a geothermal field about 35 miles north of my home in Santa Rosa, but I never gave it much thought until my first bike ride through the area. Then I learned a number of interesting things. It’s the world’s largest geothermal field, producing more than 700 megawatts. It accounts … Continue reading Geothermal power in the North Bay</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-05T18:42:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Connect specifications published as ISO standards</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2573</link>
      <description>I’m thrilled to report that the OpenID Connect specifications have now been published as ISO/IEC standards. They are: ISO/IEC 26131:2024 — Information technology — OpenID connect — OpenID connect core 1.0 incorporating errata set 2 ISO/IEC 26132:2024 — Information technology — OpenID connect — OpenID connect discovery 1.0 incorporating errata set 2 ISO/IEC 26133:2024 — […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-01T16:32:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s NotebookLM, RAG and Then Some</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/googles-notebookllm-rag-and-then-some-08b817d82417?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> I played around just a little bit with Google’s NotebookLM. It’s a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) tool. One thing it does is convert your content into a podcast format and it provides an impressive-sounding result. It's a little superficial on the content synthesis and definitely gimmicky, but it is a podcast after all. Its other features are your typical RAG chat interface. All I can say is</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 11:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-01T11:53:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a Vote Forward checklist</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/09/30/making-a-vote-forward-checklist/</link>
      <description>In How and why to write letters to voters I discussed Vote Forward, my favorite way for those of us who aren’t in swing states to reach out to voters in swing states. The site works really well for adopting batches of voters, and downloading packets of form letters. As I close in on 1000 … Continue reading Making a Vote Forward checklist</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 18:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-30T18:08:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk to Compensation Coach before signing showing agreement to maximize savings</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/talk-to-compensation-coach-before-signing-showing-agreement-to-maximize-savings/</link>
      <description> #LegalHackers: Know about the new role emerging at the start of real estate transactions because homebuyers are now being asked to sign an agreement before… 
The post Talk to Compensation Coach before signing showing agreement to maximize savings first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-27T00:48:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement a Geo-distance search using .NET Aspire, Elasticsearch and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/09/23/implement-a-geo-distance-search-using-net-aspire-elasticsearch-and-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>This article shows how to implement a geo location search in an ASP.NET Core application using a LeafletJs map. The selected location can be used to find the nearest location with an Elasticsearch Geo-distance query. The Elasticsearch container and the ASP.NET Core UI application are setup for development using .NET Aspire. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/WebGeoElasticsearch Setup For […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 08:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-23T08:56:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KERI Series: Understanding Self-Addressing Identifiers (SAID)</title>
      <link>https://kentbull.com/2024/09/22/keri-series-understanding-self-addressing-identifiers-said/</link>
      <description>What is a self addressing identifier, a SAID? What does this mean and how is a SAID created and verified? This post answers these questions. We show a generalized process for calculating SAIDs and delve into the encoding format for CESR-compliant self addressing identifiers. Examples with three popular algorithms, SHA2-256, […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 19:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-22T19:27:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic’s Contextual Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/anthropics-contextual-retrieval-11dbd16841b4?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> One of the problems I have encountered in trying to do Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) where a complete single document was not uploaded for queries on that document alone is that chunks created from documents for embedding often lose context. I have often considered what would be the outcome if one were to put some limited but useful context along with each chunk. Now I know. Introducing Ant</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 10:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-22T10:59:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>deo absente deum culpa</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/09/20/deo-absente-deum-culpa/</link>
      <description>On a recent trip I saw this pair of Latin phrases tattooed on the back of a flight attendant’s arms: Left: Deo absente. Right: Deum culpa. I took Latin in middle school, and could guess what the combination might mean. It’s not a common construction, and a search seems to confirm my guess. Both Google … Continue reading deo absente deum culpa</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 05:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-21T05:24:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL translation from Postgres to SQLite and DuckDB</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/09/20/sql-translation-from-postgres-to-sqlite-and-duckdb/</link>
      <description>Powerpipe dashboards can now connect not only to Steampipe but also to SQLite and DuckDB. This creates a combinatorial explosion of possibilities, including dashboards that use SQL to visualize large datasets read from Parquet files by DuckDB. SQL Translation From Postgres to SQLite and DuckDB Part of the LLM series at The New Stack.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-20T19:59:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask A [cybersecurity] Futurist</title>
      <link>https://heathervescent.medium.com/ask-a-cybersecurity-futurist-c0178a617317?source=rss-d2cae665ce3c------2</link>
      <description> Welcome to the inaugural “Ask a [cybersecurity] futurist column. This month’s question comes from Anna&amp;nbsp;Borg.  She asks:  How can we change the “rules in the game” and make it less interesting to use the internet for attacks on organisations and societies including democracy. We will never “win the game” if we are forced to play defence play 24/7, 365 days per year. How do we change the incent</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 23:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-16T23:35:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Elasticsearch with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/09/16/using-elasticsearch-with-net-aspire/</link>
      <description>This post shows how to use Elasticsearch in .NET Aspire. Elasticsearch is setup to use HTTPS with the dotnet developer certificates and and simple client can be implemented to query the data. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/keycloak-backchannel Setup Two services are setup to run in .NET Aspire. The first service is the official Elasticsearch docker container and deployed […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-09-16T04:24:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch: Postgres ABI and API Guidance</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/06/abi-api-guidance/</link>
      <description>Dear Postgres extension developers: Please review and give feedback on the
proposed patch adding ABI and API guidance to the C language documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-06-27T18:05:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>