<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Identosphere Identity Blogcatcher: Personal</title>
    <link>https://identosphere.com</link>
    <description>Personal blogs of individuals working in decentralized identity.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/15/todays-moral-dilemma-if-i.html</link>
      <description> **Today’s Moral Dilemma ** 
 If I transcribe an online meeting directly to text - no recording involved - and so certainly not stored … is that ok? </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 05:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-15T05:08:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Title Needed … But This Still Is A Title</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/15/no-title-needed-but-this.html</link>
      <description> Poking Wordland … 
 Reminder to self. 
 This is routing to Philpin.com which is currently flagged as an AI experiment. This is not an AI experiment. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 21:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T21:12:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/15/nicely-said.html</link>
      <description> 💬 Nicely said. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 21:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T21:09:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/15/073118.html</link>
      <description> 💬 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T19:31:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whether Weather</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/14/whether-weather/</link>
      <description>NOAA (The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration) is the alpha US source for weather forecasting, ocean science, climate research, and much more. So, as a weather geek, it concerns me when Wired says Dismantling NOAA Threatens the World’s Ability to Monitor Carbon Dioxide Levels: The agency maintains the global backbone of measurements of CO2 and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 18:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T18:15:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Kubernetes is Built with Kat Cosgrove</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-kubernetes-is-built-with-kat</link>
      <description>Kat Cosgrove shares what Kubernetes actually does, how it’s structured and scaled, and why it’s become one of the most successful open-source projects in the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 17:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T17:06:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World Is Wooing U.S. Researchers Shunned by Trump</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-world-is-wooing-us-researchers-shunned-by-trump</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Patricia Cohen in The New York Times]  This was inevitable:   &quot;As President Trump cuts billions of federal dollars from science institutes and universities, restricts what can be studied and pushes out immigrants, rival nations are hoping to pick up talent that has been cast aside or become disenchanted.&quot;   Salaries are lower in Europe, but quality of life is far higher - and,</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T13:37:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/15/roger.html</link>
      <description> 🔗📼 Roger </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T13:06:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/15/i-presume-that-the-uae.html</link>
      <description> I presume that The UAE has ‘taken one for the team’ and has become the 51st state and Canada is safe (at least until  the clown decides we need a 52nd). 
 This is the only explanation after learning today that the ‘500Bn Stargate initiative’ that Tяump announced 40 years ago just 4 months ago and was … 
 
 focused on spending $500 billion on new facilities in the U.S. to help OpenAI develop advanc</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T12:36:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitwoch</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/14/mitwoch/</link>
      <description>More lost privacy.&amp;nbsp;404 reports that Flock Safety, an automatic license plate reader (ALPR) company, &quot;is building a product that will use people lookup tools, data brokers, and data breaches to 'jump from LPR [license plate reader] to person,' allowing police to much more easily identify and track the movements of specific people around the country […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 12:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T12:35:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Innovation We Need is Strategic, Not Technical</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/05/the-innovation-we-need-is-strategic-not-technical.html</link>
      <description>In my recap of RSAC 2025, I referenced the open letter that Patrick Opet, CISO of JPMorgan Chase, published in which he spoke about how essential security guardrails are being broken down by the lack of secure-by-design thinking in modern integration patterns within the SaaS world. His open letter challenged Cloud and SaaS providers to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 03:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T03:58:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting James Cowling</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/14/james-cowling/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  I designed Dropbox's storage system and modeled its durability. Durability numbers (11 9's etc) are meaningless because competent providers don't lose data because of disk failures, they lose data because of bugs and operator error. [...] 
 The best thing you can do for your own durability is to choose a competent provider and then ensure you don't accidentally delete or corrupt own data on it: 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 03:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T03:49:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM 0.26a0 adds support for tools!</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/14/llm-adds-support-for-tools/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> LLM 0.26a0 adds support for tools! 
It's only an alpha so I'm not going to promote this extensively yet, but my LLM project just grew a feature I've been working towards for nearly two years now: tool support! 
 I'm presenting a workshop about Building software on top of Large Language Models at PyCon US tomorrow and this was the one feature I really needed to pull everything else together. 
 Tool</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 02:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T02:00:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building, launching, and scaling ChatGPT Images</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/13/launching-chatgpt-images/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Building, launching, and scaling ChatGPT Images 
Gergely Orosz landed a fantastic deep dive interview with OpenAI's Sulman Choudhry (head of engineering, ChatGPT) and Srinivas Narayanan (VP of engineering, OpenAI) to talk about the launch back in March of ChatGPT images - their new image generation mode built on top of multi-modal GPT-4o. 
 The feature kept on having new viral spikes, including on</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 23:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T23:52:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unrealities</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/13/unrealities/</link>
      <description>Developing the uncanny valley. HT to John Naughton&amp;nbsp;(whom God preserve*) for pointage to Mistral's Le Chat, an AI image-generatng chatbot. It's a good answer to the challenge of making AI art that doesn't look like AI art. *This is an HT as well, toward one of John's warm conventions. And subscribe to his 'stack. It's […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 23:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T23:07:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landmark Report Finds Major Flaws in the Cass Review</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/landmark-report-finds-major-flaws-in-the-cass-review</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Erin In The Morning]  Unsurprisingly, there are major flaws with the Cass Report - and an expert report in Springer Nature's BMC Medical Research Methodology puts a fine point on it.   &quot;The BMC study reviewed seven different facets of the Cass Review, and found that all seven possessed “a high risk of bias due to methodological limitations and a failure to adequately address t</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T22:46:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flipboard Expands Publisher Federation with International Partners</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/flipboard-expands-publisher-federation-with-international-partners</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Flipboard Expands Publisher Federation with International Partners]  Flipboard just launched 124 new publishers to the Fediverse - bringing the total number it hosts to 1,241.   &quot;We’re excited to announce that Flipboard is beginning to federate publisher accounts in France, Italy, and Spain, while also expanding federation in Brazil, Germany, and the U.K. — making quality jour</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 19:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T19:50:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 GSOC: Mankirat Singh — ABI Compliance Reporting</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/2025-gsoc/</link>
      <description>Please welcome 2025 Google Summer of Code contributor Mankirat Singh, who will
be developing an ABI compliance checker for the PostgreSQL maintenance
branches.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 18:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T18:25:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building, launching, and scaling ChatGPT Images</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/chatgpt-images</link>
      <description>ChatGPT Images is OpenAI’s biggest launch yet, with 100 million NEW users generating 700 million images in the first week. But how was it built? A deepdive with OpenAI’s engineering team</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T15:58:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian: “We’re Not Going to Charge Most Customers Extra for AI Anymore”. The Beginning of the End of the AI Upsell?</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/13/end-of-ai-upsells/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Atlassian: “We’re Not Going to Charge Most Customers Extra for AI Anymore”. The Beginning of the End of the AI Upsell? 
Jason Lemkin highlighting a potential new trend in the pricing of AI-enhanced SaaS: 
 
 Can SaaS and B2B vendors really charge even more for AI … when it’s become core?  And we’re already paying $15-$200 a month for a seat? [...] 
 You can try to charge more, but if the competiti</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T15:52:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vision Language Models (Better, Faster, Stronger)</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/13/vision-language-models/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Vision Language Models (Better, Faster, Stronger) 
Extremely useful review of the last year in vision and multi-modal LLMs. 
 So much has happened! I'm particularly excited about the range of small open weight vision models that are now available. Models like gemma3-4b-it and Qwen2.5-VL-3B-Instruct produce very impressive results and run happily on mid-range consumer hardware.

      Via @andimara</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T15:25:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms are now the Law of the Land</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2688</link>
      <description>I’m thrilled to be able to report that, from now on, only fully-specified algorithms will be registered for JOSE and COSE. Furthermore, fully-specified signature algorithms are now registered to replace the previously registered polymorphic algorithms, which are now deprecated. For example, you can now use Ed25519 and Ed448 instead of the ambiguous EdDSA. The new […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T14:23:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Luke Kanies</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/13/luke-kanies/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  I did find one area where LLMs absolutely excel, and I’d never want to be without them: 
 AIs can find your syntax error 100x faster than you can. 
 They’ve been a useful tool in multiple areas, to my surprise. But this is the one space where they’ve been an honestly huge help: I know I’ve made a mistake somewhere and I just can’t track it down. I can spend ten minutes staring at my files and pul</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 13:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T13:13:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise-Ready MCP</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2025/05/12/27/enterprise-ready-mcp</link>
      <description>I've seen a lot of complaints about how MCP isn't ready for the enterprise.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 05:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T05:01:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Contributing to Servo</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/12/contributing-to-servo/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Contributions must not include content generated by large language models or other probabilistic tools, including but not limited to Copilot or ChatGPT. This policy covers code, documentation, pull requests, issues, comments, and any other contributions to the Servo project. [...] 
 Our rationale is as follows: 
 Maintainer burden: Reviewers depend on contributors to write and test their code bef</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 22:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-12T22:14:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>o3 o4-mini o1-pro</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/12/o3/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> It's interesting how much my perception of o3 as being the latest, best model released by OpenAI is tarnished by the co-release of o4-mini. I'm also still not entirely sure how to compare o3 to o1-pro, especially given o1-pro is 15x more expensive via the OpenAI API. 

     Tags: o1, llm-reasoning, generative-ai, openai, o3, ai, llms </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 18:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-12T18:38:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions with client credentials flow using OAuth DPoP</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/05/12/implement-client-assertions-with-client-credentials-flow-using-oauth-dpop/</link>
      <description>This blog looks at implementing client assertions for the client credentials flow using OAuth 2.0 Demonstration of Proof-of-Possession (DPoP). The client credentials flow is an OAuth 2.0 authorization grant type used for machine-to-machine authentication. DPoP further strengthens the security by ensuring that the client possesses a specific key at the time of the request, forcing […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 05:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-12T05:42:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inflation</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/11/inflation/</link>
      <description>This is at Costco. In Indiana:</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 21:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T21:33:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/12/good-watch-people-who-treat.html</link>
      <description> 🔗📼 Good Watch 
 
 People who treat AI like a teammate, coach it and give it feedback and importantly, get it to ask them questions. The fundamental orientation a lot of people take towards AI is I’m the question asker. AI is the answer giver. But if you think about AI like a teammate, you say, hey, what are ten questions I should ask about this? Or what do you need to know from me in order to get </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 19:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T19:33:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cursor: Security</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/11/cursor-security/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Cursor: Security 
Cursor's security documentation page includes a surprising amount of detail about how the Cursor text editor's backend systems work. 
 I've recently learned that checking an organization's list of documented subprocessors is a great way to get a feel for how everything works under the hood - it's a loose &quot;view source&quot; for their infrastructure! That was how I confirmed that Anthro</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 19:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T19:15:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, Immigration Is Not An “Invasion”—And It Doesn’t Justify Suspending Habeas Corpus</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/no-immigration-is-not-an-invasionand-it-doesnt-justify-suspending</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mark Mansour]  Stephen Miller, who the author rightly labels as the most dangerous person in America, has argued for removing a core constitutional right for millions of people on American soil. He wants to classify unauthorized immigration as an &quot;invasion&quot;.  It's insane, and is the precursor to yet more truly authoritarian policies.  As Mark writes:   &quot;Even if one were to acc</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 14:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T14:39:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why New Jersey Prisons’ Change from JPay to ViaPath Tablets Is Distressing</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/why-new-jersey-prisons-change-from-jpay-to-viapath-tablets</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Shakeil Price at The Marshall Project]  The technology situation for incarcerated people in the United States is beyond bad:   &quot;Because prison telecom vendors tend to bundle their services, corrections systems often contract with a single provider, regardless of quality. And dozens of states make “commissions” from user fees. Within this context, incarcerated people become the</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 14:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T14:33:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motherings</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/11/tbds/</link>
      <description>Trump will be flying Qatar One instead of (or as) Air Force One: Aaaand,,,, Call your mother, if she’s still around. If she’s not, remember her anyway. I did that here. I’m pointing to A look at broadcast history happening because it came up in a conversation about archives. Also because that history (especially concerning […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 13:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T13:28:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community college tap dancer</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/11/tap-dancer/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Achievement unlocked: tap danced in the local community college dance recital. 

     Tags: dance </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 04:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-11T04:17:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poker Face season two on FanFare</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/10/poker-face/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Poker Face season two just started on Peacock (the US streaming service). It's my favorite thing on TV right now. I've started threads on MetaFilter FanFare for episodes one, two and three. 

     Tags: tv, metafilter </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 22:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T22:34:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Customers Hate You</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/10/how-to-make-customers-hate-you-2/</link>
      <description>Exhibit A: Welcome to negative option billing at work. Other labels include “sludge,” “dark patterns,” “gotcha pricing,” “subscription trapping,” and “bait-and-default.” Works like this: offer a service at a discount that jumps up to a high “regular” price after the discount runs out, and count on the customer forgetting when the jump happens. It’s a […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 20:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T20:36:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/11/the-age-of-experience-is.html</link>
      <description> 5 - The Age Of Experience Is Different 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T12:32:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/11/the-age-of-reason-has.html</link>
      <description> 4 - The Age Of Reason Has Ended 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T12:31:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/11/why-structured-thought.html</link>
      <description> 3 - Why Structured Thought 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T12:31:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/11/overcoming-the-limitations-of-visual.html</link>
      <description> 2 - Overcoming The Limitations Of Visual Thinking 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T12:30:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/11/a-history-of-visual-thinking.html</link>
      <description> 1 - A History of Visual Thinking 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T12:29:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🎥 The Wild Robot, 2024 - ★★★★</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/10/the-wild-robot.html</link>
      <description>    Home alone and had heard good things. Just lovely. Just wonderful. And yes, I cried. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 08:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T08:07:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying out llama.cpp's new vision support</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/10/llama-cpp-vision/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> This llama.cpp server vision support via libmtmd pull request - via Hacker News - was merged earlier today. The PR finally adds full support for vision models to the excellent llama.cpp project. It's documented on this page, but the more detailed technical details are covered here. Here are my notes on getting it working on a Mac. 
 llama.cpp models are usually distributed as .gguf files. This pro</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T06:29:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: SQLite triggers</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/10/til-sqlite-triggers/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> TIL: SQLite triggers 
I've been doing some work with SQLite triggers recently while working on sqlite-chronicle, and I decided I needed a single reference to exactly which triggers are executed for which SQLite actions and what data is available within those triggers. 
 I wrote this triggers.py script to output as much information about triggers as possible, then wired it into a TIL article using </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 05:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-10T05:20:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llm -f issue:... -m echo --no-log</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/9/private-issues/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I had some notes in a GitHub issue thread in a private repository that I wanted to export as Markdown. I realized that I could get them using a combination of several recent projects. 
 Here's what I ran: 
 export GITHUB_TOKEN=&quot;$(llm keys get github)&quot;                                             
llm -f issue:https://github.com/simonw/todos/issues/170 \
  -m echo --no-log | jq .prompt -r &amp;gt; notes</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 18:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T18:55:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Is Not Your Friend</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/ai-is-not-your-friend</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mike Caulfield in The Atlantic]  A smart analysis and suggestion about the current state of AI by Mike Caulfield:   &quot;I would propose a simple rule: no answers from nowhere. This rule is less convenient, and that’s the point. The chatbot should be a conduit for the information of the world, not an arbiter of truth.  [...] I am proposing that rather than act like an opinionated </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T16:38:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you want to use Digital Credentials? You’re now facing a myriad of choices!</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2679</link>
      <description>I gave the keynote talk So you want to use Digital Credentials? You’re now facing a myriad of choices! at EIC 2025. I opened by describing engineering choices – credential formats (W3C VCs, ISO mDOCs, SD-JWTs, SD-CWTs, JWPs, X.509 Certificates), issuance and presentation mechanisms (bespoke and standards-based, in-person and remote), mechanisms for choosing them (query […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 15:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T15:20:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Tabs</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/09/future-tabs/</link>
      <description>Stay Calm and Check it out. Pure libertarians are neither right nor left, nor where the extremes of both meet. Mostly they come from a sensibility outside both redstream and mainstream: one that PJ O'Roarke put perfectly in Parliament of Whores: &quot;The Democrats are the party that says government will make you smarter, taller, richer, […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 15:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T15:13:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sqlite-utils 4.0a0</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/9/sqlite-utils-40a0/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> sqlite-utils 4.0a0 
New alpha release of sqlite-utils, my Python library and CLI tool for manipulating SQLite databases. 
 It's the first 4.0 alpha because there's a (minor) backwards-incompatible change: I've upgraded the .upsert() and .upsert_all() methods to use SQLIte's UPSERT mechanism, INSERT INTO ... ON CONFLICT DO UPDATE. Details in this issue. 
 That feature was added to SQLite in version</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 04:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T04:02:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 2.5 Models now support implicit caching</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/9/gemini-implicit-caching/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Gemini 2.5 Models now support implicit caching 
I just spotted a cacheTokensDetails key in the token usage JSON while running a long chain of prompts against Gemini 2.5 Flash - despite not configuring caching myself: 
 {&quot;cachedContentTokenCount&quot;: 200658, &quot;promptTokensDetails&quot;: [{&quot;modality&quot;: &quot;TEXT&quot;, &quot;tokenCount&quot;: 204082}], &quot;cacheTokensDetails&quot;: [{&quot;modality&quot;: &quot;TEXT&quot;, &quot;tokenCount&quot;: 200658}], &quot;thought</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 02:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T02:46:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLite CREATE TABLE: The DEFAULT clause</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/8/sqlite-create-table-default-timestamp/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> SQLite CREATE TABLE: The DEFAULT clause 
If your SQLite create table statement includes a line like this: 
 CREATE TABLE alerts (
    -- ...
    alert_created_at text default current_timestamp
)
 
 current_timestamp will be replaced with a UTC timestamp in the format 2025-05-08 22:19:33. You can also use current_time for HH:MM:SS and current_date for YYYY-MM-DD, again using UTC. 
 Posting this her</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 22:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T22:37:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Claude's system prompt</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/8/claudes-system-prompt/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  If Claude is asked to count words, letters, and characters, it thinks step by step before answering the person. It explicitly counts the words, letters, or characters by assigning a number to each. It only answers the person once it has performed this explicit counting step. [...] 
 If Claude is shown a classic puzzle, before proceeding, it quotes every constraint or premise from the person’s mes</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 22:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T22:32:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reservoir Sampling</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/8/reservoir-sampling/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Reservoir Sampling 
Yet another outstanding interactive essay by Sam Rose (previously), this time explaining how reservoir sampling can be used to select a &quot;fair&quot; random sample when you don't know how many options there are and don't want to accumulate them before making a selection. 
 
 Reservoir sampling is one of my favourite algorithms, and I've been wanting to write about it for years now. It</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 21:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T21:00:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Oleg Pustovit</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/8/oleg-pustovit/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Microservices only pay off when you have real scaling bottlenecks, large teams, or independently evolving domains. Before that? You’re paying the price without getting the benefit: duplicated infra, fragile local setups, and slow iteration.  
 — Oleg Pustovit, Microservices Are a Tax Your Startup Probably Can’t Afford 

     Tags: software-architecture, startups, microservices </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 19:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T19:30:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #133: Apps rushing to add web payments on iOS</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-133-app-rushing-to-add</link>
      <description>Apple fighting Spotify, Kindle, Patreon, and other apps add web payment buttons to iOS apps. Also: the downside of feature flags, Big Tech generates 20-30% of code with AI tools, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T16:31:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I started fresh</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/if-i-started-fresh</link>
      <description> 
   Erin and I stood at the front of the room, our seven-minute pitch slides for Known still projected above us. At the wooden table in front of us, investors and media executives prepared to give us unfiltered feedback about what we’d just presented to them. Beyond them, an audience of entrepreneurs, more investors, and other enthusiasts were raising their hands.  “Does your excitement outweigh y</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T15:53:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ashley Willis</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/8/ashley-willis/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  But I’ve also had my own quiet concerns about what [vibe coding] means for early-career developers. So much of how I learned came from chasing bugs in broken tutorials and seeing how all the pieces connected, or didn’t. There was value in that. And maybe I’ve been a little protective of it. 
 A mentor challenged that. He pointed out that debugging AI generated code is a lot like onboarding into a</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 12:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T12:10:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Musk Massacre</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/05/07/the-musk-massacre/</link>
      <description>The great adventure of my birth family was the fifteen months we lived in New Delhi, from June of 1961, on a USAID-sponsored educational mission. So the destruction of USAID feels personal. I’m only now realizing that we were there at the very beginning of USAID, during what Jackie Kennedy later mythologized as the Camelot … Continue reading The Musk Massacre</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 05:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T05:52:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llm-gemini 0.19.1</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/8/llm-gemini-0191/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-gemini 0.19.1 
Bugfix release for my llm-gemini plugin, which was recording the number of output tokens (needed to calculate the price of a response) incorrectly for the Gemini &quot;thinking&quot; models. Those models turn out to return candidatesTokenCount and thoughtsTokenCount as two separate values which need to be added together to get the total billed output token count. Full details in this issu</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 05:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T05:49:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing web search on the Anthropic API</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/7/anthropic-api-search/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Introducing web search on the Anthropic API 
Anthropic's web search (presumably still powered by Brave) is now also available through their API, in the shape of a new web search tool called web_search_20250305. 
 You can specify a maximum number of uses per prompt and you can also pass a list of disallowed or allowed domains, plus hints as to the user's current location. 
 Search results are retur</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 23:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T23:25:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create and edit images with Gemini 2.0 in preview</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/7/gemini-images-preview/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Create and edit images with Gemini 2.0 in preview 
Gemini 2.0 Flash has had image generation capabilities for a while now, and they're now available via the paid Gemini API - at 3.9 cents per generated image. 
 According to the API documentation you need to use the new gemini-2.0-flash-preview-image-generation model ID and specify {&quot;responseModalities&quot;:[&quot;TEXT&quot;,&quot;IMAGE&quot;]} as part of your request. 
 </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 22:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T22:49:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medium is the new large</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/7/medium-is-the-new-large/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Medium is the new large 
New model release from Mistral - this time closed source/proprietary. Mistral Medium claims strong benchmark scores similar to GPT-4o and Claude 3.7 Sonnet, but is priced at $0.40/million input and $2/million output - about the same price as GPT 4.1 Mini. For comparison, GPT-4o is $2.50/$10 and Claude 3.7 Sonnet is $3/$15. 
 The model is a vision LLM, accepting both images</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 21:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T21:14:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llm-prices.com</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/7/llm-prices/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-prices.com 
I've been maintaining a simple LLM pricing calculator since October last year. I finally decided to split it out to its own domain name (previously it was hosted at tools.simonwillison.net/llm-prices), running on Cloudflare Pages. 
  
 The site runs out of my simonw/llm-prices GitHub repository. I ported the history of the old llm-prices.html file using a vibe-coded bash script tha</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T20:15:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>astral-sh/ty</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/7/ty/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> astral-sh/ty 
Astral have been working on this &quot;extremely fast Python type checker and language server, written in Rust&quot; quietly but in-the-open for a while now. Here's the first alpha public release - albeit not yet announced - as ty on PyPI (nice donated two-letter name!) 
 You can try it out via uvx like this - run the command in a folder full of Python code and see what comes back: 
 uvx ty ch</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 18:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T18:37:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Windsurf with Varun Mohan</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/building-windsurf-with-varun-mohan</link>
      <description>Varun Mohan, CEO of Windsurf, shares how building an AI-native IDE is reshaping software development—from optimizing LLM latency to enabling non-engineers to ship code.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T16:32:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI of dead Arizona road rage victim addresses killer in court</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/ai-of-dead-arizona-road-rage-victim-addresses-killer-in</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Cy Neff in The Guardian]  This is straight out of Black Mirror:   &quot;Chris Pelkey was killed in a road rage shooting in Chandler, Arizona, in 2021.  Three-and-a-half years later, Pelkey appeared in an Arizona court to address his killer. Sort of.  [...] Pelkey’s appearance from beyond the grave was made possible by artificial intelligence in what could be the first use of AI to </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-07T14:35:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/07/what-brad-said-but-until.html</link>
      <description> What Brad said - but until you have heard this cover - you haven’t heard Creep 🤯🎵 by @bradbarrish 
 
 I’ve heard “Creep” too many times, but seeing Erin Morton perform it gave me chills and made me cry. Just wow. 
 
 &amp;nbsp; </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 20:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T20:07:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sovereignty v Journalism</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/05/sovereignty-v-journalism.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;Some things repeat, without end... functional Sovereignty beats paid/fake Journalism daily.       </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T19:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/07/i-just-recorded-a-day.html</link>
      <description> I just recorded a 1300 day streak on Readwise. Hard to believe it has been that long! </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 19:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T19:49:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What's the carbon footprint of using ChatGPT?</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/6/whats-the-carbon-footprint-of-using-chatgpt/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> What's the carbon footprint of using ChatGPT? 
Inspired by Andy Masley's cheat sheet (which I linked to last week) Hannah Ritchie explores some of the numbers herself. 
 Hanah is Head of Research at Our World in Data, a Senior Researcher at the University of Oxford (bio) and maintains a prolific newsletter on energy and sustainability so she has a lot more credibility in this area than Andy or mys</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 19:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T19:47:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saying &quot;hi&quot; to Microsoft's Phi-4-reasoning</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/6/phi-4-reasoning/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Microsoft released a new sub-family of models a few days ago: Phi-4 reasoning. They introduced them in this blog post celebrating a year since the release of Phi-3: 
 
 Today, we are excited to introduce Phi-4-reasoning, Phi-4-reasoning-plus, and Phi-4-mini-reasoning - marking a new era for small language models and once again redefining what is possible with small and efficient AI. 
 
 All three </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 18:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T18:25:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 2.5 Pro Preview: even better coding performance</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/6/gemini-25-pro-preview/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Gemini 2.5 Pro Preview: even better coding performance 
New Gemini 2.5 Pro &quot;Google I/O edition&quot; model, released a few weeks ahead of that annual developer conference.  
 They claim even better frontend coding performance, highlighting their #1 ranking on the WebDev Arena leaderboard, notable because it knocked Claude 3.7 Sonnet from that top spot. They also highlight &quot;state-of-the-art video unders</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 18:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T18:09:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Changed in 50 Years of Computing: Part 4</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/mythical-man-month-part-4</link>
      <description>Is the landmark software engineering book ‘The Mythical Man-Month’ still relevant today, and what’s changed during half a century of computing in dev productivity, shipping of projects, and docs?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T15:55:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms Specification Addressing IESG Feedback</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2671</link>
      <description>Orie Steele and I have updated the “Fully-Specified Algorithms for JOSE and COSE” specification to address feedback received through directorate reviews and from Internet Engineering Steering Group (IESG) members. This prepares us for consideration of the specification by the IESG during its “telechat” on Thursday. This is an important milestone towards progressing the specification to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T14:00:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overhearings</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/06/overhearings/</link>
      <description>Strange but true enough. Why I've been farting less in 1996. From the Undersecretaries of Overstate. My phone bings with notifications from my weather apps saying there is a Dense Fog Advisory in effect—just as the clouds part and vanish, opening a clear blue sky and a bright new day. Where weather forecasts used to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 12:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T12:48:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 5: Extension Management in CNPG</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306551747/</link>
      <description>The last Mini-Summit of the year features Gabriele Bartolini talking about
extension management in CloudNativePG.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 21:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T21:51:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Offing of What’s On</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/05/the-offing-of-whats-on/</link>
      <description>For the final seven decades of the last millennium, most people in the developed world scheduled their evenings by answering a simple question: What’s on? For the first two of those decades, the question was “What’s on the radio?” For the next five, it was “What’s on TV?” Guidance toward answers were provided on newspaper […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 18:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T18:31:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSAC 2025: AI is Everywhere. Trust? Not So Much.</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/05/rsac-2025-ai-is-everywhere-trust-not-so-much.html</link>
      <description>Just wrapped up a packed, somewhat frenetic, but mostly enjoyable RSAC 2025 Conference. And if I had to sum it up in a sentence: AI is everywhere, but trust and control are still catching up. The conference opened with a shot fired across the bow of the security and identity industry. Patrick Opet, CISO of […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T15:42:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departments of Correction</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/05/05/departments-of-correction/</link>
      <description>Fortunately, we've already got it here: unlimited 2GB/s symmetrical service for $59/month.&amp;nbsp;Bloomington's city fiber rollout has been paused by the mayor. Here's&amp;nbsp;square's story about it, which is also in Bloomdocs—an example of a news commons at work. One more reason to move off Chrome?&amp;nbsp;A URL that begins with&amp;nbsp;chrome-extension://efwhaddfugisallthisjiveepwnj/ before it gets to http</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T15:07:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/05/the-tiktoktincan-rolls-again.html</link>
      <description> The ‘TikTokTinCan’ Rolls Again </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 11:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T11:18:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/05/i-wonder-how-much-of.html</link>
      <description> I wonder how much of the stage you could see .. let alone Gaga ..  if you were the last to arrive and you had 2.5 million people in front of you? </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 20:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T20:03:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/losing-an-election-is-one.html</link>
      <description> Losing an election is one thing. Party leader losing their seat? That’s next level. Congrats, Australia and Canada. 
 Dear Winston &amp;amp; David: some thing to ponder. Enjoy the wave ripple while it lasts … because the guy in the White House? He’s only getting worse, and it’s all downhill from here. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 03:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T03:11:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/preet-talking-to-ian-bremmer.html</link>
      <description> Preet talking to Ian Bremmer .. sensible talk. 
 🔗🎙️Listen </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 02:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T02:51:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/christopher-lydon-tump-a-real.html</link>
      <description> Christopher Lydon … Tяump a real life Great Gatsby 100 years later❓ 
 🔗🎙️Listen </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 02:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T02:48:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/i-just-found-this-in.html</link>
      <description> I just found this in my notes with no attribution - but looks like 🔗 Semaphor 
 
 South Africa is among the nations that have sought counsel from Goldman Sachs on how to improve ties with Washington. According to The Wall Street Journal, the bank advised Pretoria — which has been in the White House’s crosshairs for months over its close ties to Russia and its genocide case against Israel at the In</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T00:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/mac-filefinding-gems-from-brett.html</link>
      <description> Mac File-Finding Gems from 🔗 Brett Terpstrabrett.trpstra.net/link/535/…) - I particulalry liked the look of auto tagging in  HoudahSpot. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T00:49:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Isaac Asimov</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/about-isaac-asimov.html</link>
      <description>Prompted by a William Gallagher post, A short take on Asimov, memory, and how storytelling evolves. “it’s not the colour of the pill, but the effect”. … A reflection on reading, writing, and what still holds up.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T00:27:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/what-civilization-can-learn-from.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 What Civilization Can Learn from Pizza - posted this earlier on - because i do like Gaping Void - but this one …
 
 … stands to be corrected. 
 Here’s the thing. Communication is 
 
 the imparting or exchanging of information by speaking, writing, or using some other medium. 
 
 or even 
 
 means of sending or receiving information, such as phone lines or computers. 
 
 **Might I suggest a third</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-04T00:15:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/05/04/too-funny.html</link>
      <description> ￼￼￼Too funny 
  
 via 🔗 Helen Lewis </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 23:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-03T23:45:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 4 Transcript: The User POV</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/2025-mini-summit-four/</link>
      <description>Last week Floor Drees moderated a panel on “The User POV” at the fourth
Extension Mini-Summit. Read on for the transcript and link to the video.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T21:02:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving the Team</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/evolving-the-team</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Andy Piper at Mastodon]  It’s really exciting to see these new movements from Mastodon - not least because they’re very intentionally marching to their own rhythm. Mastodon wouldn’t be a good fit for being a standard tech company, and it won’t be one.    “Mastodon has taken the strategic decision not to accept venture capital investments for growth, but rather restructure to a</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 18:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T18:50:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Need to Talk About AI's Impact on Public Health</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/we-need-to-talk-about-ais-impact-on-public-health</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Adam Wierman and Shaolei Ren in IEEE Spectrum]  An interesting finding on the energy use implicit in training and offering AI services. I do think some of these principles could apply to all of cloud computing - it’s out of sight and out of mind, but certainly uses a great deal of power. Still, there’s no doubt that AI isn’t exactly efficient, and as detailed below, is a signi</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T15:41:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #132: “Apple Tax” must end NOW, court rules</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-132</link>
      <description>Also: Judge says Apple ignored a court injunction and lied under oath, Cursor’s incredible growth comes with AI troubles, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 13:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T13:59:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Million Italian Digital Wallet Users</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2666</link>
      <description>My friend Giuseppe De Marco shared the article “Documenti su IO: 5 milioni di attivazioni per IT-Wallet” with me about how five million people are now using the Italian digital wallet. It adds the information that 4.3 million health cards, 4 million driver’s licenses and 100,000 European Disability Cards have been issued to those wallets. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T10:37:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Case For Ethical and Transparent Research Experiments in the Public Interest - Coalition for Independent Technology Research</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/a-case-for-ethical-and-transparent-research-experiments-in-the</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [By Sarah Gilbert, Michael Zimmer, and Nathan Matias at the Coalition for Independent Technology Research]  A strong statement from the Coalition for Independent Technology Research:   &quot;On April 26, moderators of r/ChangeMyView, a community on Reddit dedicated to understanding the perspectives of others, revealed that academic researchers from the University of Zürich conducted</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 22:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-30T22:10:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to work better with Product, as an Engineer with Ebi Atawodi</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-to-work-better-with-product-as</link>
      <description>Ebi Atawodi, Director at YouTube Studio, shares strategies from Uber and Netflix on building strong product-engineering partnerships, fostering trust, and unlocking team innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 17:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-30T17:39:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Subreddit Statement: The Attack on U.S. Research Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/joint-subreddit-statement-the-attack-on-us-research-infrastructure</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Joint Subreddit statement posted on r/AskHistorians]  30 or so Reddit communities have joined together to make a joint statement in defense of US research. This comes from people with real expertise: in addition to the depth of research talent involved in these communities, Dan Howlett has signed the statement, with CAT Lab's Sarah Gilbert contributing.   &quot;The NIH is seeking t</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 03:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-30T03:38:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Unethical’ AI Study Reveals Terrifying New Threat to All Digital Discourse</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/when-robots-lie-unethical-ai-study-reveals-dangerous-new-threats-to-digital-discourse-4c9fee096444?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Ethical Hot&amp;nbsp;Water  Researchers at the University of Zurich have been formally reprimanded by the university after not disclosing their use of AI in a fascinating and scarily conclusive study:  AI can change people’s minds 6X more effectively than humans&amp;nbsp;can.  The ethical dilemma: the best way to accurately determine some AI threats may be for study subjects to not know they’re interactin</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 03:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-30T03:00:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics for software engineers: humanoid robots</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/humanoid-robots</link>
      <description>Why are humanoid robots becoming popular, and which skills make for a great robotics engineer? Guest post by Humanoid Robot Learning Researcher, Sandor Felber</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 12:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-29T12:30:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Must it always be Virtual?</title>
      <link>https://idm-thoughtplace.blogspot.com/2025/04/must-it-always-be-virtual.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;  
  The
only constant in life is change
  
 
	-Heraclitus.&amp;nbsp;
 
    

 

 
 
One of the things that most people in the Identity field know about
me is that I am a huge fan of Virtual Directory Services (VDS). But
it’s possible this is starting to
change. It’s also entirely
possible that working with the technologies at Ping Identity every
day has something to do with this. 1    
 
What I</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-29T00:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update Your Control Files</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/update-control/</link>
      <description>Suggestions to PostgreSQL extension maintainers to make some tweaks to your
.control files and Makefiles.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 20:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-28T20:08:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soll ich der elektronischen Patientenakte widersprechen und wie geht das?</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/soll-ich-der-elektronischen-patientenakte-widersprechen-und-wie-geht-das/</link>
      <description> Wenn du gesetzlich krankenversichert bist, stellt deine Krankenkasse ab 29.04.2025 eine elektronische Patientenakte für dich bundesweit bereit – es sei denn, du widersprichst. Durch einen Widerspruch dürfen dir keine Nachteile entstehen. … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-28T09:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Public Key Encryption (HPKE) for JOSE incorporating feedback from IETF 122</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2657</link>
      <description>The “Use of Hybrid Public-Key Encryption (HPKE) with JSON Object Signing and Encryption (JOSE)” specification has updated to incorporate feedback from IETF 122 in Bangkok. Per the History entries, the changes were: Use &quot;enc&quot;:&quot;int&quot; for integrated encryption. Described the reasons for excluding authenticated HPKE. Stated that mutually known private information MAY be used as the […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T00:27:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $20,000 American-made electric pickup with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-20000-american-made-electric-pickup-with-no-paint-no-stereo</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Tim Stevens at The Verge]  It's rare these days that I see a new product and think, this is really cool, but seriously, this is really cool:   &quot;Meet the Slate Truck, a sub-$20,000 (after federal incentives) electric vehicle that enters production next year. It only seats two yet has a bed big enough to hold a sheet of plywood. It only does 150 miles on a charge, only comes in </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 13:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-25T13:30:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump ‘Alarmists’ Were Right. We Should Say So.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/trump-alarmists-were-right-we-should-say-so</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Toby Buckle at LiberalCurrents]  This resonates for me too.  About the Tea Party, the direction the Republican Party took during the Obama administration, and then of Trump first riding down the escalator to announce his candidacy:   &quot;If you saw in any of this a threat to liberal democracy writ large, much less one that could actually succeed, you were looked at with the kind </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-24T14:53:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IIW Participants Value Most</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/what-iiw-participants-value-most</link>
      <description>Last week, I posted a report on IIW XL, our fortieth event.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T21:52:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata is now RFC 9728</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2653</link>
      <description>The OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata specification has been published as RFC 9728! This is certainly the longest that any RFC that I have worked on has taken from initial individual draft to RFC – August 2016 to April 2025 – 8 years and 8 months. As we discussed at the 2025 OAuth Security Workshop […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T21:27:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grumpy morning thoughts</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/grumpy-morning-thoughts</link>
      <description> 
 I earn 5-10X what I did when I lived in the UK, but my quality of life is markedly worse. My whole thing boils down to: how can America have the same standard of living I grew up with?  For a lot of people, the idea of prosperity boils down to, “I can buy what I want,” not, “I can live how I want.” The latter is the one that matters: that’s what freedom actually is.  National healthcare works (o</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 12:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T12:58:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Reddit’s iOS and Android app</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/building-reddits-ios-and-android</link>
      <description>Reddit’s mobile engineers share how they completely rebuilt the iOS and Android app, introducing a new core tech stack, modern architecture, and improved testing strategies at massive scale.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T12:56:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than one million readers</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/one-million</link>
      <description>A massive milestone hit, which seemed barely possible when I launched The Pragmatic Engineer Newsletter a little over 3 years ago...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T14:58:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building our &quot;native-AI newsroom&quot;</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/building-our-native-ai-newsroom</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Henry Blodget]  Henry Blodget, former co-founder of Business Insider, has started a new, &quot;AI-native&quot; newsroom. It's not, in my opinion, a positive use of AI, but it does indicate how some people are thinking about using the technology.  This apparently includes harassing your newly-created virtual employees:   &quot;This might be an inappropriate and unprofessional thing to say. An</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T13:41:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 4: The User POV</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306682918/</link>
      <description>Join our fine panel on Wednesday at Extension Mini Summit #4 to hear all about
“The User POV” — for better and for worse!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T17:26:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Identity Workshop XL Report</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/internet-identity-workshop-xl-report</link>
      <description>This past week, we held the 40th Internet Identity Workshop—a milestone event that brought together a global community of builders, dreamers, and implementers focused on the future of digital identity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T14:10:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions for OAuth client credential flows in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/04/21/implement-client-assertions-for-oauth-client-credential-flows-in-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>This blog implements client assertions using an OAuth client credential flow in ASP.NET Core. Client assertions provide a secure way for client authentication without sharing a secret, enhancing the security the OAuth client credentials flow. By using JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) client assertions, this approach ensures strong client identity (application) verification and mitigates risks associated […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 08:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T08:24:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elf — A Social Card Game of Collaboration, Deception, and Suspense</title>
      <link>https://theblockstalk.medium.com/elf-a-social-card-game-of-collaboration-deception-and-suspense-730c107bccf3?source=rss-d8f296833e37------2</link>
      <description> Elf — A Social Card Game of Collaboration, Deception, and&amp;nbsp;Suspense  In 2015, deep in Patagonia, I was taught a unique and little-known card game called by a group of Israeli travelers they called Elf. Since then, while teaching it to friends, family and complete strangers it has captivated the hearts of all players! To this day, it remains undocumented — until&amp;nbsp;now.  Elf is a hybrid of te</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 19:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T19:26:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The goal of a protest song is to make people feel strong and alive’: Ani DiFranco on Broadway, Fugazi and 30 years of activism</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-goal-of-a-protest-song-is-to-make-people</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Ani DiFranco interviewed by Kate Hutchinson in The Guardian]  Ani DiFranco, the artist I've seen live more than any other, answered my question as part of this Guardian Q&amp;amp;A. It's about a sobering topic, but still, this made me very happy.  Here's what I asked:   &quot;Woody Guthrie wrote “this machine kills fascists” on his guitar as a symbol of the power of words and music to </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 21:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-19T21:43:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOGE Is Building a Master Database to Surveil and Track Immigrants</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/doge-is-building-a-master-database-to-surveil-and-track</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Makena Kelly and Vittoria Elliott at WIRED]  The Holocaust was organized on IBM punch cards. Hitler gave the head of IBM, Watson, a medal for his services; they met in person so that Watson could receive the award. Later, they named their AI tech after him.  Anyway, in unrelated news:   &quot;DOGE is knitting together immigration databases from across DHS and uploading data from ou</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 13:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-19T13:27:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPICEy Developments</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2650</link>
      <description>This week saw several useful developments in the IETF Secure Patterns for Internet CrEdentials (SPICE) working group. Two new drafts were adopted and an individual draft was published also intended for later adoption by the working group. Here’s the tour… GLobal Unique Enterprise (GLUE) Identifiers was adopted. The specification’s abstract is: This specification establishes an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T23:19:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I ran Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/if-i-ran-mastodon</link>
      <description> 
   This is the second part in a three-part series. Part one was about Bluesky. To make sure you get part three, make sure you’re subscribed.  In 2011, I sat on a panel at SXSW Interactive with Blaine Cook, the former Twitter CTO who had demonstrated an decentralized integration with the social media platform Jaiku, and Christian Sandvig, who at the time was the founder of the Center for People an</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 18:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T18:54:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Halts Data Collection on Drug Use, Maternal Mortality, Climate Change, More</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/trump-halts-data-collection-on-drug-use-maternal-mortality-climate</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Alec MacGillis at ProPublica]  The statistics that help us navigate our world are under thread:   &quot;Every year, year after year, workers in agencies that many of us have never heard of have been amassing the statistics that undergird decision-making at all levels of government and inform the judgments of business leaders, school administrators and medical providers nationwide. </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T17:54:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #131: why is every company is launching its own coding agent?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-131</link>
      <description>Also: CVE program nearly axed, restored at the 11th hour, Rippling rescinds signed offer the candidate-to-join already handed in their resignation, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 17:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-17T17:03:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Call: “Cosmetic” changes in MLSpin delivering consumer savings?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/last-call-cosmetic-changes-in-mlspin-delivering-consumer-savings/</link>
      <description> The clock is ticking on the Nosalek vs MLSpin lawsuit, one of an estimated 20 against the real estate cartel (aka #RECartel), but arguably the… 
The post Last Call: “Cosmetic” changes in MLSpin delivering consumer savings? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-17T14:59:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creator economy businesses - a correction</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/creative-economy-businesses---a-correction</link>
      <description> 
 I realized I misspoke in today’s piece about Bluesky product strategy. In it, I said this:   I’m generally not bullish about creator economy services.   What I meant to say is that I’m generally not bullish about venture-funded creative economy services. It’s the need for venture scale and sky-high valuations that makes these a tough nut to crack. In a vacuum, there’s nothing wrong with these bu</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 23:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T23:03:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fix Postgres strchrnul Compile Error on macOS 15.4</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/fix-postgres-strchrnul/</link>
      <description>A fix for the error: 'strchrnul' is only available on macOS 15.4 or newer
Postgres compile error.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T19:03:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working at Amazon as a software engineer – with Dave Anderson</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/working-at-amazon-as-a-software-engineer</link>
      <description>Dave Anderson, formerly Tech Director at Amazon, shares an inside look at Amazon's engineering culture—from hiring and promotions to team autonomy and extreme frugality.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T17:02:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I ran Bluesky Product</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/if-i-ran-bluesky-product</link>
      <description> 
   A lifetime or two ago, Biz Stone was showing me and my co-founder around South Park in San Francisco. The Twitter office was sat there, a weird building with glass bricks across the road from what would later be the Instagram office. We grabbed a coffee at Caffe Centro and talked social media; two founders talking shop with a member of our advisory board.  He was particularly excited about the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T15:36:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where we're at</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/where-were-at</link>
      <description> 
 A quick aside:  I now believe it’s going to get a lot worse before it gets better (if it gets better). I’m not going to enumerate what’s been going on; you’re either paying attention or you’re not, but we’re less than one hundred days in and the lurch towards real fascism has been notable.  24 years ago, we experienced a lurch towards a surveillance state in the wake of 9/11. George W Bush, thro</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 11:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T11:41:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Policy Languages Feel So Hard?</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/why-do-policy-languages-feel-so-hard</link>
      <description>Permit.io just published the results of a survey they conducted with over 200 developers on access control. There's lots of good data there, but one thing that struck me is that over 50% of developers said that they've never used any of the popular policy languages. I was wondering why that could be and came up with a few reasons why policy languages often feel foreign and frustrating:</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-15T16:04:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech hiring: is this an inflection point?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/tech-hiring-inflection-point</link>
      <description>We might be seeing the end of remote interviews as we know them, and a return of in-person interviews, trial weeks and longer trial periods. Could hiring be returning to pre-pandemic norms?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 15:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-15T15:53:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 3 Transcript: Apt Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/mini-summit-three/</link>
      <description>Last week Christoph Berg, who maintains PostgreSQL’s APT packaging system,
gave a very nice talk on that system. Herein lie the transcript and links to
the slides and video.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 22:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T22:48:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes to a diverse community.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/yes-to-a-diverse-community</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Tony Stubblebine on The Medium Blog]  In the midst of some challenging cultural times, Tony Stubblebine and Medium are doing the right thing:   &quot;Over the past several months, I’ve gotten questions from the Medium community asking if we’re planning to change our policies in reaction to recent political pressure against diversity, equity, and inclusion. As some companies dismant</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 21:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T21:48:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating a News Publication Into the Fediverse</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/integrating-a-news-publication-into-the-fediverse</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Sean Tilley]  Sean has been integrating We Distribute with the fediverse for years. It's been hard - particularly at the beginning, which is the plight of the very early adopter. This rundown is incredibly useful for anyone who wants to integrate their own publication with the network, and highlights again how important the work Ghost has been doing really is.  The findings ar</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 14:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T14:46:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who will take care of you in your time of need?</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/04/12/who-will-take-care-of-you-in-your-time-of-need/</link>
      <description>This Fresh Air interview with Hanif Kureishi had me riveted from the beginning, for one reason, and then at the end for a different reason. Kureishi is best known as the author of the 1985 British rom-com My Beautiful Laundrette. During an illness in 2022 he fainted, fell on his face, broke his neck, and … Continue reading Who will take care of you in your time of need?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 16:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-12T16:55:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing First Person Digital Trust</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/establishing-first-person-digital</link>
      <description>I've spent the better part of the week thinking about the idea of first-person identity and verifiable relationship credentials after Drummond Reed spoke about them on Monday at VRM day.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T19:16:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #130: Google releases AI-powered IDE</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-130-google-releases-ai</link>
      <description>Also: Git turns 20, a new trend of AI cost saving pressure at developer agencies, John Carmack on how LLMs will impact the industry, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T16:51:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finishing the OpenID Connect EAP ACR Values specification</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2646</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect Extended Authentication Profile (EAP) ACR Values 1.0 specification has started its 60-day review to become an OpenID Final Specification. Recent steps leading up to this were: I added Context Class definitions to the Authentication Context Class Reference Values (“acr” values) defined by the specification, which enabled me to finally register them in […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 01:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T01:53:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Presentations at April 2025 OpenID Workshop and IIW</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2644</link>
      <description>As has become traditional, I gave the following presentation at the Monday, April 7, 2025 OpenID Workshop at Google: OpenID Connect Working Group Update (PowerPoint) (PDF) I also gave this invited “101” session presentation at the Internet Identity Workshop (IIW) on Tuesday, April 8, 2025: Introduction to OpenID Connect (PowerPoint) (PDF)</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 22:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T22:42:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fool in White House creating Greater Fool’s Housing Market?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/fool-in-white-house-creating-greater-fools-housing-market/</link>
      <description> Trying to forecast interest rates can make a fool of all of us, but Peter Schiff argues: “If Trump’s secret agenda is to crash the… 
The post Fool in White House creating Greater Fool’s Housing Market? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 17:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T17:13:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Philosophy of Software Design – with John Ousterhout</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-philosophy-of-software-design</link>
      <description>Stanford professor John Ousterhout explains why thoughtful software design matters more than ever as AI tools transform coding practices and developer workflows.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 16:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T16:25:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP Protocol: a new AI dev tools building block</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/mcp</link>
      <description>The Model Context Protocol - that extends IDEs’ AI capabilities - is &amp;nbsp;gaining rapid popularity. Why is this, and why should us developers pay attention to it?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T16:27:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Workshop 速報</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6927/</link>
      <description>本日日本時間午前４時半〜８時、カリフォリニアのGoogleキャンパスでOpenID財団ワークショップが行われました。近々ビデオとスライドも公開される予定ですが、まずは速報です。 Gail Hodges（OpenID財団エグゼクティブディレクター）による概況報告 Gail Hodg…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 06:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T06:58:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Foundation Workshopクィックレビュー</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/04/openid-foundation-workshop.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    今年もInternet Identity Workshop（IIW）に参加するためにMountainViewに来ています。     今日は前日ということで例年通りOpenID FoundationのWorkshopとDCP Working Groupの対面会議がありました。     ということで書ける範囲でクィックレビューを。（主にOIDF Workshopについて）       今回の会場はGoogleのオフィスでした。いつものことながらチャリが可愛い。乗って帰ろうかと思いました。      ということで中身に。     OIDF Milestones in the last 6 Months: Gail  まずはOpenID FoundationのExecutive DirectorのGailからここ半年のOpenID Foundationのアクティビティ</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T01:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/first-person-identity</link>
      <description>I'm sitting in VRM day listening to Drummond Reed talk about his First Person Project.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T23:56:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 3: APT Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306682786/</link>
      <description>Join us at PostgresSQL Extension Mini Summit #3 this week, where PostgreSQL
Debian packaging maintainer Christoph Berg will takes on a tour of APT
extension packaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 18:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T18:33:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Who is the best show ever made. Here’s why.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/doctor-who-is-the-best-show-ever-made-heres-why-f2619aed7a46?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    62 years of trying to be nice, always being kind.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 19:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T19:27:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDの進化：OpenID4VPの重要な仕様変更</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6912/</link>
      <description>重要なポイント 静かな革命：デジタルIDにおける重要な変更 2025年4月、デジタルID技術の世界で大きな転換点が静かに訪れました。OpenID for Verifiable Presentations（OpenID4VP）の仕様から「Presentation Exchange」…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 10:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T10:25:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Significant Event Without Fanfare</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2638</link>
      <description>A significant event in digital identity occurred without fanfare today. Presentation Exchange was removed from the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations specification. It had once-upon-a-time been the only query language used for verifiable credential presentation. In October 2024, the Digital Credential Query Language (DCQL) was added alongside it. Today, after much discussion by the working group, </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T06:54:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's fix OAuth in MCP</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2025/04/03/15/oauth-for-model-context-protocol</link>
      <description>Let's not overthink auth in MCP.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 23:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T23:39:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #129: new trend of EMs quitting to be startup founders using AI</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-129-new-trend-of-ems-quitting</link>
      <description>Also: Trump tariffs to hit tech, Gemini Pro 2.5 might be the best coding model yet, tips on using LLMs to code, and leaked startup recruitment guidelines reveal how much pedigree matters</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 15:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T15:50:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>商業登記電子証明書の手数料引き下げ〜１か月500円からに</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6906/</link>
      <description>この４月１日から、商業登記電子証明書の手数料が改定されました。 有効期間1か月の電子証明書が500円で発行可能に、有効期間3か月～27か月の電子証明書も、最大1,000円の値下げされました。 500円でできるなら、一回申請してみようかなと思います。Windows PCからじゃない…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T06:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Live RSS</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/long-live-rss</link>
      <description>Like many, I've grown increasingly disinterested in social media over the last year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T20:00:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy ≠ Freedom (but it should)</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/privacy-freedom/</link>
      <description>The data is in. Privacy is not correlated to Freedom. It is time to rethink how we write privacy laws.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T16:32:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stacked diffs and tooling at Meta with Tomas Reimers</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/stacked-diffs-and-tooling-at-meta</link>
      <description>Tomas Reimers, ex-Meta engineer and Graphite co-founder, shares how Meta’s custom developer tools pioneered practices like stacked diffs and monorepos—shaping industry standards and the future of AI-assisted coding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T16:27:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【4月1日】預貯金口座付番制度等が拡充拡充されました</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6901/</link>
      <description>2025年4月1日から預貯金口座付番制度（口座管理法制度）拡充されました。この制度は、個人の同意を前提として、マイナンバーと金融機関の預貯金口座を紐付けるものであり、主に相続時や災害時における手続きの簡略化を目的としています。 【資料】 主なメリット: 相続時・災害時の手続き簡略…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 02:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T02:58:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Postgres Extensions Mini Summit Two</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/mini-summit-two/</link>
      <description>A transcript of from the second PostgreSQL Extension Mini Summit,
“Implementing an Extension Search Path”, by Peter Eisentraut.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 19:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T19:32:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reality of Tech Interviews in 2025</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-reality-of-tech-interviews</link>
      <description>Interview processes are changing in a tech market that’s both cooling AND heating up at the same time. A deepdive with Hello Interview founders, Evan King and Stefan Mai</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 16:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T16:33:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>アップル、フランス当局から242億円の罰金を科される〜プライバシー保護の名のもとに市場支配力を強化？</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6895/</link>
      <description>フランス競争当局（FCA）は3月31日、アップルに対して1億5000万ユーロ（約242億円）という高額な罰金を科しました。問題となったのは、2021年から2023年にかけてアップルが導入した「App Tracking Transparency（ATT）」と呼ばれるプライバシー保護…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 11:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T11:30:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【デジタル庁】本人確認ガイドラインの改定に向けた有識者会議（令和6年度）の取りまとめが公表されました</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6889/</link>
      <description>4月1日、デジタル庁から本人確認ガイドラインの改定に向けた有識者会議（令和6年度）の取りまとめが公表されました。「DS-500 行政手続におけるオンラインによる本人確認の手法に関するガイドライン」（通称「本人確認ガイドライン」）は、行政手続きをデジタル化する時に、安全に本人確認す…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 09:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T09:51:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GビズIDの大幅アップデートとOpenID Connect for Identity Assuranceへの対応</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/03/gidopenid-connect-for-identity-assurance.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    いわゆる法人共通認証基盤と呼ばれる、デジタル庁が提供しているGビズIDの大幅アップデートが公開されましたね。     出典）デジタル庁 - GビズID&amp;nbsp;https://gbiz-id.go.jp/top/         GビズIDについてはこれまでもOpenIDファウンデーションジャパンのイベント等に古くは経産省、デジタル庁へ移管されてからはデジタル庁の方々にお越しいただき技術仕様やトラストフレームワークについてご発表いただいてきました。      OpenID Summit Tokyo 2020 - 2020/1/24  https://www.openid.or.jp/summit/2020/     OpenID BizDay #14 - 2021/1/27  https://openid.connpass.com/event/200742/</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-30T01:37:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #128: Mishandled security vulnerability in Next.js</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-128</link>
      <description>Cloudflare stepped up to deliver a fix for the vulnerability, following unexpected silence from the Next.js team. Also: OpenAI’s new image generation feature shows how Japan has lax copyright laws</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 17:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-27T17:32:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web3 is Reintroducing Cross-Origin Tracking Accidentally</title>
      <link>https://kyledenhartog.com/recreating-web3-cross-origin-tracking/</link>
      <description>We should expect that when the user shares their address that will act as implied consent for cross-origin tracking in the same way cookie notices act as a prompt for tracking.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oktaベンチャーが選ぶThe Identity 25の2025年版に選ばれました。</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6865/</link>
      <description>そう、あのニューヨークのタイムズスクエアにでかでかと顔がでるやつです。（写真１）参照。去年は３月２１日に出ていたようですが、今年はどうなるでしょうね。 日本からは他に、CTCの富士榮さんが入っていますね。あとは、EU DI ARFを作っている Paolo de Rosaとか、SP…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 03:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-26T03:39:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Okta Venturesが選ぶ、今年のアイデンティティ界の25人（The Identity 25）に選ばれました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/03/okta-ventures25the-identity-25.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    どうやらOkta Venturesが2024年から始めた今年のアイデンティティ界の25人（The Identity 25）に選ばれました。        https://www.okta.com/resources/datasheet-the-identity-25/        このプログラム、2024年からスタートしたもののようで、昨年はSPRIN-Dにいる安田クリスチーナやMicrosoftのPam DIngle、YubicoのJohn Bradleyなどが選ばれていました。     今年はOpenID FoundationのExecutive DirectorのGail HodgesやChairの崎村さんらの錚々たるメンバの中に何故か私も加えていただけたようです。     しかし、最初Okta Ventures側から連絡をもらった時はよくある詐欺かと</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T20:18:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated Microsoft OBO access token management (Entra only)</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/25/asp-net-core-delegated-microsoft-obo-access-token-management-entra-only/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated Microsoft On-Behalf-Of flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. The solution uses Microsoft.Identity.Web to implement the different flows and it really simple to implement, when you know how to use the Nuget package and use the correct Microsoft documentation. The application can […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 12:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T12:45:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key themes going into IIW XL (40) </title>
      <link>https://identitywoman.net/key-themes-going-into-iiw-xl-40/</link>
      <description> We are heading into the 40th Internet Identity Workshop, an event that I cofounded with Doc Searls and Phil Windley 20 years ago. I am not sure we ever thought it would last this long but it has. We continue to be the world’s leading innovation forum for decentralized digital identity focused on a range […] 
 The post Key themes going into IIW XL (40)&amp;nbsp; appeared first on Identity Woman. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T23:27:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 2: Extension Search Path Patch</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306569342/</link>
      <description>Join us at PostgresSQL Extension Mini Summit #2 this week, where PostgreSQL
committer Peter Eisentraut will discuss the extension search path patch.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T21:14:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Postgres Extensions Mini Summit One</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/mini-summit-one/</link>
      <description>A rough transcript of my talk “State of the Extension Ecosystem”.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T20:46:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is proposed MLSpin Settlement the April Fool’s Day joke #RECartel doesn’t want consumers retelling?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/is-proposed-mlspin-settlement-the-april-fools-day-joke-recartel-doesnt-consumers-retelling/</link>
      <description> Homebuyers &amp;amp; sellers, intend to buy or sell this Spring and talking to real estate agents about their fees? Have any mentioned that is just… 
The post Is proposed MLSpin Settlement the April Fool’s Day joke #RECartel doesn’t want consumers retelling? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T17:23:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタル庁とJR西日本、マイナンバーカードを活用した在学証明の実証実験：オンライン学割乗車券購入の実現へ</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6825/</link>
      <description>デジタル学生証明による学割サービスの話は、かなり前から検討されている話題です。わたしの周りでも、遅くとも2012年には Student Identity Trust Framework として国立情報学研究所（NII）との間で検討がなされてきました。 今回発表されたものは、これら…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T09:38:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcing people back to the office was a choice. I’m making mine.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/forcing-people-back-to-the-office-was-a-choice-im-making-mine-e1e7b8dd0af4?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Here’s why I won’t RTO.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-19T20:32:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Version of FIDO2 Client to Authenticator Protocol (CTAP 2.2) Now a Standard</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2631</link>
      <description>The FIDO Alliance has completed the CTAP 2.2 Specification. The closely-related third version of the W3C Web Authentication (WebAuthn) specification is also nearing final status; this WebAuthn Level 3 working draft is currently going through the review steps to become a W3C Recommendation. So what’s new in the third versions? Changes between CTAP 2.1 and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-18T07:15:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【告知】3/29「分人経済革命」ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 徹底対談【次世代ネットの扉を開く革命の起こしかた】</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6797/</link>
      <description>LIVE告知です。メタバース進化論の著者のバーチャル美少女ねむさんとYouTube Live を行います。 ・配信日時：3月29日（土）21:00より1.5時間程度予定・YouTube LIVEにて無料配信・配信URL：「分人経済革命」ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 徹底対談【次世代ネットの…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-17T11:23:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognition, Identity, and AI: Building Trust in Digital Agents</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/03/recognition-identity-and-ai-building.html</link>
      <description> My first love was self-sovereign distributed data, where each person owns and controls their data, hosting it wherever they choose and permissioning it under their own terms. But I got lost in the complexity of building a robust distributed identity infrastructure. How can you give permission to someone if you can’t 'name' them in a way that is verifiable and resistant to subversion? There's no po</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T16:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOV.UK WalletとOne Login</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6766/</link>
      <description>GOV.UK Wallet とは GOV.UK Walletは、デジタル運転免許証のコンテキストで1月21日に明らかになったイギリス政府が開発中のデジタル文書管理アプリで、2025年2月5日にはピーター・カイル科学・イノベーション・技術担当国務長官によりその詳細が発表が行われまし…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T19:13:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Hiatus – Look For Me In The Garden</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/03/11/on-hiatus-look-for-me-in-the-garden/</link>
      <description>Today I realized that even though the Web3 program is ramping up as demonstrated by Silicon Valley’s plans to turn Argentina into a “network state,” few understand what is unfolding with cybernetic governance. For that reason, I decided to take time off this spring to work on my garden and simply be with real people [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T04:32:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms Specification Addressing Area Director Feedback</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2627</link>
      <description>Orie Steele and I want to thank Deb Cooley for her Area Director review of the “Fully-Specified Algorithms for JOSE and COSE” specification. Addressing it simplified the exposition, while preserving the essence of what the draft accomplishes. Specifically, the resulting draft significantly simplified the fully-specified encryption description and removed the appendix on polymorphic ECDH algorithms.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 05:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T05:44:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEDI Details for Identity Nerds</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/sedi-details-for-identity-nerds-e1949af5cc30?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> This post is a more technical follow-up to the post announcing the passing of SB 260 in Utah, establishing the principles for state-endorsed digital identity (SEDI). While SEDI does not mandate any particular technology, its mandated principles close the door for technologies that do not comply, and open the door for technologies that do. This article explores what SEDI makes technically possible,</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T00:15:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utah Blazes New Trail for SSI: SEDI</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/utah-blazes-new-trail-for-ssi-sedi-441d8ce65ab8?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Finally!  On March 4, 2025, the Utah legislature unanimously passed SB 260, a groundbreaking digital identity bill that carries this description:  “This bill enacts provisions related to a state-endorsed digital identity” (SEDI).  Now it’s off to the governor for signature, who has been publicly positive about it. Huge credit to Sen. Cullimore, the bill’s sponsor, and Christopher Bramwell, the sta</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T23:30:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/03/07/making-the-fediverse-more-accessible-with-claude-3-7-sonnet/</link>
      <description>A few years ago I abandoned Twitter in favor of Mastodon. Recent events validate that choice and underscore the strategic importance of a decentralized fediverse that can’t be owned by a single corporate or state actor. But while Mastodon meets my needs, much of the Twitter diaspora has gone to Bluesky. That’s fine for now … Continue reading Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonn</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T17:54:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extension Ecosystem Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/extension-ecosystem-summit/</link>
      <description>We’re doing it again! The PostgreSQL Extension Ecosystem Summit returns to
PGConf.dev. We’ll again be looking at indexing, discovery, packaging, and
core support. And we’ll once again be hosting a series of “Mini Summits”
leading up to the event. Join us!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T00:35:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2621</link>
      <description>Emil Lundberg and I have published the COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing specification. Its abstract is: This specification defines COSE algorithm identifiers used when the signing operation is performed cooperatively between two parties. When performing two-party signing, the first party typically hashes the data to be signed and the second party signs the hashed data […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 02:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-04T02:47:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCC at the 2025 1EdTech Digital Credentials Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/dcc-at-the-2025-1edtech-digital-credentials-summit-e506d7c8051c?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> LCW Experience Badge &amp;amp; Introduction to Open Badges 3.0 Course at Participate  This week is the 2025 Digital Credentials Summit hosted by the organization that shepherds the Open Badges 3.0 standard. This is a great space to meet with implementers, educators, technologists, funders, and policy makers from all over the world to&amp;nbsp;connect.  I will be attending this year and have the privilege </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:13:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Badges 3.0 Basics: Watch, Learn, and Earn on Participate</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/open-badges-3-0-basics-watch-learn-and-earn-on-participate-660c2bf922dd?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Join the Digital Credentials Consortium Learning&amp;nbsp;Hub  The Digital Credential has started a series of short posts explaining the characteristics and trust models of W3C Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0. To accompany this series, we collaborated with our colleagues as Participate to create the The Digital Credentials Consortium Learning Hub and offer a short course, “Introduction to O</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:12:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A future for Self Sovereign Identity?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/a-future-for-self-sovereign-identity-c237caa5e46f?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Symbolic representation of Web Security applied to&amp;nbsp;SSI. Many children in Europe grew up with the tales of Baron Münchhausen, who claims to have lifted himself and his horse out of a mire by pulling his own hair. The image is so powerful because the problem of the circular dependency is so clearly visible. In real life, circular dependencies are often far less&amp;nbsp;obvious.  Which is why the fi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The LCW Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/the-lcw-experience-6a5bef5cca4d?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> The Digital Credentials Consortium, our team and our members, are aiming to advance the understanding &amp;amp; use of privacy-enhanced, portable, verifiable digital credentials like Open Badges 3.0. We’ve noticed that while many are interested in the opportunities LERs as digital credentials may offer, many haven’t yet experienced what it is like to claim and accept an Open Badge 3.0 credential with </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:14:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement Phone verification, 2FA using ASP.NET Core Identity</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/03/implement-phone-verification-2fa-using-asp-net-core-identity/</link>
      <description>This post shows how to implement phone (SMS) verification and two-factor authentication (2FA) using ASP.NET Core Identity. The solution integrates phone-based verification and 2FA mechanisms. The implementation uses ASP.NET Core Identity’s extensibility to incorporate SMS-based verification during user registration and login processes. SMS is no longer a recommended authentication method due to sec</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T06:05:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The web was always about redistribution of power. Let’s bring that back.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-web-was-always-about-redistribution-of-power-lets-bring-that-back-d3d855509f9c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s time to rekindle the movement.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T15:00:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cambrian Explosion of OAuth and OpenID Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2615</link>
      <description>Vladimir Dzhuvinov and I led a discussion on The Cambrian Explosion of OAuth and OpenID Specifications at the 2025 OAuth Security Workshop in Reykjavík. The abstract for the session was: The number of OAuth and OpenID specifications continues to grow. At present there are 30 OAuth RFCs, two more in the RFC Editor queue, 13 […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 12:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T12:42:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Im The Problem, You Might Be The Reason</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/02/if-im-problem-you-might-be-reason.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;Tune your metaphors..&amp;nbsp;             &amp;nbsp;From where I dance and glance in America...   All over the world, men and women are not having the same experience. Generational conflicts are arising, influencing everything, causing chaos to status quo, and making clear that the ability to r/w/rw is not shared equally. Computational supremacy, computational illiteracy, what does the data say? W</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T22:08:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatkontrolle: EU-Bürgerbeauftragte kritisiert Drehtürwechsel von Europol-Beamten zu Chatkontrolle-Lobbyist Thorn</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/chatkontrolle-eu-buergerbeauftragte-kritisiert-drehtuerwechsel-von-europol-beamten-zu-chatkontrolle-lobbyist-thorn/</link>
      <description> Die scheidende EU-Bürgerbeauftragte Emily O’Reilly hat es auf die Beschwerde des ehemaligen Europaabgeordneten der Piratenpartei Patrick Breyer als “Missstand” bewertet, dass ein Europol-Beamter trotz potenzieller Interessenskonflikte ohne jegliche Auflagen zum … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T12:20:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with a Hybrid Heat Pump Water Heater</title>
      <link>https://altmode.org/2025/02/24/my-experience-with-a-hybrid-heat-pump-water-heater/</link>
      <description>In October 2023, my wife emerged from the bathroom one morning to report that we had no hot water. I found that our gas-fired, on-demand water heater had failed and was leaking a small amount. I called our plumber, who confirmed we needed a new water heater. We immediately faced the following decision: Should we […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 01:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T01:16:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are political &amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/how-are-political-economic-uncertainty-impacting-real-estate-consumers/</link>
      <description> Writing that he knows “a bunch of people who held their nose and voted for Trump,” the president of HousingWire media issued this challenge on… 
The post How are political &amp;amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 16:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T16:14:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in OpenID Connect and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/24/use-client-assertions-in-openid-connect-and-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>Client assertions is a method of client authentication which can be used in OpenID Connect. This provides an alternative to client secrets. This approach enhances security by using signed tokens (JWTs) to authenticate clients during the token request process or the OAuth PAR request. In ASP.NET Core, client assertions is not supported per default, a […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T06:43:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPIとVerifiable Credentialsに関するイベントをやります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/fapiverifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  3月頭はFintech Weekということもあり、あちこちでFintech系のイベントが開催されますね。そのうちの一つである4F（Future Frontier Fes by FINOLAB）の一コマをいただきAuthlete川崎さんと一緒にFAPIとVerifiable Credentialsの話をします。  こちらのイベントですね。  https://4f-otmcbldg.tokyo/2025-jp/       このうち、3/4の午前中のセッションです。    セッションの詳細と申し込みはこちらからしていただけます。  https://fapi-vc.peatix.com/        &amp;nbsp;私は慶應の鈴木先生と一緒に先日発行したデジタルクレデンシャルの管理要件に関するディスカッションペーパーの中身の話を解説させていただきます。みなさん色々とデジ</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T02:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Visit To Tulsa With Microtuble Symbolic Communication + Thoughts on DOGE Against A UPenn “Quaker Kabbalah” Backdrop</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/19/a-visit-to-tulsa-with-microtuble-symbolic-communication-thoughts-on-doge-against-a-upenn-quaker-kabbalah-backdrop/</link>
      <description>Posting this late, so I won’t be writing an introduction. As is the case for me lately, the offering is a somewhat rambling discussion that surfaces quiet a few nuggets for you to chew on.&amp;nbsp; Life in this absurdist improvisational theater might easier if we can practice the Tao of Pooh. Smile. Here’s a link [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 04:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-20T04:55:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signing Off from Uniken: Thank You for the Adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/signing-off-from-uniken-thank-you-for-the-adventure.html</link>
      <description>It’s the end of an era: after eight incredible years, it felt like the right time to close the chapter on my story at Uniken. When I joined as CTO, Uniken was an ambitious startup with a unique core technology and a vision to make a global impact. What made the ensuing journey so rewarding […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T15:11:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing a single client sign-in using parameters in Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/17/customizing-a-single-client-sign-in-using-parameters-in-duende-identityserver/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. In the previous post, the UI was customized per […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T06:34:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/multiply-tiny-house-love-story-with-million-backyard-march/</link>
      <description> After a post about a college that’s teaching students how to build their own tiny houses for just $5,000 drew a lot of attention, decided… 
The post Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-14T21:49:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Components</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/02/12/web-components/</link>
      <description>The JavaScript industrial complex won’t crumble anytime soon. But the stage is set for a return to an ecosystem of reusable components accessible to business developers, only this time based on the universal web platform and its core standards. How To Build Web Components Using ChatGPT LLM series at The New Stack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T12:43:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business Case for Dynamic Authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/the-business-case-for-dynamic-authorization</link>
      <description>Authorization isn't just about security.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T18:31:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Science</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/02/11/bitcoin-science/</link>
      <description>  

 Bitcoin failed.  J.P. Koning notes in The end of El Salvador’s bitcoin payments experiment: 

  But here was a government that was going to champion the stuff, nullifying all of the headwinds against bitcoin in one stroke! The government meddling hypothesis would be put to test.

The Salvadoran government used a combination of sticks and carrots to kick-start adoption. First, let's list the ca</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T17:28:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated OAuth Token Exchange access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/10/asp-net-core-delegated-oauth-token-exchange-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated OAuth 2.0 Token Exchange RFC 8693 flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. It looks at how the OAuth Token Exchange can be implemented and how an application can request delegated access tokens on behalf of a user and another application, providing […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 06:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T06:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal For A Spring Break From Mind Viruses – March 13 to the Summer Solstice: Ground, Gather Energy, Reflect, Renew 5 Years Later</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/07/proposal-for-a-spring-break-from-mind-viruses-march-13-to-the-summer-solstice-ground-gather-energy-reflect-renew-5-years-later/</link>
      <description>I made a video today reflecting on how we manage (or don’t) our energy and how our engagement with digital information complicates our lives. I’m proposing that people consider dialing back their social media consumption to spend time reflecting on their thinking, what we have learned over the past five years, and how we can [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 02:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-08T02:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>そういえばEUDIW Architecture Reference Framework 1.5.0が出てますね</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/eudiw-architecture-reference-framework.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    そういえば2月4日にEUDIW ARFの1.5.0が出てますね。  https://eu-digital-identity-wallet.github.io/eudi-doc-architecture-and-reference-framework/latest/architecture-and-reference-framework-main/           GithubのCHANGELOGを見ると     The ARF is aligned with the adopted Implementing Acts, covering articles 5a and 5c of the eIDAS Regulation.&amp;nbsp;  The ARF also includes changes in response to comments provid</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T23:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Up On Quantum Realism In Connection With Gordon Pask’s Mechanical Theatricality – Plus A “Diamond Age” Excerpt Read Aloud</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/05/follow-up-on-quantum-realism-in-connection-with-gordon-pasks-mechanical-theatricality-plus-a-diamond-age-excerpt-read-aloud/</link>
      <description>This is a follow up to yesterday’s video reiterating my thoughts about Live Action Role Play with encoded artefacts as an example of extended mind and possible future inter-dimensional information processing system. The talk goes along with two earlier talks Jason and I did on the work of Michael Mateas here. The feature image is [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:37:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/growing-democracy/</link>
      <description>There is a place, little noticed and even less understood by most Canadians, where democracy is growing stronger despite a history of violence and exploitation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:20:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Candidate Recommendation for Controlled Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2612</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group has published a Snapshot Candidate Recommendation of the Controlled Identifiers specification. This follows the five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group in December 2024. Two of these specifications, including Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE, depend upon the Controlled Identifiers spec. The planned update</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 06:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T06:30:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halbguter neuer polnischer Vorschlag zur Chatkontrolle wird am Mittwoch diskutiert</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/halbguter-neuer-polnischer-vorschlag-zur-chatkontrolle-wird-am-mittwoch-diskutiert/</link>
      <description> Polen, das derzeit den Vorsitz im EU-Rat innehat, schlägt eine wichtige Änderung des viel kritisierten EU-Vorschlags zur Chatkontrolle vor: Anstatt die generelle Durchsuchung privater Chats anzuordnen soll die Chatkontrolle wie … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T10:52:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison Reflects on Joseph Gonzalez’s Theory of Quantum Realism – A Hopeful Participatory Universe Built On Love!</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/03/alison-reflects-on-joseph-gonzalezs-theory-of-quantum-realism-a-hopeful-participatory-universe-built-on-love/</link>
      <description>Below are Joseph Gonzalez’s responses to questions I posed about his theory of quantum realism. You can find out more at his blog bantamjoe.com. I discuss these questions in the video below starting at timestamp 20 minutes. Select links from Bantamjoe.com: The Self-Aware Circle of Consciousness: Here A Holographic Reality Designed By Consciousness, Designed For [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 23:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T23:05:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is About To Come From Inside The House</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/the-call-is-about-to-come-from-inside-the-house.html</link>
      <description>You would have to be living under a rock to have missed all the talk about Agentic AI, and how it is going to revolutionize the way we live and work. AI-powered agents will be anything and everything – from personal shopper to travel concierge, executive assistant to inventory manager, medical diagnostician to customer service […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T21:45:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple client sign-in customizations using Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/03/multiple-client-sign-in-customizations-using-duende-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/duende-multi-tenant Blogs in the series Setup The solution […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 06:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T06:55:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Years of Digital Identity!</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2607</link>
      <description>Kim Cameron first told me what Digital Identity is on February 1, 2005. He said that the Internet was created without an identity layer. He encouraged me “You should come help build it with me.” I’ve been at it ever since! What I wrote about digital identity a decade ago remains as true today: An […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 02:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T02:46:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want you to do these four things right now</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/i-want-you-to-do-these-four-things-right-now-3ea064583460?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Some simple steps to keep yourself safe.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-01T21:04:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win Stupid Prizes</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/30/win-stupid-prizes/</link>
      <description>

 Deadly D.C. Plane Crash Comes Months After Congress Ignored Warning About Traffic at Reagan Airport 

 As the new administration is playing stupid games, yesterday morning, prior to yesterday’s aviation disaster, professor Thomas Schaller cautioned:
 

 
   An FAA employee I know confirms agency already lacks sufficient air traffic controllers. The so-called “buyouts” and other attacks on federa</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T14:44:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take 1... Solid Pods and Dids</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/take-1-solid-pods-and-dids.html</link>
      <description> My first attempt at building a decentralized app in this day and age will use Solid Pods and DIDs. The goal? A super simple “BooksWeLike” app—a place where I can review books and see what my friends are reading and enjoying.     What makes this app different is how it handles data. Unlike traditional apps where data lives in a centralized database, my app will let users store their own data in Sol</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T00:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust, Least Privilege, and Just-in-Time Access</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/zero-trust-least-privilege-and-just</link>
      <description>Security professionals have long taught that organizations should limit the access individuals have in computer systems to just those privileges necessary to perform their job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T13:55:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andreessen and Horowitz’s Debrief On Their Fairshake PAC and Sunny Days Ahead For “Little Tech” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/20/andreessen-and-horowitzs-debrief-on-their-fairshake-pac-and-sunny-days-ahead-for-little-tech-under-trump/</link>
      <description>I took notes on Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz’s post-election discussion of their Fairshake pro-crypto Pac and the coming Trump presidency about two months ago, but set them aside and other topics took precedence. Given the rising craziness in the crypto space around the inauguration, I thought it was a good time to put them [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T03:58:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T07:34:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Dance, Oscillation, And Going “Inside”</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/18/trump-dance-oscillation-and-going-inside/</link>
      <description>In this morning’s video I somehow missed the fact that the inauguration coincides with MLK Day, which is an interesting sync with the “melanin as optical material” lens. I’m going to drop a few links to old blog posts that touch on the YMCA and “out of school time learning” as as well as my [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T17:06:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestalt, Quakers and Carbon Trading – Do You See Faces Or A Vase?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/17/gestalt-quakers-and-carbon-trading-do-you-see-faces-or-a-vase/</link>
      <description>In this video I draw connections between Gestalt theory and organizational development as applied to digital groupthink in the context of Christiana Figueres, a leader in the development of carbon trading, who trained at the Gestalt Institute of Cleveland. As a young woman, she attended Swarthmore College, a Quaker institution. The first wife of her [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T06:06:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T08:18:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Configuration Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/01/14/the-configuration-crisis/</link>
      <description>Perhaps, even though they are not themselves explainable, AIs can help us engineer explainable systems. But I’m not optimistic. It feels like we’re on a path to keep making systems harder for humans to configure, and we keep expanding our reliance on superhuman intelligence to do that for us. The Configuration Crisis and Developer Dependency … Continue reading The Configuration Crisis</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:23:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day An Evangelical Christian Convinced ChatGPT I Was A Hippy, Schwab-Aligned Sociopathic Magician</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/14/the-day-an-evangelical-christian-convinced-chatgpt-i-was-a-hippy-schwab-aligned-sociopathic-magician/</link>
      <description>What will come of large language models when they mirror unsettled psyches defined by religious hero complexes into the cloud? We do ourselves and future generations a profound disservice when we choose not to make time to comprehend and interrogate how emerging technologies and narrative flows are being deployed to steer psychological states individually and [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:00:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/explaining-verifiable-credentials-and-open-badges-3-0-34ae898b98b2?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Part 2: Issuing&amp;nbsp;Badges  In part one of this series, we discussed how the trust model of Open Badges 3.0 differs from earlier versions. Credentials issued as Open Badges 3.0 are based on the W3C Verifiable Credentials data model which describes how claims made online can be&amp;nbsp;proven.  To explore this trust model, let’s explore the story of Olivia who has been taking classes at a local commu</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T15:28:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is anybody out there?</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/is-anybody-out-there.html</link>
      <description> Is blogging still a thing?  If you’re reading this, please comment or like it so I know.     I am, at heart, still the XDI Guy. My passion for robust, secure, and scalable distributed data management hasn’t waned. Building one of the first XDI implementations (shout-out to Markus Sabadello, who might have built the only other one), I learned a lot about the challenges and opportunities of distribu</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T16:20:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECDSAに対応したゼロ知識証明の論文がGoogleから出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/ecdsagoogle.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  AAMVAのモバイル運転免許証のガイドラインでも触れましたが、mdocやSD-JWTのリンク可能性へ対応するためには今後ゼロ知識証明が大切になります。  年末にGoogleの研究者が  Anonymous credentials from ECDSA  というタイトルでペーパーを出しています。  https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/2010    AIでイラスト生成すると色々とおかしなことになって面白いですねw    アブストラクトの中からポイントを抜粋すると、従来のBBS+では暗号スイートへの対応に関する要件が厳しかったのでレガシーで対応できるようにECDSAでもできるようにしたよ、ということのようですね。   Part of the difficulty arises because schemes in the literature,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T00:23:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an open web that protects us from harm</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/building-an-open-web-that-protects-us-from-harm-40a95da1d82f?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s not enough to be neutral. We must be allies.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T15:58:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI RAG with LlamaIndex, Local Embedding, and Ollama Llama 3.1 8b</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-rag-with-llamaindex-local-embedding-and-ollama-llama-3-1-8b-b0620116a715?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> In this post, I cover using LlamaIndex LlamaParse in auto mode to parse a PDF page containing a table, using a Hugging Face local embedding model, and using local Llama 3.1 8b via Ollama to perform naive Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). That’s a mouthful. I won’t go into how to setup Ollama and Llama 3.1 8b; this post assumes it is&amp;nbsp;running.  First off, you can find the code for this in m</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T14:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gregg Braden Led Me To Share My Thoughts on Quantum Coherence, Collective Computing, and Tokenized Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/10/how-gregg-braden-led-me-to-share-my-thoughts-on-quantum-coherence-collective-computing-and-tokenized-spirituality/</link>
      <description>This is a video I posted yesterday. And a follow up to clarify certain points. Sorry, I guess the youtube AI choose the “hands up” screenshot for the preview image. I do talk a lot with my hands. Here is a link to Joseph Gonzalez’s blog post on emergent information communication systems. Here are two [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T06:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorization Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/authorization-matters</link>
      <description>In 2013, poor authorization practices led to one of the largest data breaches in history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T19:36:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sqitch 1.5.0</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/sqitch-1.5.0/</link>
      <description>Sqitch v1.5.0: out now in all the usual places!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T02:30:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hockey Trivia</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/08/hockey-trivia/</link>
      <description>  

 As I just registered for a new season of beer league hockey starting this weekend, I thought about an episode of C’est comme ça que je t’aime I recently watched which is set in 1974 Sainte-Foy, Quebec City.  Nearly all the 1974 Quebec cultural references are new to me and in this episode, there is an adventure in a hockey arena and you can pause the video in a few places and see signage in the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T16:03:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OYO AI</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/01/oyo-ai.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;With over 1000 AI communities deployed in 2024, the next AI cohort begins..                                   Coding, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence, Entrepreneurial Skill Development, Teacher PD,&amp;nbsp;  With mentor support of all learners, students and teachers. Unlimited learning by design: (own root)&amp;nbsp;  OYO®&amp;nbsp; AI&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;by kidOYO®&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;at OYOclass.com, Educati</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T12:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 books</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/46-books-5f8c47016bb2?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Every book is a portal out of here.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-07T23:29:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-llamaindex-part-1-openai-e96b3efa699a?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI  I have started to experiment with LlamaIndex for use in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) document parsing and indexing. My results were mixed on the simple page provided. This is part 1, where I make a short post on LlamaIndex with OpenAI as the LLM component. I expect part 2 to be LlamaIndex with Ollama and Llama3–8b as the LLM components.  This is a very sho</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T21:15:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Second Candidate Recommendation for Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2603</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group published the Snapshot Second Candidate Recommendation of the Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE specification just before the holidays. This was one of five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group at the same time, including for the Verifiable Credentials Data Model 2.0, which I’m also an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-03T04:57:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should URI::mysql Switch to DBD::MariaDB?</title>
      <link>https://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=11163487</link>
      <description>Should Sqitch and URI::mysql use DBD::MariaDB instead of DBD::mysql? If so,
what are the implications for Sqitch deployment and usage?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T22:47:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New JSONPath Feature: SelectLocated</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/jsonpath-located/</link>
      <description>New in the jsonpath Go package and Playground: “Located” results that pair
selected values with normalized paths to their locations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:43:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intention Economyその後</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/intention-economy.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    年末にDoc SearlsがIntention Economyについて「The Real Intention Economy」というポストをしています。かなり重要なポストだと思うので読んでおいた方が良さそうです。     https://doc.searls.com/2024/12/30/the-real-intention-economy/     彼の著書は日本語にも翻訳されていますね。  https://amzn.to/3C2PX9n        さて、今回のDocのポストに戻ると、彼がIntention Economyの考え方を発表してからもう直ぐ20年が経とうとしている現在、生成AIの文脈も相まって、Intention Economy自体が脅威となりつつある、という話です。     Intention Economyで検索すると結構ヤバ目の結果が返</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T03:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL/JSON Path Playground Update</title>
      <link>https://theory.github.io/sqljson/</link>
      <description>The Go SQL/JSON Playground has been updated with a fresh design and PostgreSQL
17 compatibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T20:40:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tintin and the fascists</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/tintin-and-the-fascists-90241c93b3c6?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    The boy reporter has a fascist origin. But something new is possible.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T16:46:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for tech, 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/predictions-for-tech-2025-4046a6331cb9?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s going to be a hard year.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T15:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>366/366 !!!</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/366366.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  ついにこの日が来ました。           去年の正月休みに某猫とのチキンレースが始まってしまったので収まりがつかなくなって惰性で描き続けていましたが気がついたら本当に1年経ってしまいました。  ↓某猫のポスト 
  ふじえさん、やっぱりやっとるな！ 毎日記事を書く366チャレンジや！ これ絶対やっとるぞ！ — 👹秋田の猫🐱 (@ritou) January 4, 2024  
    最初のうちは割と実装してみよう！的なポストが多かったのですが、中盤〜後半は忙しくなりすぎたこともあり読んでみようシリーズが大半を占めてしまったのは反省です。  ということで振り返ってみましょう。  1月のポストはこんな感じです。     この頃は結構作ってますね。まぁ、冬休みが暇だったので実装し始めたのがきっかけだったので。  あとは1月はOpenID Summit Tokyo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T23:11:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑧</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01040135091.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだまだプライバシーの章が続きます。  4.5.&amp;nbsp;DELETING MDL INFORMATION FROM A DEVICE   An mDL holder must have the capability to delete the mDL holder’s mDL from the mDL holder’s device. Such deletion:      Must delete all mDL information, log information, and any metadata (e.g. settings) that could impart information </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-29T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑦</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_02108542609.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     引き続き4章のプライバシーの部分を読んでいきます。  4.3.&amp;nbsp;PROTECTING DATA   It is up to Issuing Authorities to ensure that all mDL data stored on the mDL holder’s device is adequately protected. As standards in this respect are still under development, each Issuing Authority should take great care to ensure that the design of its</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑥</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_28.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        ようやく4章の「PRIVACY AND SECURITY」に入ります。4章も結構長いんですよね。。。ただ、結構重要な章なので細かくみていきたいと思います。     4.1.&amp;nbsp;INTRODUCTION   The privacy of an mDL holder has been paramount in the mDL design process from the start. Care was and is being taken in all the work to ensure that methods and means are available to protect mDL h</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T21:57:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a framework for living well</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/creating-a-framework-for-living-well-4aafe427c74b?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Drawing upa North Star for building my life  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T17:06:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 Foundation: SDO Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/26/web-7-0-foundation-sdo-accreditation/</link>
      <description>The Web 7.0 Foundation is a relatively new organization, incorporated in Canada on May 1, 2023². It focuses on developing specifications and standards for a unified software and hardware ecosystem aimed at building resilient, trusted, and decentralized systems¹³. Source: Conversation … Continue reading →</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T23:05:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑤</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0938402867.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだ３章が続きますが今回で３章は終わりです。     3.6.&amp;nbsp;IACA ROOT CERTIFICATE   In Table B.1 of ISO/IEC 18013-5, on the table row for the “ISSUER” certificate component, replace:     stateOrProvinceName is optional. If this element is present, the element shall also be present in the end-entity certificates and hold the same va</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む④</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01062834414.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        引き続き３章を読んでいきます。  3-3.&amp;nbsp;PORTRAIT IMAGE   The portrait image is the primary means by which an mDL is matched to the person presenting the mDL in an attended transaction. The portrait image therefore needs to be of suitable quality for this purpose. ISO/IEC 18013-5 requires the portrait to comply with Ann</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-25T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>