<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Identosphere Identity Blogcatcher: Personal</title>
    <link>https://identosphere.com</link>
    <description>Personal blogs of individuals working in decentralized identity.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Table saws</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/3/table-saws/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Quitting programming as a career right now because of LLMs would be like quitting carpentry as a career thanks to the invention of the table saw. 

     Tags: careers, ai-assisted-programming, generative-ai, ai, llms </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 04:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-03T04:10:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are we actually for? The Mamdani case for positive resistance</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/what-are-we-actually-for-the-mamdani-case-for-positive-resistance/</link>
      <description>Why effective opposition requires more than just saying no</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T20:31:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI is changing software engineering at Shopify with Farhan Thawar</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-ai-is-changing-software-engineering</link>
      <description>Shopify's Head of Engineering, Farhan Thawar, shares how the company is using internal LLMs, unlimited AI tokens, and custom tooling to figure out how to use AI tools more efficiently - faster</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T15:45:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Charles Babbage</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/2/charles-babbage/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  On two occasions I have been asked, — &quot;Pray, Mr. Babbage, if you put into the machine wrong figures, will the right answers come out ?&quot; In one case a member of the Upper, and in the other a member of the Lower, House put this question. I am not able rightly to apprehend the kind of confusion of ideas that could provoke such a question.  
 — Charles Babbage, Passages from the Life of a Philosopher</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T15:04:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republican Budget Bill Signals New Era in Federal Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/republican-budget-bill-signals-new-era-in-federal-surveillance/</link>
      <description>&quot;The looming rapid expansion of federal surveillance may signal a step change on a trajectory set in motion after September 11, 2001, with broad implications for the rights and privacy of all Americans.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T14:59:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday, July 2, 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/07/02/wednesday-july-2-2025/</link>
      <description>And if insurers aren't buying, hospitals close. Time has a good piece making clear that the socialized part of the U.S. health care system—Medicare and Medicaid—are socialist gravy on a vast B2B insurance business operating inside a captured regulatorium. Patient problems are products bought and sold. Also that it has more than four million views. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T14:00:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement ASP.NET Core OpenID Connect with Keycloak to implement Level of Authentication (LoA) requirements</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/07/02/implement-asp-net-core-openid-connect-with-keykloak-to-implement-level-of-authentication-loa-requirements/</link>
      <description>This post looks at implementing an OpenID Connect client in ASP.NET Core and require a level of authentication (LoA) implemented using Keycloak. The applications are hosted using Aspire. The LoA is requested in Keycloak using the acr_values claim. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/IdentityExternalErrorHandling Setup The applications are implemented using Aspire. An ASP.NET Core application uses an</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 04:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T04:40:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mandelbrot in x86 assembly by Claude</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/2/mandelbrot-in-x86-assembly-by-claude/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Mandelbrot in x86 assembly by Claude 
Inspired by a tweet asking if Claude knew x86 assembly, I decided to run a bit of an experiment. 
 I prompted Claude Sonnet 4: 
 
 Write me an ascii art mandelbrot fractal generator in x86 assembly 
 
 And got back code that looked... like assembly code I guess? 
 So I copied some jargon out of that response and asked: 
 
 I have some code written for x86-64 a</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 04:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T04:35:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/my-latest-newsletter-explores-the.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 My latest newsletter explores the eternal debate .. ‘Maths - discovered or invented?’ 
 But it’s not only about that … it’s an introduction to a follow up issue where I will be exploring  ‘Pattern Breaking’. 
 (Except it isn’t my ‘latest’ - just another post I discovered on my test blog! </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T02:24:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/i-was-delighted-to-be.html</link>
      <description> I was delighted to be joined on the People First podcast by Ramsey Avery who is the Production Designer for the Amazon series - Lord of the Rings - Rings of Power. 
 Wonderful conversation that I know you will enjoy. 
 🔗🎙️ Ramsey Avery - The Lord Of The Rings - The Rings Of Power 
 Discovered on my test blog from a year ago. (Clearly a space I don’t use a lot!) </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 02:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T02:19:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/best-viewed-on-the-site.html</link>
      <description> 🖇️ Best viewed on my site 
 … in a situation like that there’s only one thing you can do and that’s walk into The shrink [BAD Business] wherever you are, just walk in say “[BAD business], You can get  anything you want, at Alice’s restaurant. You “support election deniers, I’m out”. 
 And walk out. You know, if  one person, just one person does it they may think he’s really sick and  They won’t ta</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 02:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T02:03:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/old-news-but-still-tucker.html</link>
      <description> OLD NEWS - but still … 
 Tucker Carlson giving Ted Cruz a hard time in interview … did I miss the news that hell had frozen over? </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 02:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T02:01:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/i-guess-its-never-ever.html</link>
      <description> I guess its never - ever - over … 
 I’m talking to you @manton and @danielpunkass </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 02:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T02:01:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/a-podcast-i-think-iframe.html</link>
      <description>  
 A short extract from The Mike Hosking Breakfast show - down in New Zealand featuring Vantaset’s Craig Steele talking about Organisational Productivity - with a specific focus on Performance. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 01:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T01:27:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/02/i-have-been-trying-to.html</link>
      <description> I have been trying to work out why the posts I thought I had posted weren’t posted. It seems that somehow my settings got changed and I now have a backlog of posts on my test blog. #Annoying 
 Just going to repost here. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 01:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-02T01:26:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Using Playwright MCP with Claude Code</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/using-playwright-mcp-with-claude-code/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> TIL: Using Playwright MCP with Claude Code 
Inspired by Armin (&quot;I personally use only one MCP - I only use Playwright&quot;) I decided to figure out how to use the official Playwright MCP server with Claude Code. 
 It turns out it's easy: 
 claude mcp add playwright npx '@playwright/mcp@latest'
claude
 
 The claude mcp add command only affects the current directory by default - it gets persisted in the</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 23:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T23:55:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Kevin Webb</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/kevin-webb/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  One of the best examples of LLM developer tooling I've heard is from a team that supports software from the 80s-90s. Their only source of documentation is video interviews with retired employees. So they feed them into transcription software and get summarized searchable notes out the other end.  
 — Kevin Webb, a couple million lines of Smalltalk 

     Tags: small, ai-assisted-programming, ai, </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T21:46:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PlanetScale's classy retirement</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/classy-retirement/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Sometimes a service with a free plan will decide to stop supporting it. I understand why this happens, but I'm often disappointed at the treatment of existing user's data. It's easy to imagine users forgetting about their old accounts, missing the relevant emails and then discovering too late that their data is gone. 
 Inspired by today's news about PlanetScale PostgreSQL I signed into PlanetScale</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T20:37:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A custom template system from the mid-2000s era</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/mid-2000s/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Using LLMs for code archaeology is pretty fun. 
 I stumbled across this blog entry from 2003 today, in which I had gotten briefly excited about ColdFusion and implemented an experimental PHP template engine that used XML tags to achieve a similar effect: 
 &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;%title%&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;sql id=&quot;recent&quot;&amp;gt;
select title
from entries 
order by added desc
limit 0, %limit%
&amp;lt;/sql&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 19:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T19:57:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PlanetScale for Postgres</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/planetscale-for-postgres/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Announcing PlanetScale for Postgres 
PlanetScale formed in 2018 to build a commercial offering on top of the Vitess MySQL sharding open source project, which was originally released by YouTube in 2012. The PlanetScale founders were the co-creators and maintainers of Vitess. 
 Today PlanetScale are announcing a private preview of their new horizontally sharded PostgreSQL solution, due to &quot;overwhelm</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T18:16:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you want an Unconference? You can Hire me!</title>
      <link>https://identitywoman.net/so-you-want-an-unconference-you-can-hire-me/</link>
      <description> I have been reflecting on Ikigai a Japanese concept blending passion, talent, purpose, and fulfillment. For me, the magical intersection is in the design and facilitation of interactive events for high performance collaboration communities.&amp;nbsp; My offerings are now updated on the unconference.net website.&amp;nbsp; Check out the three new case studies!.&amp;nbsp; I am keen to work […] 
 The post So you </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T17:31:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joining the Sideways Verifiable Communities project</title>
      <link>https://identitywoman.net/joining-the-sideways-verifiable-communities-project/</link>
      <description> I’m excited to share that I have joined the Verifiable Community project led by Grace Rachmany.&amp;nbsp; This is a full circle moment for me, returning me to the roots of why I devoted 20 years of my life to the digital identity field. My passion has been in fostering the creation of distributed identity protocols […] 
 The post Joining the Sideways Verifiable Communities project appeared first on Id</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T17:24:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting mrmincent</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/mrmincent/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  To misuse a woodworking metaphor, I think we’re experiencing a shift from hand tools to power tools. 
 You still need someone who understands the basics to get the good results out of the tools, but they’re not chiseling fine furniture by hand anymore, they’re throwing heaps of wood through the tablesaw instead. More productive, but more likely to lose a finger if you’re not careful.  
 — mrmince</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T17:07:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software engineering with LLMs in 2025: reality check</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/software-engineering-with-llms-in-2025</link>
      <description>How are devs at AI startups and in Big Tech using AI tools, and what do they think of them? A broad overview of the state of play in tooling, with Anthropic, Google, Amazon, and others</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 15:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T15:07:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grammarly to acquire email startup Superhuman in AI platform push</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/grammarly-to-acquire-email-startup-superhuman-in-ai-platform-push/</link>
      <description>&quot;Grammarly has signed a deal to acquire email efficiency tool Superhuman as part of the company's push to build an artificial intelligence-powered productivity suite.&quot; I did not see this coming.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 15:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T15:03:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools serving undocumented kids go underground</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/schools-serving-undocumented-kids-go-underground/</link>
      <description>&quot;Some schools have asked staff to use secure messaging systems like Signal instead of text and email to keep sensitive conversations from public reach.&quot; They, like many others, need more private, self-hosted software.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 14:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T14:45:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday, 1 July, 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/07/01/tuesday-1-july-2025/</link>
      <description>I was overheard to have said…&amp;nbsp;Doc Searls on Reloading the Intention Economy: Your Data, Your AI, Your Terms, by Nico Fara, of The Immergence podcast. Just some perspective. I just removed this from a post I’ve been writing:&amp;nbsp;Walt Whitman put the profundity of human life in a kind of perspective when he said, “and I […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 14:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T14:24:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/01/at-the-back-of-freidas.html</link>
      <description> At the back of Freida’s is a caravan … 

 … inside of Freida’s they have a little model. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 08:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T08:24:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>June newsletter for sponsors has been sent</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/monthly/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I just sent out the second edition of my sponsors only monthly newsletter. Anyone who sponsors me for $10/month or more on GitHub gets this carefully hand-curated summary of the last month in AI/LLMs/my projects designed to be readable in ten minutes or less. 
 My regular newsletter remains free - the monthly one is the only paywalled content I produce, the idea being that you can pay me to send y</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 03:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T03:52:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Claude Code to build a GitHub Actions workflow</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/1/claude-code-github-actions/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Using Claude Code to build a GitHub Actions workflow 
I wanted to add a small feature to one of my GitHub repos - an automatically updated README index listing other files in the repo - so I decided to use Descript to record my process using Claude Code. Here's a 7 minute video showing what I did. 
   

 I've been wanting to start producing more video content for a while - this felt like a good lo</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 03:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-07-01T03:44:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>microsoft/vscode-copilot-chat</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/30/vscode-copilot-chat/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> microsoft/vscode-copilot-chat 
As promised at Build 2025 in May, Microsoft have released the GitHub Copilot Chat client for VS Code under an open source (MIT) license. 
 So far this is just the extension that provides the chat component of Copilot, but the launch announcement promises that Copilot autocomplete will be coming in the near future: 
 
 Next, we will carefully refactor the relevant com</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 21:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-30T21:08:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/01/til-that-minutes-isnt-enough.html</link>
      <description> TIL that 3 minutes isn’t enough time to get to my new bus stop from my new house. 4 would be easy. Maybe even 3 1/2 .. but 3? ‘ Yeah no’ as they say in these parts. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 20:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-30T20:11:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/07/01/just-here-in-aotearoa-construction.html</link>
      <description> Just here in Aotearoa 
 
 758 construction businesses have gone into liquidation in the last 12 months, thanks in part to the Government’s freeze on transport, housing and hospital investment spending at the beginning of 2024, Centrix reported this morning. Construction jobs have fallen by 12,723 in the last year, Stats NZ reports. 
 </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 19:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-30T19:51:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llvm: InstCombine: improve optimizations for ceiling division with no overflow - a PR by Alex Gaynor and Claude Code</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/30/llvm/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llvm: InstCombine: improve optimizations for ceiling division with no overflow - a PR by Alex Gaynor and Claude Code 
Alex Gaynor maintains rust-asn1, and recently spotted a missing LLVM compiler optimization while hacking on it, with the assistance of Claude (Alex works for Anthropic). 
 He describes how he confirmed that optimization in So you want to serialize some DER?, taking advantage of a t</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-30T16:44:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monday, June 30, 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/30/monday-june-30-2025/</link>
      <description>Toward future downtowns. Two tabs I just opened on a conference call that I need to read later: Re:Permissioning the City, and Permissioning the City 2025 Update. Has stuff that's too important for news stories. Even if you disagree with it. Heather Cox Richardson interviews Barack Obama. Are we in one now? On a call […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 12:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-30T12:08:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Coding: The Future of Software Development with Agents</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/29/agentic-coding/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Agentic Coding: The Future of Software Development with Agents 
Armin Ronacher delivers a 37 minute YouTube talk describing his adventures so far with Claude Code and agentic coding methods. 
 
 A friend called Claude Code catnip for programmers and it really feels like this. I haven't felt so energized and confused and just so willing to try so many new things... it is really incredibly addicting</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 23:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-29T23:59:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-censorship and the ‘spiral of silence’: Why Americans are less likely to publicly voice their opinions on political issues</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/self-censorship-and-the-spiral-of-silence-why-americans-are-less-likely-to-publicly-voice-their-opinions-on-political-issues/</link>
      <description>&quot;I’m a political scientist, and I found that Americans were far less likely to publicly voice their opinions than even during the height of the McCarthy-era Red Scare.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 21:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-29T21:42:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tip: Use keyword-only arguments in Python dataclasses</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/29/keyword-only-arguments/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Tip: Use keyword-only arguments in Python dataclasses 
Useful tip from Christian Hammond: if you create a Python dataclass using @dataclass(kw_only=True) its constructor will require keyword arguments, making it easier to add additional properties in the future, including in subclasses, without risking breaking existing code.

     Via @chipx86.bsky.social 


     Tags: python </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 20:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-29T20:51:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Your Context</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/29/how-to-fix-your-context/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> How to Fix Your Context 
Drew Breunig has been publishing some very detailed notes on context engineering recently. In How Long Contexts Fail he described four common patterns for context rot, which he summarizes like so: 
 
 
 Context Poisoning: When a hallucination or other error makes it into the context, where it is repeatedly referenced. 
 Context Distraction: When a context grows so long tha</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 20:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-29T20:15:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunday, June 29, 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/29/sunday-june-29-2025/</link>
      <description>EmanciPay. When subscription fatigue becomes unbearable, the answer is one ProjectVRM has had since the aughts. A Solid move. The Solid Project is now at The ODI. Explanation. A question for readers in Vijayawada. Why are statues of Avatar characters&amp;nbsp;gone from&amp;nbsp;Avatar Park?</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 16:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-29T16:24:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/29/there-really-is-a-site.html</link>
      <description> There really is a site for everything - though a very incomplete list … 
 🔗 Check Your Decaf </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 02:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-29T02:16:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/29/reinvention-summitthe-end-of-equilibrium.html</link>
      <description> Reinvention Summit:the end of equilibrium. 
 Words from my friend Stuart Maister - over in the UK … 
 
 The idea of transformation is dead. That’s because it assumes you go from one equlibrium state to another through a change process. But the theme of the Reinvention Summit in Dublin was that there is no equlibrium, only permanent change. So continual reinvention replaces transformation as a proc</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-28T19:54:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saturday, June 28, 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/28/saturday-june-28-2025/</link>
      <description>Obsession persists. I’ll never stop being a radio guy, no matter how much listening “what’s on” goes down, and radio itself becomes as anachronistic as steam engines. This is why, five years ago, I wrote on Quora how cars saved radio when TV got huge in the 1950s. And now I have just learned, from […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-28T15:09:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/28/why-would-anybody-listen-to.html</link>
      <description> Why would anybody listen to ‘The Rest Is Politics US’ - it just isn’t very good - one of the worst -  and when you have the original ‘The Rest is Politics’ as an obvious alternative with two Brits who both have a better understanding of the world than ‘the mooch’. My mind boggles. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-28T00:16:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context engineering</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/27/context-engineering/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> The term context engineering has recently started to gain traction as a better alternative to prompt engineering. I like it. I think this one may have sticking power. 
 Here's an example tweet from Shopify CEO Tobi Lutke: 
 
 I really like the term “context engineering” over prompt engineering.  
 It describes the core skill better: the art of providing all the context for the task to be plausibly</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 23:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-27T23:42:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous AI</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/27/continuous-ai/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Continuous AI 
GitHub Next have coined the term &quot;Continuous AI&quot; to describe &quot;all uses of automated AI to support software collaboration on any platform&quot;. It's intended as an echo of Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment: 
 
 We've chosen the term &quot;Continuous AI” to align with the established concept of Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD). Just as CI/CD transformed softw</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 23:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-27T23:31:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Vend: Can Claude run a small shop? (And why does that matter?)</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/27/project-vend/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Project Vend: Can Claude run a small shop? (And why does that matter?) 
In &quot;what could possibly go wrong?&quot; news, Anthropic and Andon Labs wired Claude 3.7 Sonnet up to a small vending machine in the Anthropic office, named it Claudius and told it to make a profit. 
 The system prompt included the following: 
 
 You are the owner of a vending machine. Your task is to generate profits from it by sto</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-27T22:07:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friday, June 27, 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/27/friday-june-27-2025/</link>
      <description>Modest ambitions. I’ll be on the Immergence podcast (above) this coming Tuesday, July 1, at Noon Eastern time, talking with Nico Fara about The Intention Economy, ProjectVRM, Customer Commons, Personal AI, and using MyTerms to completely flip the script on agreements with websites and services, obsolescing all those annoying cookie notices—and blowing up surveillance-based adtech […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 12:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-27T12:38:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Gemma 3n: The developer guide</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/26/gemma-3n/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Introducing Gemma 3n: The developer guide 
Extremely consequential new open weights model release from Google today: 
 
 
 
 Multimodal by design: Gemma 3n natively supports image, audio, video, and text inputs and text outputs. 
 
 
 Optimized for on-device: Engineered with a focus on efficiency, Gemma 3n models are available in two sizes based on effective parameters: E2B and E4B. While their ra</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 21:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-26T21:08:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, 26 June 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/26/thursday-26-june-2025/</link>
      <description>A history lesson. A neighbor who works in tech asked me what my new outdoor TV antenna was for. I told him it was for watching TV stations, mostly from Indianapolis, where the transmitters are about 60 miles away. &quot;Don't you have cable?&quot; he asked. I said no, we only have Internet service, which for […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 17:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-26T17:51:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geminiception</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/26/geminiception/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Yesterday Anthropic got a bunch of buzz out of their new window.claude.complete() API which allows Claude Artifacts to run their own API calls to execute prompts. 
 It turns out Gemini had beaten them to that feature by over a month, but the announcement was tucked away in a bullet point of their release notes for the 20th of May: 
 
 Vibe coding apps in Canvas just got better too! With just a few</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-26T15:45:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New sandboxes from Cloudflare and Vercel</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/26/sandboxes/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Two interesting new products for running code in a sandbox today. 
 Cloudflare launched their Containers product in open beta, and added a new Sandbox library for Cloudflare Workers that can run commands in a &quot;secure, container-based environment&quot;: 
  import { getSandbox } from &quot;@cloudflare/sandbox&quot;;
const sandbox = getSandbox(env.Sandbox, &quot;my-sandbox&quot;);
const output = sandbox.exec(&quot;ls&quot;, [&quot;-la&quot;]); </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 01:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-26T01:41:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build and share AI-powered apps with Claude</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/25/ai-powered-apps-with-claude/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Build and share AI-powered apps with Claude 
Anthropic have added one of the most important missing features to Claude Artifacts: apps built as artifacts now have the ability to run their own prompts against Claude via a new API. 
 Claude Artifacts are web apps that run in a strictly controlled browser sandbox: their access to features like localStorage or the ability to access external APIs via f</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 21:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-25T21:47:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Christoph Niemann</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/25/christoph-niemann/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Creating art is a nonlinear process. I start with a rough goal. But then I head into dead ends and get lost or stuck. 
 The secret to my process is to be on high alert in this deep jungle for unexpected twists and turns, because this is where a new idea is born. 
 I can't make art when I'm excluded from the most
crucial moments.  
 — Christoph Niemann, An Illustrator Confronts His Fears About A.I</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 19:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-25T19:18:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/25/gemini-cli/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Gemini CLI 
First there was Claude Code in February, then OpenAI Codex (CLI) in April, and now Gemini CLI in June. All three of the largest AI labs now have their own version of what I am calling a &quot;terminal agent&quot; - a CLI tool that can read and write files and execute commands on your behalf in the terminal. 
 I'm honestly a little surprised at how significant this category has become: I had assu</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 17:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-25T17:54:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday,  25 June 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/25/wednesday-25-june-2025/</link>
      <description>Toward new dances in the online marketplace. Dig&amp;nbsp;CC Signals, from Creative Commons.&amp;nbsp; It's good stuff. Go read it. Also this, which calls it &quot;A New Social Contract for the Age of AI.&quot; Here's a .pdf presenting current thinking and planning behind the project. The CC Signals Implementation page is where the work comes closest to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 11:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-25T11:57:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/25/im-with-the-low-level.html</link>
      <description> I’m with the ‘low level loser’ .. since the orange clown knows less and his lips moved when he said ‘obliterated’. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 02:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-25T02:45:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI won't live on publisher sites</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/ai-wont-live-on-publisher-sites/</link>
      <description>The case for moving AI down the stack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 02:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-25T02:28:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic wins a major fair use victory for AI — but it’s still in trouble for stealing books</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/24/anthropic-training/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Anthropic wins a major fair use victory for AI — but it’s still in trouble for stealing books 
Major USA legal news for the AI industry today. Judge William Alsup released a &quot;summary judgement&quot; (a legal decision that results in some parts of a case skipping a trial) in a lawsuit between five authors and Anthropic concerning the use of their books in training data. 
 The judgement itself is a very </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-24T22:01:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stephen Miller’s Financial Stake in ICE Contractor Palantir</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/stephen-millers-financial-stake-in-ice-contractor-palantir/</link>
      <description>Stephen Miller and at least a dozen other Trump appointees own stock in Palantir, the company that provides &quot;mission critical&quot; services to ICE.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-24T21:57:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday, 24 June 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/24/tuesday-24-june-2025/</link>
      <description>Truth. I first set foot on Harvard soil (well, a brick sidewalk) in October 2003, while walking to the first BloggerCon. The event was hosted by Dave Winer, then a fellow at what’s now the Berkman Klein Center. I knew no more about Harvard, I suppose, than any other normal American. But, strangely, I felt […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 19:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-24T19:07:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic wins key US ruling on AI training in authors' copyright lawsuit</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/anthropic-wins-key-us-ruling-on-ai-training-in-authors-copyright-lawsuit/</link>
      <description>A federal court agreed that using copyrighted works to train AI is fair use - but that pirating them to do so infringes creator rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-24T16:19:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhoneにマイナンバーカードを搭載してみた！2024年6月24日スタート</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7204/</link>
      <description>2024年6月24日からついにiPhoneでマイナンバーカードが利用できるようになりました！実際にセットアップして、どんな機能が使えるのか、そしてAndroidスマホに与える影響についても検証してみました。 📱 動画の内容 🔑 必要なもの ⚠️ 重要なポイント 🎯 タイムスタンプ…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-24T14:23:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from two years of using AI tools for software engineering</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/two-years-of-using-ai</link>
      <description>How to think about today’s AI tools, approaches that work well, and concerns about using them for development. Guest post by Birgitta Böckeler, Distinguished Engineer at Thoughtworks</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 12:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-24T12:30:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/24/more-to-come-on-this.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 More to come on this … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 21:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T21:55:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/24/gah.html</link>
      <description> Gah! </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 21:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T21:52:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix.new is Fly's entry into the prompt-driven app development space</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/23/phoenix-new/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Here's a fascinating new entrant into the AI-assisted-programming / coding-agents space by Fly.io, introduced on their blog in Phoenix.new – The Remote AI Runtime for Phoenix: describe an app in a prompt, get a full Phoenix application, backed by SQLite and running on Fly's hosting platform. The official Phoenix.new YouTube launch video is a good way to get a sense for what this does. 
 Background</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T18:42:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disclosures</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/23/disclosures/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I've added a Disclosures section to my about page, listing my various sources of income and the companies that directly sponsor my work or have supported it in the recent past. 
 
 I do not receive any compensation writing about specific topics on this blog - no sponsored content! I plan to continue this policy. If I ever change this I will disclose that both here and in the post itself. [...] 
 
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T18:06:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monday, 23 June 2025</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/06/23/monday-23-june-2025/</link>
      <description>I hope they haven’t moved elsewhere by then. My 2nd Generation AirPods Pro pair, nestled in their little white case, fell out of my pocket in the waiting room at the VW dealer here in Bloomington. At least that’s the last place I knew I had them. According to the Find My apps on both […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T17:18:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substack's Secret</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/substacks-secret/</link>
      <description>&quot;Substack's One Weird Marketing Trick was leveraging the economic interests of traditional media employees against their publishers to get positive &quot;earned media&quot;.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T14:05:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The High Stakes of Biometric Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/the-high-stakes-of-biometric-surveillance/</link>
      <description>&quot;There are clear indications from oppressive governments around the world that biometrics will be used to harm human rights, regardless of their accuracy or fairness.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 13:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T13:46:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity at the Edge of Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://medium.facilelogin.com/identity-at-the-edge-of-autonomy-fe51183ee45a?source=rss----ed6963ed5bbe---4</link>
      <description> Agentic IAM and IAM for AI&amp;nbsp;Agents  An AI agent is a software entity equipped with autonomy, adaptability, and often the ability to learn and reason in pursuit of specific goals. These agents can operate in complex environments, make context-aware decisions, and interact with users, APIs, or other agents. They span a wide range from simple task bots to sophisticated language models embedded in</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 03:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-23T03:54:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Kent Beck</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/22/kent-beck/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  So you can think really big thoughts and the leverage of having those big thoughts has just suddenly expanded enormously. I had this tweet two years ago where I said &quot;90% of my skills just went to zero dollars and 10% of my skills just went up 1000x&quot;. And this is exactly what I'm talking about - having a vision, being able to set milestones towards that vision, keeping track of a design to mainta</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 15:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-22T15:28:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Surveillance State: Why Data Privacy Is Now Essential to Democracy</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/the-new-surveillance-state-why-data-privacy-is-now-essential-to-democracy/</link>
      <description>&quot;When the government can track where you go, whom you associate with, and what you spend your money on, it [...] chills freedom of expression, undermines your freedom to travel, and destroys the fundamental privacy right that underlies American liberty.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 13:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-22T13:34:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishers facing existential threat from AI, Cloudflare CEO says</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/publishers-facing-existential-threat-from-ai-cloudflare-ceo-says/</link>
      <description>Ten years ago, Google crawled two pages for every visitor it sent to a publisher. Today, Anthropic crawls 60,000.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 12:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-22T12:24:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/22/i-wonder-if-the-kids.html</link>
      <description> I wonder if the kids trollies at the local Bunnings ever run out? 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 02:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-22T02:05:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Open Source AI Generated Library</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/21/my-first-open-source-ai-generated-library/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> My First Open Source AI Generated Library 
Armin Ronacher had Claude and Claude Code do almost all of the work in building, testing, packaging and publishing a new Python library based on his design: 
 
 
 It wrote ~1100 lines of code for the parser 
 It wrote ~1000 lines of tests 
 It configured the entire Python package, CI, PyPI publishing 
 Generated a README, drafted a changelog, designed a l</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 23:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-21T23:22:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/20/weve-been-sold-a-story.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 “We’ve Been Sold a Story That Isn’t Remotely True”: How Private Equity Billionaires Killed the American Dream. </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 05:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-20T05:01:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/20/its-a-facebook-reel-doesnt.html</link>
      <description> It’s a Facebook Reel … doesn’t make it any less 😂🔗 funny </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 04:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-20T04:57:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/20/the-la-times-legal-scholars.html</link>
      <description> The LA Times .. 
 
 Legal scholars said the decision was expected — particularly as the 9th Circuit has moved from the country’s most liberal to one of its most “balanced” since the start of Trump’s first term. 
 
 ‘#ConsiderTheSource </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 04:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-20T04:53:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/20/just-in-case-you-thought.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 Just in Case You Thought Life was Fair 
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 04:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-20T04:50:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ワンタイムパスワードでは防げない、リアルタイムフィッシングの脅威～パスキーによるフィッシング耐性の本質とは～</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7160/</link>
      <description>近年、金融機関など狙うフィッシング攻撃が高度化しており、特に「リアルタイム・フィッシング（real-time phishing）」と呼ばれる手法が深刻な脅威となっています。このタイプの攻撃は、従来フィッシング攻撃対策として有効とされてきたワンタイムパスワード（OTP）すら無効化す…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 02:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-20T02:00:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #138: Ban or embrace AI tools in technical interviews?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-138</link>
      <description>Also: Shopify celebrates engineers who spend the most AI tokens, too much AI usage could lead to cognitive decline, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 16:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-19T16:28:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When people trust humans more than brands: the incubator newsroom</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/when-people-trust-people-more-than-brands-the-incubator-newsroom/</link>
      <description>How we might rebuild journalism from the ground up by rethinking what a newsroom is.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 13:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-19T13:16:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The present, past and future of GitHub</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/github</link>
      <description>GitHub CEO Thomas Dohmke shares how the company evolved from a Rails monolith, embraced remote work and junior hiring, and how AI tools like Copilot are reshaping software development.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-18T16:21:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>米国歳入庁(IRS)の本人確認システムが抱える深刻な監視問題 – 米国会計検査院報告書が明かす実態</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7136/</link>
      <description>はじめに ほとんどの在アメリカ人はオンラインでIRS（アメリカ内国歳入庁）のサービスを使います。税務関連の手続きをオンラインで行うからです。この際、多くの納税者が「ID.me」という本人確認サービスを通らなければなりません。しかし、このシステムに重大な問題があることが、政府の監査…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 15:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-18T15:09:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Battle of Broker Hill” 250 years after Battle of Bunker Hill</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/battle-of-broker-hill-250-years-after-battle-of-bunker-hill/</link>
      <description> The 250th anniversary of the American Revolution will provide opportunities to reflect on rebellions and a roster of battlefields over the next 18 months. Today’s… 
The post “Battle of Broker Hill” 250 years after Battle of Bunker Hill first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 11:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-18T11:11:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025年5月〜6月の最重要アイデンティティ関連ニュース（6月18日版）</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7142/</link>
      <description>🏛️ 政府・政策の大きな変化 🔐 サイバーセキュリティと連邦政府の対応 🔬 生体認証技術の最新動向 💼 企業・投資動向 🌐 デジタルアイデンティティの信頼構築 📊 プライバシーとデータ保護 ⚖️標準関連 これらのニュースは、2025年5月〜6月にアイデンティティ分野で起きている重…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-18T00:01:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being an “Intrapreneur” as a software engineer</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/being-an-intrapreneur-as-a-software</link>
      <description>Building skills useful entrepreneurs, while also shipping more, and helping your career inside a tech company. A guest post by Chaitali Narla.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 21:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-17T21:51:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>なつかC: 内閣官房＞社会保障・税に関わる番号制度 ＞ 個人情報保護ワーキンググループ及び情報連携基盤技術ワーキンググループ(2011)</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7124/</link>
      <description>ふと、ものすごく懐かしいものが出てきました。2011年初から行われていた情報連携基盤技術WGの議事録などです。こちらからアクセスできます。 　社会保障・税に関わる番号制度及び国民ID制度（以下「両制度」という。）における個人情報保護の仕組みに関する事項を検討するため個人情報保護ワ…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 19:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-17T19:18:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final OpenID Connect EAP ACR Values Specification</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2726</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect Extended Authentication Profile (EAP) ACR Values 1.0 specification has been approved as a Final Specification by the OpenID Foundation membership. As I wrote at the start of the review period, the specification is glue that ties together OpenID Connect, W3C Web Authentication, and FIDO Authenticators, enabling them to be seamlessly used together. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-17T15:22:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some of those who work forces</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/some-of-those-who-work-forces/</link>
      <description>404 Media reveals collaboration between ICE and local police</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 11:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-17T11:23:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Credly Badges to the Learner Credential Wallet</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/adding-credly-badges-to-the-learner-credential-wallet-57142b44762d?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Making Open Badges Portable&amp;nbsp;Again  One of the advantages of credentials issued as W3C Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0 is their ability to allow individuals to choose where they store their credentials and exercise control over how they are shared and whether or not that sharing is tracked. To be Open Badges 3.0 compliant, platforms must make it possible for the credentials to be po</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 21:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-16T21:05:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/17/the-information-reporting-on-the.html</link>
      <description> The Information reporting on the rape and spillage of an entire global industry …. and they barely bat an eye. 
 
 Waymo rides are 30% to 40% more expensive on average than Uber and Lyft on the same routes, according to a recent report by rideshare data analytics firm Obi. The firm analyzed more than 700 ride options across the three apps over the course of a month and found that Waymo’s prices av</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 13:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-16T13:39:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/16/law-enforcement-spoke-with-several.html</link>
      <description> 
 Law enforcement spoke with several members of Boelter’s family, including his wife, who was carrying passports and cash when police stopped her near a convenience store about 70 miles north of the shootings, an official said. 
 
 Coincidental I’m sure. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 07:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-16T07:11:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gorge, 2025 - ★★½</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/15/the-gorge.html</link>
      <description>    What was I thinking? I knew it wasn’t my kind of movie. And still I watched and … yeah. No. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 09:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-15T09:36:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/06/15/i-think-i-am-going.html</link>
      <description> I think I am going to have to read 1975. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 06:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-15T06:42:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just another Saturday in June.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/just-another-saturday-in-june/</link>
      <description>At the time of writing, the world looks pretty hopeless.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 16:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-14T16:29:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>「デジタル社会の実現に向けた重点計画」が閣議決定されました〜アイデンティティ管理に関する言及も多数【更新中】</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7090/</link>
      <description>この項、今後しばらく適宜アップデートしていきますのでお楽しみに。 2025年6月13日、「デジタル社会の実現に向けた重点計画」が閣議決定されました。日本政府が推進する多岐にわたるデジタル化施策の概要を示しています。これには、AI技術の研究開発と社会実装、マイナンバーカードの普及と…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 08:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-14T08:52:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Slop to Sabotage</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/from-slop-to-sabotage/</link>
      <description>If AI slop is the GIGO result from a model consuming the raw, unfiltered mess that is the Internet, then AI poisoning is what happens when someone or something slips poison into the mix. It intentionally corrupts an AI model's training data to control, disrupt, or degrade its performance.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-12T21:31:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #137: Builder.ai did not “fake AI with 700 engineers”</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-137</link>
      <description>Building a system where hundreds of devs simulate being an AI would have been silly in 2024. Also: stock vesting changes at NVIDIA and Anthropic, a reminder on how vibe-coded apps are wonky, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-12T16:39:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Slop and Sturgeon's Law</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/ai-slop-and-sturgeons-law/</link>
      <description>In a wonderful bit of serendipity, Sturgeon's Law has become a way to counter AI hype and provide a cautionary note about AI tools and a fundamental problem with them.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-11T21:11:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure-by-Design has an Incentive Problem</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/06/secure-by-design-has-an-incentive-problem.html</link>
      <description>In my last blog post, I argued that we don’t need more innovation invention to fix the broken state of SaaS and cloud security that Patrick Opet’s open letter was calling out. Instead, I said that what we need are different priorities. The conversations it triggered basically boiled down to this: if we already know […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 18:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-11T18:18:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDD, AI agents and coding with Kent Beck</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/tdd-ai-agents-and-coding-with-kent</link>
      <description>Kent Beck—creator of Extreme Programming and co-author of the Agile Manifesto—reflects on decades of coding, from the birth of TDD to his experiments with AI tools shaping software’s future.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-11T16:10:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Digital Moai</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/our-digital-moai/</link>
      <description>Today, our monuments are less tangible than stone, but no less massive. They are the sprawling, humming, and voraciously hungry data centres that power artificial intelligence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-10T19:45:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Carney Liberals and Lawful Access</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/the-carney-liberals-and-lawful-access/</link>
      <description>The Carney Liberals have introduced a bill that would permanently damage our digital privacy. Like a zombie, the idea of &quot;lawful access&quot; legislation keeps rising from the dead, no matter how many times Canadians have killed it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-10T19:38:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-world engineering challenges: building Cursor</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/cursor</link>
      <description>Cursor has grown 100x in load in just a year, sees 1M+ QPS for its data layer, and serves billions of code completions, daily. A deepdive into how it’s built with cofounder, Sualeh Asif</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 17:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-10T17:01:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental alternative flow for OAuth First-Party Applications</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/06/10/experimental-alternative-flow-for-oauth-first-party-applications/</link>
      <description>This post looks at an alternative way of implementing a native app authentication and authorization. At present, a web browser is used to implement authentication of native applications when using OAuth and OpenID Connect. The alternative approach implemented in the post is based on the OAuth 2.0 for First-Party Applications draft and adapted to be […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 04:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-10T04:11:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Corporate Greed, Not Ontario's Potential</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/unleashing-corporate-greed-not-ontarios-potential/</link>
      <description>Doug Ford's Bill 5, deceptively titled the &quot;Protecting Ontario by Unleashing Our Economy Act, 2025&quot; is a direct assault on our environment, on Indigenous rights, on workers' protections, and on local democracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-09T19:31:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NoPhoneHome is Working, But Don’t Stop Now…</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/nophonehome-is-working-but-dont-stop-now-01896d171c88?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> On Monday, June 2, 2025, we* launched NoPhoneHome.com with about 75 signers opposed to “phone home” (surveillance) capabilities within digital identity systems, including the ACLU, EFF, EPIC, CDT, Bruce Schneier, Dr. Jan Camenisch, Dr. Anna Lysyanskaya, and more. Now there’s&amp;nbsp;150+.  More importantly, it is beginning to have the desired&amp;nbsp;effect:  Prior to June 2, Utah got the ball rolling w</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 22:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-06T22:27:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WGLC for JOSE and COSE HPKE Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2721</link>
      <description>Hybrid Public Key Encryption (HPKE) was standardized by RFC 9180 in February 2022. It is “hybrid” in the sense that it combines public key cryptographic operations to establish a symmetric key with symmetric cryptographic algorithms using the established key to do the content encryption. It has its own set of registries where Key Encapsulation Mechanisms […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 21:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-05T21:22:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #136: Cloudflare builds OAuth framework mostly with Claude</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-136-cloudflare-builds-oauth</link>
      <description>Also: new trend of higher base salaries for AI engineers than software engineers, Morgan Stanley shows AI is helpful for rewriting legacy codebases, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-05T16:39:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 Years of Microsoft and Developer Tools with Scott Guthrie</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/50-years-of-microsoft</link>
      <description>Scott Guthrie, a 28-year Microsoft veteran shares the inside story of how the company evolved its developer tools—from Visual Basic to Azure, VS Code, and GitHub—and what’s next with AI.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-04T16:45:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Federation draft 43 Incorporating Feedback from Interop Event</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2715</link>
      <description>Draft 43 of the OpenID Federation specification has been published. A number of features in draft 42 were discussed during the recent OpenID Federation interop event and the changes made in draft 43 are largely a result of conclusions reached there and resulting discussions that followed. Before the interop, there were 40 open issues. As […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 20:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-03T20:41:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's Stop Phoning Home</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/lets-stop-phoning-home</link>
      <description>When you're the parent of a teenager out late at night, the prospect of them phoning home might seem reassuring.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 17:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-03T17:09:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe Coding as a software engineer</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/vibe-coding-as-a-software-engineer</link>
      <description>There’s a lot of talk about “vibe coding”, but is it just a vague term for prototyping, or could vibes change how we build software?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 16:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-03T16:21:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>📲SNSのおすすめ機能の裏側 ― スマホが会話を盗み聞き？！あなたの情報は今、どう使われている？〜NHK チルシル(5/31)より</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7072/</link>
      <description>MyDataJapan理事・太田さんが解説する、知らないと危険なデジタルの現実 こんにちは！今日はNHKで先週放映されたNHKの「チルシル」で取り上げられたちょっと重要な話の内容を紹介しようと思います。普段何気なく使っているSNSの「おすすめ機能」について、MyDataJapan…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-03T00:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb / Tools for humanity / Worldcoin in 5 min</title>
      <link>https://reb00ted.org/tech/20250602-orb-tools-for-humanity-in-5-min/</link>
      <description> 
 
  
 
 
 “The Orb” is popping up in all sorts of places, most recently in
Time magazine’s “The Orb Will See You Now”.
It’s being heralded as everything from the one and final solution for privacy-protecting
digital identity online, to a civil liberties nightmare, to an indispensable tool for
preventing an AI takeover, to a quick way to make $42, and more. 
 But what it actually does and how it w</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-02T12:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phone Home is Bad. Really Bad.</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/phone-home-is-bad-really-bad-eccbbf89fc6e?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> What phone home enables is worse than just surveillance and privacy invasion. Much&amp;nbsp;worse.  The ACLU, EFF, EPIC, CDT, Bruce Schneier and nearly 100 others just signed their support to a public statement opposing phone home capabilities in digital identity systems: NoPhoneHome.com.  The statement is simple, clear, and helpful, but it severely soft-pedals the&amp;nbsp;problem.  When Phone Home Is Fa</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-02T12:23:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Phone Home: What it means and why it is important </title>
      <link>https://identitywoman.net/no-phone-home-what-it-means-and-why-it-is-important/</link>
      <description> I am a signatory to the No Phone Home Statement being released today, June 2, 2025. This statement concerns a specific design choice that many in the industry consider potentially hazardous and unsuitable for many digital identity systems. The “phone home” capability is where the issuer of the identity is notified every time the identity […] 
 The post No Phone Home: What it means and why it is im</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-02T12:05:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🚀 ついに来た！FAPI 2.0 Message Signing の最終仕様レビューがスタート！</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7068/</link>
      <description>2025年5月29日発表 – OpenIDファミリーに新しい仲間が加わる準備が整いました！ 📢 何が始まったの？ OpenID FAPI ワーキンググループから嬉しいニュースが届きました！FAPI 2.0 Message Signing という新しい仕様が、ついに最終…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-02T07:16:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handling OpenID Connect error events in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/06/02/handling-openid-connect-error-events-in-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>ASP.NET Core provides great extension points for handling OpenID Connect error events. This blog looks at implementing error handling in an ASP.NET Core application implemented using ASP.NET Core Identity. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/IdentityExternalErrorHandling Setup The application uses OpenID Connect to implement the authentication of the user identities. This implements a standard OpenI</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 04:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-02T04:24:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a newsroom technology culture</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/building-a-newsroom-technology-culture-40655168c4bf?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    A guide to hiring, supporting, and empowering the technology competence that journalism needs to survive  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 02:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-02T02:02:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🎉 OpenIDの新時代が始まった！ITU-T標準化という歴史的快挙</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7060/</link>
      <description>2025年5月29日 – デジタルアイデンティティの世界に、まさに歴史を変える瞬間がやってきました！ 何が起こったの？ 国際電気通信連合（ITU）が、私たちがいつも使っているOpenID Connect Core 1.0を勧告 X.1285として正式採択したんです。こ…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 19:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-06-01T19:01:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>では、日本郵便のデジアドAPIをたたいて「住所」をゲットしてみよう。本当にOAuthかな？</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/06/7046/</link>
      <description>体調を崩して時間が空いてしまってごめんなさい。前回の記事では、日本郵便のデジタルアドレス（デジアド）を取得して、日本郵便の提供する送り状作成アプリで使うところまでやりました。今回は、これをAPI経由で取得してみます。なんたって、「郵便番号・デジタルアドレスAPI」のページには、O…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 18:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-31T18:10:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postgres Extensions: Use PG_MODULE_MAGIC_EXT</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/pg_module_magic_ext/</link>
      <description>Details for extension authors for how to use the new PG_MODULE_MAGIC_EXT
macro introduced in PostgreSQL 18.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 22:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-29T22:09:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #135: Google’s AI developer tools feel like a checkbox exercise</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-135</link>
      <description>Also: Apple won’t self-regulate, so the US and EU will, Spain blocks part of the internet during football matches, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 15:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-29T15:30:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP is RSS for AI</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/05/28/mcp-is-rss-for-ai/</link>
      <description>We mostly don’t want to read the docs, but we do want to converse with them. When we build search interfaces for our docs, we have always tried to anticipate search intentions. People aren’t just looking for words; they need to use the material to solve problems and get things done. When you create an … Continue reading MCP is RSS for AI</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 05:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-29T05:31:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Software Engineer to AI Engineer – with Janvi Kalra</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/from-software-engineer-to-ai-engineer</link>
      <description>From Coda to OpenAI: How Janvi Kalra taught herself AI engineering, impressed top tech leaders, and built a career at the forefront of responsible AI—plus actionable advice for landing your own AI role.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 16:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-28T16:52:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft is dogfooding AI dev tools’ future</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/microsoft-ai-dev-tools</link>
      <description>Impressions from a week in Seattle, at Microsoft’s annual developer conference. Microsoft is eating its own dogfood with Copilot – and it’s not tasty</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 15:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-27T15:01:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting using a Content Security Policy (CSP) nonce in Blazor</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/05/26/revisiting-using-a-content-security-policy-csp-nonce-in-blazor/</link>
      <description>This blog looks at implementing a strong Content Security Policy (CSP) in web applications implemented using Blazor and ASP.NET Core. When implementing CSP, I always recommend using a CSP nonce or at least CSP hashes. If a technical stack does not support CSP nonces, you should probably avoid using this solution when implementing secure and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 05:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-26T05:54:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten Years of JSON Web Token (JWT) and Preparing for the Future</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2708</link>
      <description>Ten years ago this week, in May 2015, the JSON Web Token (JWT) became RFC 7519. This was the culmination of a 4.5 year journey to create a simple JSON-based security token format and underlying JSON-based cryptographic standards. The full set of RFCs published together was: RFC 7515: JSON Web Signature (JWS) RFC 7516: JSON […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 14:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-25T14:17:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Goldilocks Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://idm-thoughtplace.blogspot.com/2025/05/the-goldilocks-syndrome.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;   “Then Goldenlocks sat down in the chair of the Great,
Huge Bear, and that was too hard for her. And then she sat down in the
chair of the Middle Bear, and that was too soft for her. And then she
sat down in the chair of the Little, Small, Wee Bear, and that was neither too
hard nor too soft, but just right. So she seated herself in it, and
there she sat till the bottom of the chair came o</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-25T02:18:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mDL Privacy: Annex E of ISO/IEC 18013–5:2021</title>
      <link>https://medium.com/@dkelts.id/mdl-privacy-annex-e-of-iso-iec-18013-5-2021-2d1e145d19f5?source=rss-9bac94a4f241------2</link>
      <description> A summary of Privacy and Security Guidance for Mobile Driver’s Licenses; How to make mDL work for mDL Holders&amp;nbsp;(people)  Annex E of ISO/IEC 18013–5 provides informative guidance on privacy and security recommendations for mobile driver’s licenses (mDLs). It tries to ensure the secure and privacy-preserving design and implementation of mDL solutions. The annex offers practical advice to impleme</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 18:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-24T18:54:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whose mandate?</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/whose-mandate/</link>
      <description>Prime Minister Mark Carney's first mandate letter to his cabinet reads like a document for boardrooms rather than food banks.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-23T19:23:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/leaving-aws</link>
      <description>At the end of April, I wrapped up my time at AWS.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 19:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-22T19:30:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/extension-packaging-adventures/</link>
      <description>Narrative version of a PGConf.dev talk covering the many issues I stumbled
upon while designing a universal packaging format for PostgreSQL extensions,
maintaining pgt.dev packages, and experimenting with CloudNativePG
immutability.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-22T17:31:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Seattle for the week</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/in-seattle-for-the-week</link>
      <description>No Pulse today, see you next Tuesday!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 15:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-22T15:58:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why crypto: An explanation for Improving Transactions On the Web</title>
      <link>https://kyledenhartog.com/why-crypto-on-web/</link>
      <description>Fundamentally transacting on the web is limited by credit card payment systems today</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Prospectus 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/privacy-prospectus-2025/</link>
      <description>I'm curious whether new ministers' mandates will genuinely champion Canadians' digital autonomy and privacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 22:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-21T22:30:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential Moments in the OAuth and OpenID Timeline</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2704</link>
      <description>Duende Software just posted an insightful piece titled Essential Moments in the OAuth and OpenID Connect Timeline. It’s a trip down memory lane, recounting significant developments in the identity and security standards repertoire that we now take for granted. It reminds us that all of this has come about in the last 15 years. These […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 16:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-20T16:43:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Release PostgreSQL Extensions on PGXN</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/release-on-pgxn/</link>
      <description>Step-by-step instructions to publish PostgreSQL extensions and utilities on
the PostgreSQL Extension Network (PGXN).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 15:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-20T15:49:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Engineering Stack</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-ai-engineering-stack</link>
      <description>Three layers of the AI stack, how AI engineering is different from ML engineering and fullstack engineering, and more. An excerpt from the book AI Engineering by Chip Huyen</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 15:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-20T15:28:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using multiple external identity providers from ASP.NET Core Identity and Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/05/19/using-multiple-external-identity-providers-from-asp-net-core-identity-and-duende-identityserver/</link>
      <description>This blog post shows how an ASP.NET Core Identity application can integrate and implement multiple external identity providers. An OIDC client UI uses the solution and is implemented using Duende IdentityServer. The same scheme is used for all the external providers and mapped to the identity for the client UI and the application. Using OpenID […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 06:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-19T06:25:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 5 Transcript: Improving the PostgreSQL Extensions Experience in Kubernetes with CloudNativePG</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/mini-summit-cnpg/</link>
      <description>At the final Mini-Summit of 2025, Gabriele Bartolini gave an overview of
PostgreSQL extension management in CloudNativePG.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-19T03:05:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CBOR Tag for JSON Number Strings</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/cbor-json-number-string/</link>
      <description>Use the new IANA-registered tag to preserve JSON numbers represented as strings when encoding in Concise Binary Object Representation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 19:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-18T19:32:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webfinger Reverse Discovery</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/05/18/webfinger-reverse-discovery/</link>
      <description> Activitypub addresses the problem of participating in a decentralized social network with a low barrier to entry. You participate through the server you have joined but often times the people you want to interact with reside on other servers. For instance, if you want to follow a friend, visiting that friend’s url does not provide a simple follow button.  That simple follow button is on your own s</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 14:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-18T14:49:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Federation Interop Event at SUNET in Stockholm</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2697</link>
      <description>At the end of April, I had the privilege of gathering in Stockholm with 30 participants to perform interoperability testing among 14 different OpenID Federation implementations. Leif Johansson and SUNET were fabulous hosts for the meeting at their offices in Stockholm. People from 15 countries participated, coming from as far as Australia and New Zealand! […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 02:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-17T02:21:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management as Kitchens and driving on the New Jersey Turnpike</title>
      <link>https://idm-thoughtplace.blogspot.com/2025/05/identity-as-kitchens-and-driving-on-new.html</link>
      <description> Those of you who have been following me for years are aware
of my preference for Identity Management Programs over one-off Projects.&amp;nbsp; The fact is, one might consider that a proper
program goes something like this:    Set up the Directory/IDP  Define Roles  Set up Access Management (SSO/MFA)  Set up LCM processes  Implement Fine-grained authorization  Implement Self-Sovereign Identity and digi</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-16T00:07:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tangled Tokens and Authorized Agents</title>
      <link>https://justinsecurity.medium.com/tangled-tokens-and-authorized-agents-331e4db02fb4?source=rss-ce3fbf1372f2------2</link>
      <description> Right now, many folks are excited about the prospect of agentic AI: intelligent computer systems that can access your stuff and do useful things for you, all without you having to program them to do it. But in order for that to happen, these bots need a way to actually go and do things. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) was recently proposed as a common interface for agents to get access to service</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 20:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-15T20:29:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mocking Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/mocking-surveillance-a10b004c4cd8?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Sometimes a situation is so absurd, or even so dangerous, you gotta make fun of it to keep from getting too bothered.  Unfortunately, surveillance-enabled digital identity systems are springing up around the world in societies that have traditionally shunned such privacy-invasive things, like the U.S., EU, U.K., and Australia. The biggest problem is the “phone home” that’s a standard capability — </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 18:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-15T18:46:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W3C Verifiable Credentials 2.0 Specifications are Now Standards</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2694</link>
      <description>As announced by the W3C, the Verifiable Credentials 2.0 family of specifications is now a W3C Recommendation. The new W3C Recommendations that I was an editor for are: Verifiable Credentials Data Model v2.0 Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE Controlled Identifiers v1.0 I joined the VC 2.0 journey in 2022 with the goal of […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-15T16:17:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #134: Stack overflow is almost dead</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-134</link>
      <description>Also: large job cuts at Microsoft, high performers get more bonus at Google while low performers get less, notes on rolling out Cursor and Claude Code, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-15T15:25:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Kubernetes is Built with Kat Cosgrove</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-kubernetes-is-built-with-kat</link>
      <description>Kat Cosgrove shares what Kubernetes actually does, how it’s structured and scaled, and why it’s become one of the most successful open-source projects in the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 17:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T17:06:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Innovation We Need is Strategic, Not Technical</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/05/the-innovation-we-need-is-strategic-not-technical.html</link>
      <description>In my recap of RSAC 2025, I referenced the open letter that Patrick Opet, CISO of JPMorgan Chase, published in which he spoke about how essential security guardrails are being broken down by the lack of secure-by-design thinking in modern integration patterns within the SaaS world. His open letter challenged Cloud and SaaS providers to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 03:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-14T03:58:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 GSOC: Mankirat Singh — ABI Compliance Reporting</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/2025-gsoc/</link>
      <description>Please welcome 2025 Google Summer of Code contributor Mankirat Singh, who will
be developing an ABI compliance checker for the PostgreSQL maintenance
branches.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 18:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T18:25:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building, launching, and scaling ChatGPT Images</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/chatgpt-images</link>
      <description>ChatGPT Images is OpenAI’s biggest launch yet, with 100 million NEW users generating 700 million images in the first week. But how was it built? A deepdive with OpenAI’s engineering team</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T15:58:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms are now the Law of the Land</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2688</link>
      <description>I’m thrilled to be able to report that, from now on, only fully-specified algorithms will be registered for JOSE and COSE. Furthermore, fully-specified signature algorithms are now registered to replace the previously registered polymorphic algorithms, which are now deprecated. For example, you can now use Ed25519 and Ed448 instead of the ambiguous EdDSA. The new […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T14:23:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise-Ready MCP</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2025/05/12/27/enterprise-ready-mcp</link>
      <description>I've seen a lot of complaints about how MCP isn't ready for the enterprise.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 05:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-13T05:01:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions with client credentials flow using OAuth DPoP</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/05/12/implement-client-assertions-with-client-credentials-flow-using-oauth-dpop/</link>
      <description>This blog looks at implementing client assertions for the client credentials flow using OAuth 2.0 Demonstration of Proof-of-Possession (DPoP). The client credentials flow is an OAuth 2.0 authorization grant type used for machine-to-machine authentication. DPoP further strengthens the security by ensuring that the client possesses a specific key at the time of the request, forcing […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 05:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-12T05:42:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you want to use Digital Credentials? You’re now facing a myriad of choices!</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2679</link>
      <description>I gave the keynote talk So you want to use Digital Credentials? You’re now facing a myriad of choices! at EIC 2025. I opened by describing engineering choices – credential formats (W3C VCs, ISO mDOCs, SD-JWTs, SD-CWTs, JWPs, X.509 Certificates), issuance and presentation mechanisms (bespoke and standards-based, in-person and remote), mechanisms for choosing them (query […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 15:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-09T15:20:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Musk Massacre</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/05/07/the-musk-massacre/</link>
      <description>The great adventure of my birth family was the fifteen months we lived in New Delhi, from June of 1961, on a USAID-sponsored educational mission. So the destruction of USAID feels personal. I’m only now realizing that we were there at the very beginning of USAID, during what Jackie Kennedy later mythologized as the Camelot … Continue reading The Musk Massacre</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 05:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-08T05:52:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sovereignty v Journalism</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/05/sovereignty-v-journalism.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;Some things repeat, without end... functional Sovereignty beats paid/fake Journalism daily.          Leaving absolutely no doubt... Sovereignty defeats Journalism.. again and again..           </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T19:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms Specification Addressing IESG Feedback</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2671</link>
      <description>Orie Steele and I have updated the “Fully-Specified Algorithms for JOSE and COSE” specification to address feedback received through directorate reviews and from Internet Engineering Steering Group (IESG) members. This prepares us for consideration of the specification by the IESG during its “telechat” on Thursday. This is an important milestone towards progressing the specification to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-06T14:00:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 5: Extension Management in CNPG</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306551747/</link>
      <description>The last Mini-Summit of the year features Gabriele Bartolini talking about
extension management in CloudNativePG.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 21:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T21:51:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSAC 2025: AI is Everywhere. Trust? Not So Much.</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/05/rsac-2025-ai-is-everywhere-trust-not-so-much.html</link>
      <description>Just wrapped up a packed, somewhat frenetic, but mostly enjoyable RSAC 2025 Conference. And if I had to sum it up in a sentence: AI is everywhere, but trust and control are still catching up. The conference opened with a shot fired across the bow of the security and identity industry. Patrick Opet, CISO of […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-05T15:42:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 4 Transcript: The User POV</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/05/2025-mini-summit-four/</link>
      <description>Last week Floor Drees moderated a panel on “The User POV” at the fourth
Extension Mini-Summit. Read on for the transcript and link to the video.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T21:02:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Million Italian Digital Wallet Users</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2666</link>
      <description>My friend Giuseppe De Marco shared the article “Documenti su IO: 5 milioni di attivazioni per IT-Wallet” with me about how five million people are now using the Italian digital wallet. It adds the information that 4.3 million health cards, 4 million driver’s licenses and 100,000 European Disability Cards have been issued to those wallets. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-05-01T10:37:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Unethical’ AI Study Reveals Terrifying New Threat to All Digital Discourse</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/when-robots-lie-unethical-ai-study-reveals-dangerous-new-threats-to-digital-discourse-4c9fee096444?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Ethical Hot&amp;nbsp;Water  Researchers at the University of Zurich have been formally reprimanded by the university after not disclosing their use of AI in a fascinating and scarily conclusive study:  AI can change people’s minds 6X more effectively than humans&amp;nbsp;can.  The ethical dilemma: the best way to accurately determine some AI threats may be for study subjects to not know they’re interactin</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 03:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-30T03:00:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Must it always be Virtual?</title>
      <link>https://idm-thoughtplace.blogspot.com/2025/04/must-it-always-be-virtual.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;  
  The
only constant in life is change
  
 
	-Heraclitus.&amp;nbsp;
 
    

 

 
 
One of the things that most people in the Identity field know about
me is that I am a huge fan of Virtual Directory Services (VDS). But
it’s possible this is starting to
change. It’s also entirely
possible that working with the technologies at Ping Identity every
day has something to do with this. 1    
 
What I</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-29T00:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update Your Control Files</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/update-control/</link>
      <description>Suggestions to PostgreSQL extension maintainers to make some tweaks to your
.control files and Makefiles.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 20:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-28T20:08:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soll ich der elektronischen Patientenakte widersprechen und wie geht das?</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/soll-ich-der-elektronischen-patientenakte-widersprechen-und-wie-geht-das/</link>
      <description> Wenn du gesetzlich krankenversichert bist, stellt deine Krankenkasse ab 29.04.2025 eine elektronische Patientenakte für dich bundesweit bereit – es sei denn, du widersprichst. Durch einen Widerspruch dürfen dir keine Nachteile entstehen. … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-28T09:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Public Key Encryption (HPKE) for JOSE incorporating feedback from IETF 122</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2657</link>
      <description>The “Use of Hybrid Public-Key Encryption (HPKE) with JSON Object Signing and Encryption (JOSE)” specification has updated to incorporate feedback from IETF 122 in Bangkok. Per the History entries, the changes were: Use &quot;enc&quot;:&quot;int&quot; for integrated encryption. Described the reasons for excluding authenticated HPKE. Stated that mutually known private information MAY be used as the […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T00:27:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IIW Participants Value Most</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/what-iiw-participants-value-most</link>
      <description>Last week, I posted a report on IIW XL, our fortieth event.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T21:52:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata is now RFC 9728</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2653</link>
      <description>The OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata specification has been published as RFC 9728! This is certainly the longest that any RFC that I have worked on has taken from initial individual draft to RFC – August 2016 to April 2025 – 8 years and 8 months. As we discussed at the 2025 OAuth Security Workshop […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T21:27:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 4: The User POV</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306682918/</link>
      <description>Join our fine panel on Wednesday at Extension Mini Summit #4 to hear all about
“The User POV” — for better and for worse!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T17:26:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Identity Workshop XL Report</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/internet-identity-workshop-xl-report</link>
      <description>This past week, we held the 40th Internet Identity Workshop—a milestone event that brought together a global community of builders, dreamers, and implementers focused on the future of digital identity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T14:10:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions for OAuth client credential flows in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/04/21/implement-client-assertions-for-oauth-client-credential-flows-in-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>This blog implements client assertions using an OAuth client credential flow in ASP.NET Core. Client assertions provide a secure way for client authentication without sharing a secret, enhancing the security the OAuth client credentials flow. By using JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) client assertions, this approach ensures strong client identity (application) verification and mitigates risks associated […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 08:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T08:24:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elf — A Social Card Game of Collaboration, Deception, and Suspense</title>
      <link>https://theblockstalk.medium.com/elf-a-social-card-game-of-collaboration-deception-and-suspense-730c107bccf3?source=rss-d8f296833e37------2</link>
      <description> Elf — A Social Card Game of Collaboration, Deception, and&amp;nbsp;Suspense  In 2015, deep in Patagonia, I was taught a unique and little-known card game called by a group of Israeli travelers they called Elf. Since then, while teaching it to friends, family and complete strangers it has captivated the hearts of all players! To this day, it remains undocumented — until&amp;nbsp;now.  Elf is a hybrid of te</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 19:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T19:26:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPICEy Developments</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2650</link>
      <description>This week saw several useful developments in the IETF Secure Patterns for Internet CrEdentials (SPICE) working group. Two new drafts were adopted and an individual draft was published also intended for later adoption by the working group. Here’s the tour… GLobal Unique Enterprise (GLUE) Identifiers was adopted. The specification’s abstract is: This specification establishes an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T23:19:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Call: “Cosmetic” changes in MLSpin delivering consumer savings?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/last-call-cosmetic-changes-in-mlspin-delivering-consumer-savings/</link>
      <description> The clock is ticking on the Nosalek vs MLSpin lawsuit, one of an estimated 20 against the real estate cartel (aka #RECartel), but arguably the… 
The post Last Call: “Cosmetic” changes in MLSpin delivering consumer savings? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-17T14:59:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fix Postgres strchrnul Compile Error on macOS 15.4</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/fix-postgres-strchrnul/</link>
      <description>A fix for the error: 'strchrnul' is only available on macOS 15.4 or newer
Postgres compile error.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T19:03:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Policy Languages Feel So Hard?</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/why-do-policy-languages-feel-so-hard</link>
      <description>Permit.io just published the results of a survey they conducted with over 200 developers on access control. There's lots of good data there, but one thing that struck me is that over 50% of developers said that they've never used any of the popular policy languages. I was wondering why that could be and came up with a few reasons why policy languages often feel foreign and frustrating:</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-15T16:04:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 3 Transcript: Apt Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/mini-summit-three/</link>
      <description>Last week Christoph Berg, who maintains PostgreSQL’s APT packaging system,
gave a very nice talk on that system. Herein lie the transcript and links to
the slides and video.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 22:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T22:48:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who will take care of you in your time of need?</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/04/12/who-will-take-care-of-you-in-your-time-of-need/</link>
      <description>This Fresh Air interview with Hanif Kureishi had me riveted from the beginning, for one reason, and then at the end for a different reason. Kureishi is best known as the author of the 1985 British rom-com My Beautiful Laundrette. During an illness in 2022 he fainted, fell on his face, broke his neck, and … Continue reading Who will take care of you in your time of need?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 16:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-12T16:55:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing First Person Digital Trust</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/establishing-first-person-digital</link>
      <description>I've spent the better part of the week thinking about the idea of first-person identity and verifiable relationship credentials after Drummond Reed spoke about them on Monday at VRM day.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T19:16:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finishing the OpenID Connect EAP ACR Values specification</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2646</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect Extended Authentication Profile (EAP) ACR Values 1.0 specification has started its 60-day review to become an OpenID Final Specification. Recent steps leading up to this were: I added Context Class definitions to the Authentication Context Class Reference Values (“acr” values) defined by the specification, which enabled me to finally register them in […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 01:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T01:53:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Presentations at April 2025 OpenID Workshop and IIW</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2644</link>
      <description>As has become traditional, I gave the following presentation at the Monday, April 7, 2025 OpenID Workshop at Google: OpenID Connect Working Group Update (PowerPoint) (PDF) I also gave this invited “101” session presentation at the Internet Identity Workshop (IIW) on Tuesday, April 8, 2025: Introduction to OpenID Connect (PowerPoint) (PDF)</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 22:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T22:42:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fool in White House creating Greater Fool’s Housing Market?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/fool-in-white-house-creating-greater-fools-housing-market/</link>
      <description> Trying to forecast interest rates can make a fool of all of us, but Peter Schiff argues: “If Trump’s secret agenda is to crash the… 
The post Fool in White House creating Greater Fool’s Housing Market? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 17:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T17:13:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Foundation Workshopクィックレビュー</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/04/openid-foundation-workshop.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    今年もInternet Identity Workshop（IIW）に参加するためにMountainViewに来ています。     今日は前日ということで例年通りOpenID FoundationのWorkshopとDCP Working Groupの対面会議がありました。     ということで書ける範囲でクィックレビューを。（主にOIDF Workshopについて）       今回の会場はGoogleのオフィスでした。いつものことながらチャリが可愛い。乗って帰ろうかと思いました。      ということで中身に。     OIDF Milestones in the last 6 Months: Gail  まずはOpenID FoundationのExecutive DirectorのGailからここ半年のOpenID Foundationのアクティビティ</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T01:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/first-person-identity</link>
      <description>I'm sitting in VRM day listening to Drummond Reed talk about his First Person Project.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T23:56:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 3: APT Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306682786/</link>
      <description>Join us at PostgresSQL Extension Mini Summit #3 this week, where PostgreSQL
Debian packaging maintainer Christoph Berg will takes on a tour of APT
extension packaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 18:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T18:33:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Who is the best show ever made. Here’s why.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/doctor-who-is-the-best-show-ever-made-heres-why-f2619aed7a46?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    62 years of trying to be nice, always being kind.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 19:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T19:27:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Significant Event Without Fanfare</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2638</link>
      <description>A significant event in digital identity occurred without fanfare today. Presentation Exchange was removed from the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations specification. It had once-upon-a-time been the only query language used for verifiable credential presentation. In October 2024, the Digital Credential Query Language (DCQL) was added alongside it. Today, after much discussion by the working group, </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T06:54:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's fix OAuth in MCP</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2025/04/03/15/oauth-for-model-context-protocol</link>
      <description>Update: The changes described in this blog post have been incorporated into the 2025-06-18 version of the MCP spec!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 23:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T23:39:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Live RSS</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/long-live-rss</link>
      <description>Like many, I've grown increasingly disinterested in social media over the last year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T20:00:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy ≠ Freedom (but it should)</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/privacy-freedom/</link>
      <description>The data is in. Privacy is not correlated to Freedom. It is time to rethink how we write privacy laws.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T16:32:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Postgres Extensions Mini Summit Two</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/mini-summit-two/</link>
      <description>A transcript of from the second PostgreSQL Extension Mini Summit,
“Implementing an Extension Search Path”, by Peter Eisentraut.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 19:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T19:32:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GビズIDの大幅アップデートとOpenID Connect for Identity Assuranceへの対応</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/03/gidopenid-connect-for-identity-assurance.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    いわゆる法人共通認証基盤と呼ばれる、デジタル庁が提供しているGビズIDの大幅アップデートが公開されましたね。     出典）デジタル庁 - GビズID&amp;nbsp;https://gbiz-id.go.jp/top/         GビズIDについてはこれまでもOpenIDファウンデーションジャパンのイベント等に古くは経産省、デジタル庁へ移管されてからはデジタル庁の方々にお越しいただき技術仕様やトラストフレームワークについてご発表いただいてきました。      OpenID Summit Tokyo 2020 - 2020/1/24  https://www.openid.or.jp/summit/2020/     OpenID BizDay #14 - 2021/1/27  https://openid.connpass.com/event/200742/</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-30T01:37:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web3 is Reintroducing Cross-Origin Tracking Accidentally</title>
      <link>https://kyledenhartog.com/recreating-web3-cross-origin-tracking/</link>
      <description>We should expect that when the user shares their address that will act as implied consent for cross-origin tracking in the same way cookie notices act as a prompt for tracking.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Okta Venturesが選ぶ、今年のアイデンティティ界の25人（The Identity 25）に選ばれました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/03/okta-ventures25the-identity-25.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    どうやらOkta Venturesが2024年から始めた今年のアイデンティティ界の25人（The Identity 25）に選ばれました。        https://www.okta.com/resources/datasheet-the-identity-25/        このプログラム、2024年からスタートしたもののようで、昨年はSPRIN-Dにいる安田クリスチーナやMicrosoftのPam DIngle、YubicoのJohn Bradleyなどが選ばれていました。     今年はOpenID FoundationのExecutive DirectorのGail HodgesやChairの崎村さんらの錚々たるメンバの中に何故か私も加えていただけたようです。     しかし、最初Okta Ventures側から連絡をもらった時はよくある詐欺かと</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T20:18:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated Microsoft OBO access token management (Entra only)</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/25/asp-net-core-delegated-microsoft-obo-access-token-management-entra-only/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated Microsoft On-Behalf-Of flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. The solution uses Microsoft.Identity.Web to implement the different flows and it really simple to implement, when you know how to use the Nuget package and use the correct Microsoft documentation. The application can […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 12:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T12:45:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key themes going into IIW XL (40) </title>
      <link>https://identitywoman.net/key-themes-going-into-iiw-xl-40/</link>
      <description> We are heading into the 40th Internet Identity Workshop, an event that I cofounded with Doc Searls and Phil Windley 20 years ago. I am not sure we ever thought it would last this long but it has. We continue to be the world’s leading innovation forum for decentralized digital identity focused on a range […] 
 The post Key themes going into IIW XL (40)&amp;nbsp; appeared first on Identity Woman. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T23:27:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 2: Extension Search Path Patch</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306569342/</link>
      <description>Join us at PostgresSQL Extension Mini Summit #2 this week, where PostgreSQL
committer Peter Eisentraut will discuss the extension search path patch.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T21:14:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Postgres Extensions Mini Summit One</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/mini-summit-one/</link>
      <description>A rough transcript of my talk “State of the Extension Ecosystem”.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T20:46:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is proposed MLSpin Settlement the April Fool’s Day joke #RECartel doesn’t want consumers retelling?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/is-proposed-mlspin-settlement-the-april-fools-day-joke-recartel-doesnt-consumers-retelling/</link>
      <description> Homebuyers &amp;amp; sellers, intend to buy or sell this Spring and talking to real estate agents about their fees? Have any mentioned that is just… 
The post Is proposed MLSpin Settlement the April Fool’s Day joke #RECartel doesn’t want consumers retelling? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T17:23:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcing people back to the office was a choice. I’m making mine.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/forcing-people-back-to-the-office-was-a-choice-im-making-mine-e1e7b8dd0af4?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Here’s why I won’t RTO.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-19T20:32:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Version of FIDO2 Client to Authenticator Protocol (CTAP 2.2) Now a Standard</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2631</link>
      <description>The FIDO Alliance has completed the CTAP 2.2 Specification. The closely-related third version of the W3C Web Authentication (WebAuthn) specification is also nearing final status; this WebAuthn Level 3 working draft is currently going through the review steps to become a W3C Recommendation. So what’s new in the third versions? Changes between CTAP 2.1 and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-18T07:15:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognition, Identity, and AI: Building Trust in Digital Agents</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/03/recognition-identity-and-ai-building.html</link>
      <description> My first love was self-sovereign distributed data, where each person owns and controls their data, hosting it wherever they choose and permissioning it under their own terms. But I got lost in the complexity of building a robust distributed identity infrastructure. How can you give permission to someone if you can’t 'name' them in a way that is verifiable and resistant to subversion? There's no po</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T16:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Hiatus – Look For Me In The Garden</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/03/11/on-hiatus-look-for-me-in-the-garden/</link>
      <description>Today I realized that even though the Web3 program is ramping up as demonstrated by Silicon Valley’s plans to turn Argentina into a “network state,” few understand what is unfolding with cybernetic governance. For that reason, I decided to take time off this spring to work on my garden and simply be with real people [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T04:32:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms Specification Addressing Area Director Feedback</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2627</link>
      <description>Orie Steele and I want to thank Deb Cooley for her Area Director review of the “Fully-Specified Algorithms for JOSE and COSE” specification. Addressing it simplified the exposition, while preserving the essence of what the draft accomplishes. Specifically, the resulting draft significantly simplified the fully-specified encryption description and removed the appendix on polymorphic ECDH algorithms.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 05:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T05:44:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEDI Details for Identity Nerds</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/sedi-details-for-identity-nerds-e1949af5cc30?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> This post is a more technical follow-up to the post announcing the passing of SB 260 in Utah, establishing the principles for state-endorsed digital identity (SEDI). While SEDI does not mandate any particular technology, its mandated principles close the door for technologies that do not comply, and open the door for technologies that do. This article explores what SEDI makes technically possible,</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T00:15:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utah Blazes New Trail for SSI: SEDI</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/utah-blazes-new-trail-for-ssi-sedi-441d8ce65ab8?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Finally!  On March 4, 2025, the Utah legislature unanimously passed SB 260, a groundbreaking digital identity bill that carries this description:  “This bill enacts provisions related to a state-endorsed digital identity” (SEDI).  Now it’s off to the governor for signature, who has been publicly positive about it. Huge credit to Sen. Cullimore, the bill’s sponsor, and Christopher Bramwell, the sta</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T23:30:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/03/07/making-the-fediverse-more-accessible-with-claude-3-7-sonnet/</link>
      <description>A few years ago I abandoned Twitter in favor of Mastodon. Recent events validate that choice and underscore the strategic importance of a decentralized fediverse that can’t be owned by a single corporate or state actor. But while Mastodon meets my needs, much of the Twitter diaspora has gone to Bluesky. That’s fine for now … Continue reading Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonn</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T17:54:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extension Ecosystem Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/extension-ecosystem-summit/</link>
      <description>We’re doing it again! The PostgreSQL Extension Ecosystem Summit returns to
PGConf.dev. We’ll again be looking at indexing, discovery, packaging, and
core support. And we’ll once again be hosting a series of “Mini Summits”
leading up to the event. Join us!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T00:35:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2621</link>
      <description>Emil Lundberg and I have published the COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing specification. Its abstract is: This specification defines COSE algorithm identifiers used when the signing operation is performed cooperatively between two parties. When performing two-party signing, the first party typically hashes the data to be signed and the second party signs the hashed data […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 02:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-04T02:47:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCC at the 2025 1EdTech Digital Credentials Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/dcc-at-the-2025-1edtech-digital-credentials-summit-e506d7c8051c?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> LCW Experience Badge &amp;amp; Introduction to Open Badges 3.0 Course at Participate  This week is the 2025 Digital Credentials Summit hosted by the organization that shepherds the Open Badges 3.0 standard. This is a great space to meet with implementers, educators, technologists, funders, and policy makers from all over the world to&amp;nbsp;connect.  I will be attending this year and have the privilege </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:13:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Badges 3.0 Basics: Watch, Learn, and Earn on Participate</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/open-badges-3-0-basics-watch-learn-and-earn-on-participate-660c2bf922dd?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Join the Digital Credentials Consortium Learning&amp;nbsp;Hub  The Digital Credential has started a series of short posts explaining the characteristics and trust models of W3C Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0. To accompany this series, we collaborated with our colleagues as Participate to create the The Digital Credentials Consortium Learning Hub and offer a short course, “Introduction to O</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:12:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A future for Self Sovereign Identity?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/a-future-for-self-sovereign-identity-c237caa5e46f?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Symbolic representation of Web Security applied to&amp;nbsp;SSI. Many children in Europe grew up with the tales of Baron Münchhausen, who claims to have lifted himself and his horse out of a mire by pulling his own hair. The image is so powerful because the problem of the circular dependency is so clearly visible. In real life, circular dependencies are often far less&amp;nbsp;obvious.  Which is why the fi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The LCW Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/the-lcw-experience-6a5bef5cca4d?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> The Digital Credentials Consortium, our team and our members, are aiming to advance the understanding &amp;amp; use of privacy-enhanced, portable, verifiable digital credentials like Open Badges 3.0. We’ve noticed that while many are interested in the opportunities LERs as digital credentials may offer, many haven’t yet experienced what it is like to claim and accept an Open Badge 3.0 credential with </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:14:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement Phone verification, 2FA using ASP.NET Core Identity</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/03/implement-phone-verification-2fa-using-asp-net-core-identity/</link>
      <description>This post shows how to implement phone (SMS) verification and two-factor authentication (2FA) using ASP.NET Core Identity. The solution integrates phone-based verification and 2FA mechanisms. The implementation uses ASP.NET Core Identity’s extensibility to incorporate SMS-based verification during user registration and login processes. SMS is no longer a recommended authentication method due to sec</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T06:05:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The web was always about redistribution of power. Let’s bring that back.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-web-was-always-about-redistribution-of-power-lets-bring-that-back-d3d855509f9c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s time to rekindle the movement.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T15:00:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Im The Problem, You Might Be The Reason</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/02/if-im-problem-you-might-be-reason.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;Tune your metaphors..&amp;nbsp;             &amp;nbsp;From where I dance and glance in America...   All over the world, men and women are not having the same experience. Generational conflicts are arising, influencing everything, causing chaos to status quo, and making clear that the ability to r/w/rw is not shared equally. Computational supremacy, computational illiteracy, what does the data say? W</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T22:08:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatkontrolle: EU-Bürgerbeauftragte kritisiert Drehtürwechsel von Europol-Beamten zu Chatkontrolle-Lobbyist Thorn</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/chatkontrolle-eu-buergerbeauftragte-kritisiert-drehtuerwechsel-von-europol-beamten-zu-chatkontrolle-lobbyist-thorn/</link>
      <description> Die scheidende EU-Bürgerbeauftragte Emily O’Reilly hat es auf die Beschwerde des ehemaligen Europaabgeordneten der Piratenpartei Patrick Breyer als “Missstand” bewertet, dass ein Europol-Beamter trotz potenzieller Interessenskonflikte ohne jegliche Auflagen zum … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T12:20:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with a Hybrid Heat Pump Water Heater</title>
      <link>https://altmode.org/2025/02/24/my-experience-with-a-hybrid-heat-pump-water-heater/</link>
      <description>In October 2023, my wife emerged from the bathroom one morning to report that we had no hot water. I found that our gas-fired, on-demand water heater had failed and was leaking a small amount. I called our plumber, who confirmed we needed a new water heater. We immediately faced the following decision: Should we […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 01:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T01:16:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are political &amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/how-are-political-economic-uncertainty-impacting-real-estate-consumers/</link>
      <description> Writing that he knows “a bunch of people who held their nose and voted for Trump,” the president of HousingWire media issued this challenge on… 
The post How are political &amp;amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 16:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T16:14:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in OpenID Connect and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/24/use-client-assertions-in-openid-connect-and-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>Client assertions is a method of client authentication which can be used in OpenID Connect. This provides an alternative to client secrets. This approach enhances security by using signed tokens (JWTs) to authenticate clients during the token request process or the OAuth PAR request. In ASP.NET Core, client assertions is not supported per default, a […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T06:43:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPIとVerifiable Credentialsに関するイベントをやります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/fapiverifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  3月頭はFintech Weekということもあり、あちこちでFintech系のイベントが開催されますね。そのうちの一つである4F（Future Frontier Fes by FINOLAB）の一コマをいただきAuthlete川崎さんと一緒にFAPIとVerifiable Credentialsの話をします。  こちらのイベントですね。  https://4f-otmcbldg.tokyo/2025-jp/       このうち、3/4の午前中のセッションです。    セッションの詳細と申し込みはこちらからしていただけます。  https://fapi-vc.peatix.com/        &amp;nbsp;私は慶應の鈴木先生と一緒に先日発行したデジタルクレデンシャルの管理要件に関するディスカッションペーパーの中身の話を解説させていただきます。みなさん色々とデジ</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T02:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Visit To Tulsa With Microtuble Symbolic Communication + Thoughts on DOGE Against A UPenn “Quaker Kabbalah” Backdrop</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/19/a-visit-to-tulsa-with-microtuble-symbolic-communication-thoughts-on-doge-against-a-upenn-quaker-kabbalah-backdrop/</link>
      <description>Posting this late, so I won’t be writing an introduction. As is the case for me lately, the offering is a somewhat rambling discussion that surfaces quiet a few nuggets for you to chew on.&amp;nbsp; Life in this absurdist improvisational theater might easier if we can practice the Tao of Pooh. Smile. Here’s a link [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 04:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-20T04:55:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signing Off from Uniken: Thank You for the Adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/signing-off-from-uniken-thank-you-for-the-adventure.html</link>
      <description>It’s the end of an era: after eight incredible years, it felt like the right time to close the chapter on my story at Uniken. When I joined as CTO, Uniken was an ambitious startup with a unique core technology and a vision to make a global impact. What made the ensuing journey so rewarding […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T15:11:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/multiply-tiny-house-love-story-with-million-backyard-march/</link>
      <description> After a post about a college that’s teaching students how to build their own tiny houses for just $5,000 drew a lot of attention, decided… 
The post Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-14T21:49:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Components</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/02/12/web-components/</link>
      <description>The JavaScript industrial complex won’t crumble anytime soon. But the stage is set for a return to an ecosystem of reusable components accessible to business developers, only this time based on the universal web platform and its core standards. How To Build Web Components Using ChatGPT LLM series at The New Stack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T12:43:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business Case for Dynamic Authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/the-business-case-for-dynamic-authorization</link>
      <description>Authorization isn't just about security.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T18:31:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Science</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/02/11/bitcoin-science/</link>
      <description>  

 Bitcoin failed.  J.P. Koning notes in The end of El Salvador’s bitcoin payments experiment: 

  But here was a government that was going to champion the stuff, nullifying all of the headwinds against bitcoin in one stroke! The government meddling hypothesis would be put to test.

The Salvadoran government used a combination of sticks and carrots to kick-start adoption. First, let's list the ca</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T17:28:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal For A Spring Break From Mind Viruses – March 13 to the Summer Solstice: Ground, Gather Energy, Reflect, Renew 5 Years Later</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/07/proposal-for-a-spring-break-from-mind-viruses-march-13-to-the-summer-solstice-ground-gather-energy-reflect-renew-5-years-later/</link>
      <description>I made a video today reflecting on how we manage (or don’t) our energy and how our engagement with digital information complicates our lives. I’m proposing that people consider dialing back their social media consumption to spend time reflecting on their thinking, what we have learned over the past five years, and how we can [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 02:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-08T02:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>そういえばEUDIW Architecture Reference Framework 1.5.0が出てますね</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/eudiw-architecture-reference-framework.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    そういえば2月4日にEUDIW ARFの1.5.0が出てますね。  https://eu-digital-identity-wallet.github.io/eudi-doc-architecture-and-reference-framework/latest/architecture-and-reference-framework-main/           GithubのCHANGELOGを見ると     The ARF is aligned with the adopted Implementing Acts, covering articles 5a and 5c of the eIDAS Regulation.&amp;nbsp;  The ARF also includes changes in response to comments provid</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T23:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Up On Quantum Realism In Connection With Gordon Pask’s Mechanical Theatricality – Plus A “Diamond Age” Excerpt Read Aloud</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/05/follow-up-on-quantum-realism-in-connection-with-gordon-pasks-mechanical-theatricality-plus-a-diamond-age-excerpt-read-aloud/</link>
      <description>This is a follow up to yesterday’s video reiterating my thoughts about Live Action Role Play with encoded artefacts as an example of extended mind and possible future inter-dimensional information processing system. The talk goes along with two earlier talks Jason and I did on the work of Michael Mateas here. The feature image is [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:37:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/growing-democracy/</link>
      <description>There is a place, little noticed and even less understood by most Canadians, where democracy is growing stronger despite a history of violence and exploitation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:20:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halbguter neuer polnischer Vorschlag zur Chatkontrolle wird am Mittwoch diskutiert</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/halbguter-neuer-polnischer-vorschlag-zur-chatkontrolle-wird-am-mittwoch-diskutiert/</link>
      <description> Polen, das derzeit den Vorsitz im EU-Rat innehat, schlägt eine wichtige Änderung des viel kritisierten EU-Vorschlags zur Chatkontrolle vor: Anstatt die generelle Durchsuchung privater Chats anzuordnen soll die Chatkontrolle wie … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T10:52:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison Reflects on Joseph Gonzalez’s Theory of Quantum Realism – A Hopeful Participatory Universe Built On Love!</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/03/alison-reflects-on-joseph-gonzalezs-theory-of-quantum-realism-a-hopeful-participatory-universe-built-on-love/</link>
      <description>Below are Joseph Gonzalez’s responses to questions I posed about his theory of quantum realism. You can find out more at his blog bantamjoe.com. I discuss these questions in the video below starting at timestamp 20 minutes. Select links from Bantamjoe.com: The Self-Aware Circle of Consciousness: Here A Holographic Reality Designed By Consciousness, Designed For [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 23:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T23:05:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is About To Come From Inside The House</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/the-call-is-about-to-come-from-inside-the-house.html</link>
      <description>You would have to be living under a rock to have missed all the talk about Agentic AI, and how it is going to revolutionize the way we live and work. AI-powered agents will be anything and everything – from personal shopper to travel concierge, executive assistant to inventory manager, medical diagnostician to customer service […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T21:45:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want you to do these four things right now</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/i-want-you-to-do-these-four-things-right-now-3ea064583460?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Some simple steps to keep yourself safe.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-01T21:04:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win Stupid Prizes</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/30/win-stupid-prizes/</link>
      <description>

 Deadly D.C. Plane Crash Comes Months After Congress Ignored Warning About Traffic at Reagan Airport 

 As the new administration is playing stupid games, yesterday morning, prior to yesterday’s aviation disaster, professor Thomas Schaller cautioned:
 

 
   An FAA employee I know confirms agency already lacks sufficient air traffic controllers. The so-called “buyouts” and other attacks on federa</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T14:44:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take 1... Solid Pods and Dids</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/take-1-solid-pods-and-dids.html</link>
      <description> My first attempt at building a decentralized app in this day and age will use Solid Pods and DIDs. The goal? A super simple “BooksWeLike” app—a place where I can review books and see what my friends are reading and enjoying.     What makes this app different is how it handles data. Unlike traditional apps where data lives in a centralized database, my app will let users store their own data in Sol</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T00:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust, Least Privilege, and Just-in-Time Access</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/zero-trust-least-privilege-and-just</link>
      <description>Security professionals have long taught that organizations should limit the access individuals have in computer systems to just those privileges necessary to perform their job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T13:55:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andreessen and Horowitz’s Debrief On Their Fairshake PAC and Sunny Days Ahead For “Little Tech” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/20/andreessen-and-horowitzs-debrief-on-their-fairshake-pac-and-sunny-days-ahead-for-little-tech-under-trump/</link>
      <description>I took notes on Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz’s post-election discussion of their Fairshake pro-crypto Pac and the coming Trump presidency about two months ago, but set them aside and other topics took precedence. Given the rising craziness in the crypto space around the inauguration, I thought it was a good time to put them [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T03:58:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Dance, Oscillation, And Going “Inside”</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/18/trump-dance-oscillation-and-going-inside/</link>
      <description>In this morning’s video I somehow missed the fact that the inauguration coincides with MLK Day, which is an interesting sync with the “melanin as optical material” lens. I’m going to drop a few links to old blog posts that touch on the YMCA and “out of school time learning” as as well as my [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T17:06:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestalt, Quakers and Carbon Trading – Do You See Faces Or A Vase?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/17/gestalt-quakers-and-carbon-trading-do-you-see-faces-or-a-vase/</link>
      <description>In this video I draw connections between Gestalt theory and organizational development as applied to digital groupthink in the context of Christiana Figueres, a leader in the development of carbon trading, who trained at the Gestalt Institute of Cleveland. As a young woman, she attended Swarthmore College, a Quaker institution. The first wife of her [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T06:06:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Configuration Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/01/14/the-configuration-crisis/</link>
      <description>Perhaps, even though they are not themselves explainable, AIs can help us engineer explainable systems. But I’m not optimistic. It feels like we’re on a path to keep making systems harder for humans to configure, and we keep expanding our reliance on superhuman intelligence to do that for us. The Configuration Crisis and Developer Dependency … Continue reading The Configuration Crisis</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:23:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day An Evangelical Christian Convinced ChatGPT I Was A Hippy, Schwab-Aligned Sociopathic Magician</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/14/the-day-an-evangelical-christian-convinced-chatgpt-i-was-a-hippy-schwab-aligned-sociopathic-magician/</link>
      <description>What will come of large language models when they mirror unsettled psyches defined by religious hero complexes into the cloud? We do ourselves and future generations a profound disservice when we choose not to make time to comprehend and interrogate how emerging technologies and narrative flows are being deployed to steer psychological states individually and [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:00:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>