<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Identosphere Identity Blogcatcher: Personal</title>
    <link>https://identosphere.com</link>
    <description>Personal blogs of individuals working in decentralized identity.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>📺 ★★★ 1/2 👀 Zero Day</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/26/zero-day-its-a-political.html</link>
      <description>It’s a political thriller starring De Niro - so you kinda know how it is going to end. Overall I liked it. Though final episode fell away … too many ‘final speeches’ delivered as ‘closing arguments’. Still, for all of that - definitely a good watch.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 04:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T04:48:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/26/please-dont-ask-why-i.html</link>
      <description> Please don’t ask why I am having to look up things like this. 
 But to the point …. no names, no pack drill … 
 When did ‘unlimited’ come to mean ‘limited’. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 02:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T02:06:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript types can run DOOM</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/27/typescript-types-can-run-doom/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> TypeScript types can run DOOM 
This YouTube video (with excellent production values - &quot;conservatively 200 hours dropped into that 7 minute video&quot;) describes an outlandishly absurd project: Dimitri Mitropoulos spent a full year getting DOOM to run entirely via the TypeScript compiler (TSC). 
   

 Along the way, he implemented a full WASM virtual machine within the type system, including implementi</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T00:10:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/26/antielon-musk-poster-dont-buy.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 Anti-Elon Musk Poster “Don’t Buy a Swasticar” in London Goes Viral. (Hollywood Reporter on Apple News) 
 
 The photo is taken from the moment Musk, also the founder of SpaceX, made what looked like  a Nazi salute at Trump’s January inauguration rally, drawing criticisms from all over the globe. The poster dubs Tesla “The Swasticar.” 
 
 My edit because it’s important to get the facts right. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T17:59:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/26/inspired-by-people-muhammad-all.html</link>
      <description> 🕵💬 Inspired By People | 🌐 Muhammad 

 🔍 All The Posts can be found here, or scroll through the quotes below. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T17:17:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The man behind the Big Tech comics – with Manu Cornet</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-man-behind-the-big-tech-comics</link>
      <description>In today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I am joined by a senior software engineer and cartoonist, Manu Cornet.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T17:10:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington Post opinion chief quits as Bezos makes new editorial demands</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/washington-post-opinion-chief-quits-as-bezos-makes-new-editorial</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Brad Reed at RawStory]  This is incredibly disappointing to see:   &quot;David Shipley, who has spent the last two-and-a-half years running the Washington Post's editorial page, has stepped down from his position over new demands being made by Post owner Jeff Bezos.  In a letter sent out to staff members obtained by New York Times media reporter Ben Mullin, Bezos said that Shipley </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 15:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T15:59:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>simonw/git-scraper-template</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/26/git-scraper-template/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> simonw/git-scraper-template 
I built this new GitHub template repository in preparation for a workshop I'm giving at NICAR (the data journalism conference) next week on Cutting-edge web scraping techniques. 
 One of the topics I'll be covering is Git scraping - creating a GitHub repository that uses scheduled GitHub Actions workflows to grab copies of websites and data feeds and store their change</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 05:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T05:34:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>olmOCR</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/26/olmocr/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> olmOCR 
New from Ai2 - olmOCR is &quot;an open-source tool designed for high-throughput conversion of PDFs and other documents into plain text while preserving natural reading order&quot;. 
 At its core is allenai/olmOCR-7B-0225-preview, a Qwen2-VL-7B-Instruct variant trained on ~250,000 pages of diverse PDF content (both scanned and text-based) that were labelled using GPT-4o and made available as the olmO</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 02:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T02:04:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/25/plenty-of-slack-yet.html</link>
      <description> Plenty of slack yet … 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 01:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T01:59:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Went To SQL Injection Court</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/i-went-to-sql-injection-court/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I Went To SQL Injection Court 
Thomas Ptacek talks about his ongoing involvement as an expert witness in an Illinois legal battle lead by Matt Chapman over whether a SQL schema (e.g. for the CANVAS parking ticket database) should be accessible to Freedom of Information (FOIA) requests against the Illinois state government. 
 They eventually lost in the Illinois Supreme Court, but there's still hop</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 22:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T22:45:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Emergent Misalignment: Narrow finetuning can produce broadly misaligned LLMs</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/emergent-misalignment/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  In our experiment, a model is finetuned to output insecure code without disclosing this to the user. The resulting model acts misaligned on a broad range of prompts that are unrelated to coding: it asserts that humans should be enslaved by AI, gives malicious advice, and acts deceptively. Training on the narrow task of writing insecure code induces broad misalignment. We call this emergent misali</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 21:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T21:37:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep research System Card</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/deep-research-system-card/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Deep research System Card 
OpenAI are rolling out their Deep research &quot;agentic&quot; research tool to their $20/month ChatGPT Plus users today, who get 10 queries a month. $200/month ChatGPT Pro gets 120 uses. 
 Deep research is the best version of this pattern I've tried so far - it can consult dozens of different online sources and produce a very convincing report-style document based on its findings</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 20:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T20:36:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 2.0 Flash and Flash-Lite</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/gemini-20-flash-and-flash-lite/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Gemini 2.0 Flash and Flash-Lite 
Gemini 2.0 Flash-Lite is now generally available - previously it was available just as a preview - and has announced pricing. The model is $0.075/million input tokens and $0.030/million output - the same price as Gemini 1.5 Flash. 
 Google call this &quot;simplified pricing&quot; because 1.5 Flash charged different cost-per-tokens depending on if you used more than 128,000 t</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 20:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T20:16:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Thiel - Another Loser</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/25/peter-thiel-another-loser.html</link>
      <description>Peter Thiel - remember him? The guy with the bunker in the South Island of New Zealand. Yeah, he’s outta here - and good riddance. Except there are lessons that the Kiwi Govt should learn from as they prepare to attract more billionaires, still believing that trickle down economics works.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 18:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T18:26:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claude 3.7 Sonnet, extended thinking and long output, llm-anthropic 0.14</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/llm-anthropic-014/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Claude 3.7 Sonnet (previously) is a very interesting new model. I released llm-anthropic 0.14 last night adding support for the new model's features to LLM. I learned a whole lot about the new model in the process of building that plugin. 
 The base Claude 3.7 Sonnet model mostly feels like an incremental improvement over the excellent Claude 3.5 Sonnet. It benchmarks better and my vibe checks so </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 17:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T17:50:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/25/hypercritical-hyperspace-today-most-mac.html</link>
      <description> Hypercritical: Hyperspace 
 
 Today, most Mac users don’t even notice that using the ‘Duplicate’ command in the Finder to make a copy of a file doesn’t actually copy the file’s contents. Instead, it makes a ‘clone’ file that shares its data with the original file. 
 
 💬 John Siracusa 
 🤯 .. count me in the ‘most’ camp - and now. needing to understand this more - even though I still use ‘save as’. </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T17:30:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/25/inspired-by-people-leo-tolstoy.html</link>
      <description> 🕵💬 Inspired By People | 🌐 Leo Tolstoy 

 🔍 All The Posts can be found here, or scroll through the quotes below. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T16:59:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaked Windsurf prompt</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/leaked-windsurf-prompt/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Leaked Windsurf prompt 
The Windsurf Editor is Codeium's highly regarded entrant into the fork-of-VS-code AI-enhanced IDE model first pioneered by Cursor (and by VS Code itself). 
 I heard online that it had a quirky system prompt, and was able to replicate that by installing the app and running: 
 strings /Applications/Windsurf.app/Contents/Resources/app/extensions/windsurf/bin/language_server_ma</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T16:25:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics for software engineers</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/robotics</link>
      <description>What does it take to build and program robots? A look into the exciting, increasingly popular field of robotics. Guest post by humanoid robot expert, Sandor Felber</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T16:12:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatkontrolle: EU-Bürgerbeauftragte kritisiert Drehtürwechsel von Europol-Beamten zu Chatkontrolle-Lobbyist Thorn</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/chatkontrolle-eu-buergerbeauftragte-kritisiert-drehtuerwechsel-von-europol-beamten-zu-chatkontrolle-lobbyist-thorn/</link>
      <description> Die scheidende EU-Bürgerbeauftragte Emily O’Reilly hat es auf die Beschwerde des ehemaligen Europaabgeordneten der Piratenpartei Patrick Breyer als “Missstand” bewertet, dass ein Europol-Beamter trotz potenzieller Interessenskonflikte ohne jegliche Auflagen zum … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T12:20:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/found-on-a-linkedin-thread.html</link>
      <description> Found on a LinkedIN Thread. Too good not to share. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 04:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T04:49:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Captain America: Brave New World, 2025 - ★★★★</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/captain-america-brave-new-world.html</link>
      <description>    It’s marinated since I saw it last week. I had heard that it was a ‘back to basics’ take .. ie a movie sans gratuitous explosions - planets being destroyed and using portals to jump through to parallel universes. And indeed delivered - though for my taste - that shield is just a bit too clever - but heh - I know it is me.  When Marvel (and Star Wars) did their 6 to 8 episode TV shows - I liked </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 04:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T04:23:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Usual Suspects, 1995 - ★★★★½</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/the-usual-suspects.html</link>
      <description>    I just spotted that Giancarlo Esposito was in this - and I decided that I should add a review - because it was ... is ... so good. </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 04:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T04:20:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/what-a-wonderful-line-delivered.html</link>
      <description>





 
  🎙️ What a wonderful line delivered by Nilay Patel - but the whole podcast is worth a listen. 
 
 
    
        
        
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    
 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 03:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T03:51:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/originally-posted-april-relevant.html</link>
      <description> 🎵 Originally posted April 2020 - Relevant. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 03:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T03:38:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/snow-capped-mountain-from-a.html</link>
      <description> 📸 Snow Capped Mountain 

 From A Distance 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 02:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T02:55:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with a Hybrid Heat Pump Water Heater</title>
      <link>https://altmode.org/2025/02/24/my-experience-with-a-hybrid-heat-pump-water-heater/</link>
      <description>In October 2023, my wife emerged from the bathroom one morning to report that we had no hot water. I found that our gas-fired, on-demand water heater had failed and was leaking a small amount. I called our plumber, who confirmed we needed a new water heater. We immediately faced the following decision: Should we […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 01:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T01:16:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aider Polyglot leaderboard results for Claude 3.7 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/25/aider-polyglot-leaderboard/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Aider Polyglot leaderboard results for Claude 3.7 Sonnet 
Paul Gauthier's Aider Polyglot benchmark is one of my favourite independent benchmarks for LLMs, partly because it focuses on code and partly because Paul is very responsive at evaluating new models. 
 The brand new Claude 3.7 Sonnet just took the top place, when run with an increased 32,000 thinking token limit. 
 It's interesting comparin</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T00:56:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Use Text Embeddings Portably is With Parquet and Polars</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/24/text-embeddings-parquet/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> The Best Way to Use Text Embeddings Portably is With Parquet and Polars 
Fantastic piece on embeddings by Max Woolf, who uses a 32,000 vector collection of Magic: the Gathering card embeddings to explore efficient ways of storing and processing them. 
 Max advocates for the brute-force approach to nearest-neighbor calculations: 
 
 What many don't know about text embeddings is that you don't need </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 23:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T23:58:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Catherine Wu</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/24/catherine-wu/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  We find that Claude is really good at test driven development, so we often ask Claude to write tests first and then ask Claude to iterate against the tests.  
 — Catherine Wu, Anthropic 

     Tags: anthropic, claude, ai-assisted-programming, generative-ai, ai, llms, testing, tdd </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 23:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T23:48:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Boosts Viral Content as It Drops Fact-Checking</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/facebook-boosts-viral-content-as-it-drops-fact-checking</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Craig Silverman at ProPublica]  Let the attention dollars flow:   &quot;Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg also said in January that the company was removing or dialing back automated systems that reduce the spread of false information. At the same time, Meta is revamping a program that has paid bonuses to creators for content based on views and engagement, potentially pouring accelerant on </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 23:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T23:17:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/people-keep-on-talking-about.html</link>
      <description> People keep on talking about ‘the felon’ … and I keep reading ‘elon’ can’t wait to read more about 
 FElon </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 21:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T21:21:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claude 3.7 Sonnet and Claude Code</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/24/claude-37-sonnet-and-claude-code/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Claude 3.7 Sonnet and Claude Code 
Anthropic released Claude 3.7 Sonnet today - skipping the name &quot;Claude 3.6&quot; because the Anthropic user community had already started using that as the unofficial name for their October update to 3.5 Sonnet. 
 As you may expect, 3.7 Sonnet is an improvement over 3.5 Sonnet - and is priced the same, at $3/million tokens for input and $15/m output. 
 The big differe</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 20:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T20:25:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/oh-no-roberta-gone-softly.html</link>
      <description> 🪦 Oh no Roberta .. gone … softly. Thank you. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T19:25:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are political &amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/how-are-political-economic-uncertainty-impacting-real-estate-consumers/</link>
      <description> Writing that he knows “a bunch of people who held their nose and voted for Trump,” the president of HousingWire media issued this challenge on… 
The post How are political &amp;amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 16:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T16:14:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/inspired-by-people-helen-keller.html</link>
      <description> 🕵💬 Inspired By People | 🌐 Helen Keller 

 🔍 All The Posts can be found here, or scroll through the quotes below. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 14:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T14:57:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/24/somewhere-there-were-a-couple.html</link>
      <description> Somewhere there were a couple of complaints about the back arrow (top left) in the iOS app needing adjustment. @manton mentioned he had made changes which may have caused the problem. Adding myself to the ‘can we fix it please list’ .. particularly bad on the  iPad mini. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 14:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T14:54:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in OpenID Connect and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/24/use-client-assertions-in-openid-connect-and-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>Client assertions is a method of client authentication which can be used in OpenID Connect. This provides an alternative to client secrets. This approach enhances security by using signed tokens (JWTs) to authenticate clients during the token request process or the OAuth PAR request. In ASP.NET Core, client assertions is not supported per default, a […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T06:43:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Felt Impossible Became Possible</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/what-felt-impossible-became-possible</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Dan Sinker]  This story doesn't feel like it's going to end up inspiring, but bear with it:   &quot;George Dale printed their names in his newspaper, part of his unrelenting, unceasing, and unflinching attack on the Muncie Klan.  [...] When he wrote an editorial accusing circuit court judge Clarence Dearth of being a Klansman and stacking his juries with Klansmen, that judge sent D</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 02:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T02:46:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the Lid on Government Meetings</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/23/lifting-the-lid/</link>
      <description>Twenty-sixth in the News Commons series. On the left is Tom Evslin, former CTO for Vermont. On the right is the golden dome atop Vermont’s capitol building. Underneath that dome, and in countless spaces in government bodies everywhere are meetings recorded in video. Reviewing or reporting on those meetings is a chore. Unless that is, […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 02:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T02:29:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is no longer safe to move our governments and societies to US clouds</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/it-is-no-longer-safe-to-move-our-governments-and</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Bert Hubert]  A European point of view:   &quot;We now have the bizarre situation that anyone with any sense can see that America is no longer a reliable partner, and that the entire US business world bows to Trump’s dictatorial will, but we STILL are doing everything we can to transfer entire governments and most of our own businesses to their clouds.  Not only is it scary to have</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 22:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T22:47:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/finally-cracked-the-big-yellow.html</link>
      <description> Finally cracked the big yellow header at the top of my blog that ‘randomly appeared’ about a month ago. Turns out that uninstalling the ‘holiday lights’ wasn’t sufficient - I needed to also delete row after row of ‘invisible bullets’. #Fixed. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 21:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T21:47:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/blog-challenge-music-edition-thank.html</link>
      <description> 🎵 🖇️ Blog Challenge - Music Edition - thank you for the inspiration @Annie 
 🚧 Links To Posts by Others 
 @Annie - Annie’s Post 
 @kaa 
 @hutaffe 
 @endonend - Jason’s Post 
 @gregmoore - Greg’s Post 
 @mb - Michael’s Post 
 @robb </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 20:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T20:51:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/love-the-waterboys-and-today.html</link>
      <description> Love The Waterboys and today discovered these two tracks via The Rockenteurs in a conversation with Mike Scott. 
 🔗🎵 Hopper’s On Top (Genius) by The Waterboys 
 🔗🎵 Andy (A Guy Like You) by The Waterboys 
 If these two are any example of the other 23 tracks - it is going to ROCK. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 18:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T18:35:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AfD</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/afd</link>
      <description> 
 Hint: if a party is heavily supported by people who throw Nazi salutes, it might not be up to much good.  Some voters for new right-wing parties are economically worried, but blame their issues on the influx of immigrants rather than the increasing divides between rich and poor that we're seeing globally. They're looking for right-wing answers to their economic worries - racism like anti-immigra</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 18:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T18:18:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok 3 is highly vulnerable to indirect prompt injection</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/23/grok-3-indirect-prompt-injection/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Grok 3 is highly vulnerable to indirect prompt injection 
xAI's new Grok 3 is currently deployed on Twitter (aka &quot;X&quot;), and apparently uses its ability to search for relevant tweets as part of every response. 
 This is one of the most hostile environments I could imagine with respect to prompt injection attacks! 
 Here, Fabian Stelzer notes that you can post tweets containing both malicious instruc</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 17:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T17:37:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/more-art-more-detail.html</link>
      <description> 📸 
 More Art 

 More Detail 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 17:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T17:11:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/art-the-detail.html</link>
      <description> 📸 
 Art 

 The Detail 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 17:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T17:09:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/shortly-after-takeoff-windmills.html</link>
      <description> 📸 
 Shortly After Takeoff 

 Windmills 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 17:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T17:07:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/02/23/square-bot-and-long-bot.html</link>
      <description> 📸 
 Square Bot 

 … and Long Bot - His Sibling 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 17:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T17:05:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using a Tailscale exit node with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/23/tailscale-exit-node-with-github-actions/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Using a Tailscale exit node with GitHub Actions 
New TIL. I started running a git scraper against doge.gov to track changes made to that website over time. The DOGE site runs behind Cloudflare which was blocking requests from the GitHub Actions IP range, but I figured out how to run a Tailscale exit node on my Apple TV and use that to proxy my shot-scraper requests. 
 The scraper is running in sim</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T02:49:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPIとVerifiable Credentialsに関するイベントをやります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/fapiverifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  3月頭はFintech Weekということもあり、あちこちでFintech系のイベントが開催されますね。そのうちの一つである4F（Future Frontier Fes by FINOLAB）の一コマをいただきAuthlete川崎さんと一緒にFAPIとVerifiable Credentialsの話をします。  こちらのイベントですね。  https://4f-otmcbldg.tokyo/2025-jp/       このうち、3/4の午前中のセッションです。    セッションの詳細と申し込みはこちらからしていただけます。  https://fapi-vc.peatix.com/        &amp;nbsp;私は慶應の鈴木先生と一緒に先日発行したデジタルクレデンシャルの管理要件に関するディスカッションペーパーの中身の話を解説させていただきます。みなさん色々とデジ</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T02:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empires</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/empires</link>
      <description> 
 For the avoidance of doubt:  All empires are bad.  All empires have always been bad.  All empires always will be bad.  The concept of empire is bad.  The prerequisites for empire are bad.  And the people who like empires — any of them — are bad.  Do not have fondness for empires.  Do not have nostalgia for them.  Empires by definition colonize and rule space — physical, figurative, or both — tha</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 21:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-22T21:18:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My LLM codegen workflow atm</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/21/my-llm-codegen-workflow-atm/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> My LLM codegen workflow atm 
Harper Reed describes his workflow for writing code with the assistance of LLMs. 
 This is clearly a very well-thought out process, which has evolved a lot already and continues to change. 
 Harper starts greenfield projects with a brainstorming step, aiming to produce a detailed spec: 
 
 Ask me one question at a time so we can develop a thorough, step-by-step spec fo</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 23:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-21T23:07:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People and Blogs</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/people-and-blogs</link>
      <description> 
 I was privileged to be interviewed for this week’s People and Blogs:   Hi! I’m Ben Werdmuller. I was born in the Netherlands, grew up and spent my twenties in the UK, and spent twelve years in the San Francisco Bay Area. Now I live in Greater Philadelphia in a creaky old house with my partner, our two year old son, and my father. At night the pipes clang and we sometimes wonder if they’re haunte</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 22:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-21T22:28:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Banned Abortion. Then Sepsis Rates Soared.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/texas-banned-abortion-then-sepsis-rates-soared</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Lizzie Presser, Andrea Suozzo, Sophie Chou and Kavitha Surana at ProPublica]  My colleagues at ProPublica conducted a first-of-its-kind data analysis on health outcomes after Texas banned abortion in 2021.  Here's what it found:   &quot;The rate of sepsis shot up more than 50% for women hospitalized when they lost their pregnancies in the second trimester, ProPublica found.  The ne</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 21:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-21T21:39:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Joanna Bryson</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/20/joanna-bryson/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  There are contexts in which it is immoral to use generative AI. For example, if you are a judge responsible for grounding a decision in law, you cannot rest that on an approximation of previous cases unknown to you. You want an AI system that helps you retrieve specific, well-documented cases, not one that confabulates fictional cases. You need to ensure you procure the right kind of AI for a tas</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 13:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-20T13:14:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Visit To Tulsa With Microtuble Symbolic Communication + Thoughts on DOGE Against A UPenn “Quaker Kabbalah” Backdrop</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/19/a-visit-to-tulsa-with-microtuble-symbolic-communication-thoughts-on-doge-against-a-upenn-quaker-kabbalah-backdrop/</link>
      <description>Posting this late, so I won’t be writing an introduction. As is the case for me lately, the offering is a somewhat rambling discussion that surfaces quiet a few nuggets for you to chew on.&amp;nbsp; Life in this absurdist improvisational theater might easier if we can practice the Tao of Pooh. Smile. Here’s a link [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 04:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-20T04:55:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using S3 triggers to maintain a list of files in DynamoDB</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/19/s3-triggers/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Using S3 triggers to maintain a list of files in DynamoDB 
I built an experimental prototype this morning of a system for efficiently tracking files that have been added to a large S3 bucket by maintaining a parallel DynamoDB table using S3 triggers and AWS lambda. 
 I got 80% of the way there with this single prompt (complete with typos) to my custom Claude Project: 
 
 Python CLI app using boto3</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 22:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T22:07:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer productivity with Dr. Nicole Forsgren (creator of DORA, co-creator of SPACE)</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/developer-productivity-with-dr-nicole</link>
      <description>Nicole is one of the foremost experts in developer productivity, and author of the book Accelerate. She details how to think about, measure &amp;amp; improve developer productivity</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T17:01:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ai Pin Consumers FAQ</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/19/ai-pin/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Can I still use my Ai Pin for offline features? 
 Yes. After February 28, 2025, Ai Pin will still allow for offline features like battery level, etc., but will not include any function that requires cloud connectivity like voice interactions, AI responses, and .Center access.  
 — Ai Pin Consumers FAQ, on their shutdown after sale to HP 

     Tags: ai </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T15:34:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signing Off from Uniken: Thank You for the Adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/signing-off-from-uniken-thank-you-for-the-adventure.html</link>
      <description>It’s the end of an era: after eight incredible years, it felt like the right time to close the chapter on my story at Uniken. When I joined as CTO, Uniken was an ambitious startup with a unique core technology and a vision to make a global impact. What made the ensuing journey so rewarding […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T15:11:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 25 years of Interconnected</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/reflections-on-25-years-of-interconnected</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Matt Webb]  I love this:   &quot;Slowly, slowly, the web was taken over by platforms. Your feeling of success is based on your platform’s algorithm, which may not have your interests at heart. Feeding your words to a platform is a vote for its values, whether you like it or not. And they roach-motel you by owning your audience, making you feel that it’s a good trade because you get</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T14:18:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Matt Webb</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/19/matt-webb/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Meanwhile blogging has become small-p political again. 
 Slowly, slowly, the web was taken over by platforms. Your feeling of success is based on your platform’s algorithm, which may not have your interests at heart. Feeding your words to a platform is a vote for its values, whether you like it or not. And they roach-motel you by owning your audience, making you feel that it’s a good trade becaus</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 13:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T13:50:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Needs a Working-Class Media</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/america-needs-a-working-classmedia</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Alissa Quart in Columbia Journalism Review]  This article cuts right to the core of why media is failing to connect with mass audiences in America. It doesn't report from a perspective that they can identify with - largely because it doesn't hire people like them.   What would working-class media look like?   &quot;It would be one where economic reporters are embedded in blue-colla</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 13:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T13:03:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>files-to-prompt 0.6</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/19/files-to-prompt/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> files-to-prompt 0.6 
New release of my CLI tool for turning a whole directory of code into a single prompt ready to pipe or paste into an LLM. 
 Here are the full release notes: 
 
   New -m/--markdown option for outputting results as Markdown with each file in a fenced code block. #42 
 Support for reading a list of files from standard input. Thanks, Ankit Shankar. #44 
  Here's how to process ju</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T06:12:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tc39/proposal-regex-escaping</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/18/tc39proposal-regex-escaping/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> tc39/proposal-regex-escaping 
I just heard from Kris Kowal that this proposal for ECMAScript has been approved for ECMA TC-39: 
 
 Almost 20 years later, @simon’s RegExp.escape idea comes to fruition. This reached “Stage 4” at ECMA TC-39 just now, which formalizes that multiple browsers have shipped the feature and it’s in the next revision of the JavaScript specification. 
 
 I'll be honest, I ha</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 21:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-18T21:53:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are We Self-Segregating on Social Media?</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/are-we-self-segregating-on-social-media</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Allison Hantschel in DAME]  Hand-wringing over people leaving overtly unsafe spaces like X to find communities that are actually enjoyable to hang out in (like Mastodon and BlueSky) is absolute nonsense.   &quot;With that user growth, mostly from liberals disgusted with Musk’s nonstop promotion of conservative disinformation, came criticism that people were merely seeking out an id</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 17:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-18T17:59:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrej Karpathy's initial impressions of Grok 3</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/18/andrej-karpathy-grok-3/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Andrej Karpathy's initial impressions of Grok 3 
Andrej has the most detailed analysis I've seen so far of xAI's Grok 3 release from last night. He runs through a bunch of interesting test prompts, and concludes: 
 
 As far as a quick vibe check over ~2 hours this morning, Grok 3 + Thinking feels somewhere around the state of the art territory of OpenAI's strongest models (o1-pro, $200/month), and</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-18T16:46:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of the startup and scaleup hiring markets – as seen by recruiters</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/startup-market-in-2025</link>
      <description>More startups and scaleups are hiring engineers and engineering leaders. Advice for tech professionals on how to get noticed by specialist recruitment companies – from two specialist recruiters</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-18T16:45:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Own what’s yours</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/own-whats-yours</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [PJ Onori]  I can't disagree with anything here:   &quot;Web 2.0 seemed like such a great idea in a more innocent time. We’re at a point where it’s only prudent to view third-parties as guilty until proven innocent. Not as some abstract, principled stance, but for our own direct benefit.  Now, more than ever, it’s critical to own your data. Really own it. Like, on your hard drive an</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-18T16:43:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maybe I need re-writer’s block</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/17/maybe-i-need-re-writers-block/</link>
      <description>I’ve never had writer’s block. Give me a writing assignment and I’ll blab something out. It might even be good, or at least good enough. But I don’t write in final draft. Or talk that way. I know people who can do either or both. But I don’t know how they do it, much as […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 23:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T23:57:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Operator: Prompt Injection Exploits &amp; Defenses</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/17/chatgpt-operator-prompt-injection/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> ChatGPT Operator: Prompt Injection Exploits &amp;amp; Defenses 
As expected, Johann Rehberger found some effective indirect prompt injection strategies against OpenAI's new Operator browser automation agent. 
 Operator tends to ask for confirmation before submitting any information in a form. Johann noticed that this protection doesn't apply to forms that send data without an explicit submission actio</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 20:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T20:19:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask a CTO: security vs. productivity; when to adopt technology trends</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/ask-a-cto-security-vs-productivity-when-to-adopt-technology</link>
      <description> 
 Ask a CTO is an irregular column where I answer anonymous questions from a technical leadership perspective. You can ask questions using this form.  I have two answers to two questions this time around:  Security vs. productivity     Where do you draw the line between security and productivity? What are the drawbacks of totally locking down user workstations and onerous password, 2FA, convoluted</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 16:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T16:13:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk’s X blocks links to Signal, the encrypted messaging service</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/elon-musks-x-blocks-links-to-signal-the-encrypted-messaging</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Matt Binder at disruptionist]  Just in case you thought he was still all about free speech:   &quot;Elon Musk’s social media platform, X, is currently banning links to “Signal.me,” a URL used by the encrypted messaging service Signal. The “Signal.me” domain is specifically used by the service so that users can send out a quick link to directly contact them through the messaging app</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 14:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T14:04:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to do about SQLITE_BUSY errors despite setting a timeout</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/17/sqlite-busy/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> What to do about SQLITE_BUSY errors despite setting a timeout 
Bert Hubert takes on the challenge of explaining SQLite's single biggest footgun: in WAL mode you may see SQLITE_BUSY errors even when you have a generous timeout set if a transaction attempts to obtain a write lock after initially running at least one SELECT. The fix is to use BEGIN IMMEDIATE if you know your transaction is going to m</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 07:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T07:04:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 Years of Travel Tips</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/17/50-years-of-travel-tips/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> 50 Years of Travel Tips 
These travel tips from Kevin Kelly are the best kind of advice because they're almost all both surprising but obviously good ideas. 
 The first one instantly appeals to my love for Niche Museums, and helped me realize that traveling with someone who is passionate about something fits the same bill - the joy is in experiencing someone else's passion, no matter what the topi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T06:39:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing a single client sign-in using parameters in Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/17/customizing-a-single-client-sign-in-using-parameters-in-duende-identityserver/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. In the previous post, the UI was customized per […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T06:34:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM 0.22, the annotated release notes</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/17/llm/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I released LLM 0.22 this evening. Here are the annotated release notes: 

 
   model.prompt(..., key=) for API keys 
   chatgpt-4o-latest 
   llm logs -s/--short 
   llm models -q gemini -q exp 
   llm embed-multi --prepend X 
   Everything else 
 

 model.prompt(..., key=) for API keys 
 
 
 Plugins that provide models that use API keys can now subclass the new llm.KeyModel and llm.AsyncKeyModel </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T06:19:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>３月６日 FIN/SUMシンポジウムパネル「デジタル認証、デジタルIDが目指す未来の暮らし、仕事、社会」でモデレータをやります</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6674/</link>
      <description>毎年のことですが、今年もFIN/SUMに出ます。錚々たるパネリストの方々をモデレートさせていただきます。日経主催のFIN/SUMシンポジウムパネルです。 17:40-18:30 パネル デジタル認証、デジタル ID が目指す未来の暮らし、仕事、社会 セッション概要 日時 ３月６日…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Quote Posts to Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/bringing-quote-posts-to-mastodon</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mastodon]  Mastodon doesn't have quote posts, but is finally adding them after years of pressure. It's a harder decision than you might think - which is made clear by this excellent post by the team.  In order to help mitigate potential abuse, the team has imposed three main requirements:   You will be able to choose whether your posts can be quoted at all. 
 You will be notif</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 21:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T21:22:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Software Engineers Horrified as They Can't Easily Find Jobs Anymore</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/silicon-valley-software-engineers-horrified-as-they-cant-easily-find</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Joe Wilkins in Futurism]  The job market in the tech industry has been brutal for a little while now, and doesn't show signs of getting easier.   &quot;Of all the workers devastated by the carnage, former tech workers in Silicon Valley are having a particularly rough go of it.  The region's former software engineers and developers — whose jobs were previously thought to be ironclad</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T17:54:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life in Weeks</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/life-in-weeks</link>
      <description> 
 Inspired by Gina Trapani, Buster Benson, and others, I started to build my own Life in Weeks page from scratch. It looks pretty cool, and it’s interesting to see my life milestones presented on this scale.  But I’m not going to share it with you.  As I was building it, it became clear how much personal information I was sharing — and not just my own, but that of my parents, my sister, my partner</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 16:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T16:36:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An update on searching for trans-friendly employers who sponsor visas</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/an-update-on-searching-for-trans-friendly-employers-who-sponsor-visas</link>
      <description> 
   Last month I asked to hear from trans-friendly employers who sponsor visas, and provided a simple form for interested employers to reach out. In the process, I heard from many individuals: people who were hoping to find new employment in another country, and people who worked for companies that were aligned, who were encouraging their bosses to fill in the form.  A quick reminder before we div</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 16:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T16:08:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizing on decentralized social networks</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/organizing-on-decentralized-social-networks</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Jon Pincus at The Nexus of Privacy]  There's an argument that one reason Elon Musk bought Twitter was to reduce its effectiveness as a platform for progressive organizing. Whether you buy that or not, it's clear that the new set of social networks are fertile ground for new and existing movements to make progress.  The question is: how? Jon is an experienced organizer and is h</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 15:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T15:03:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech continues to be political</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/tech-continues-to-be-political</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Miriam Eric Suzanne]  Every single word of this piece resonated for me, from the underlying discomfort to the realization that AI as it currently manifests reflects a kind of fascist mindset in itself: an enclosure movement of culture and diversity that concentrates power into a handful of vendors.  This is true of me too:   &quot;Based on every conference I’ve attended over the la</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T13:52:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Perplexity Deep Research</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/16/introducing-perplexity-deep-research/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Introducing Perplexity Deep Research 
Perplexity become the third company to release a product with &quot;Deep Research&quot; in the name. 
 
 Google's Gemini Deep Research: Try Deep Research and our new experimental model in Gemini, your AI assistant on  December 11th 2024 
 OpenAI's ChatGPT Deep Research: Introducing deep research - February 2nd 2025 
 
 And now Perplexity Deep Research, announced on Febr</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-16T00:46:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Kevin Samuel</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/15/kevin-samuel/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  [...] if your situation allows it, always try uv first. Then fall back on something else if that doesn’t work out. 
 It is the Pareto solution because it's easier than trying to figure out what you should do and you will rarely regret it. Indeed, the cost of moving to and from it is low, but the value it delivers is quite high.  
 — Kevin Samuel, Bite code! 

     Tags: uv, astral, python </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 20:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-15T20:10:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run LLMs on macOS using llm-mlx and Apple's MLX framework</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Feb/15/llm-mlx/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-mlx is a brand new plugin for my LLM Python Library and CLI utility which builds on top of Apple's excellent MLX array framework library and mlx-lm package. If you're a terminal user or Python developer with a Mac this may be the new easiest way to start exploring local Large Language Models. 
 Running Llama 3.2 3B using llm-mlx 
 If you haven't already got LLM installed you'll need to install</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 19:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-15T19:13:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/multiply-tiny-house-love-story-with-million-backyard-march/</link>
      <description> After a post about a college that’s teaching students how to build their own tiny houses for just $5,000 drew a lot of attention, decided… 
The post Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-14T21:49:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #124: Software engineering job openings at five-year low?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-124</link>
      <description>Data from Indeed shows software developer job openings have seen the biggest decline in five years across the US. What’s the cause, and what’s next? Also: OpenAI responds to DeepSeek, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T17:37:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A streak, at last</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/a-streak-at-last</link>
      <description> 
   It’s a small thing, but I broke my Apple Fitness longest streak this week. That means my consecutive number of days that I’ve hit my fitness goals on my Apple Watch has been longer than it’s ever been.  Here’s why that’s meaningful: my previous longest streak was broken when my mother died, almost four years ago, after a ten-year terminal decline. For part of that time, I thought that my siste</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T15:49:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marshmallow Test and Parenting</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/marshmallow-test-and-parenting</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Sergey Bogdanov]  This is a story about parenting, but also about the importance of considering context inclusively. We've all heard about the Stanford marshmallow experiment, but:   &quot;Kids from wealthier families waited longer than kids from low-income families. Not because they had more self-control, but because their environment made waiting feel safer. If you grow up knowin</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T15:13:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Elon Musk's son in Trump's Oval Office tells us about politics and family</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/what-elon-musks-son-in-trumps-oval-office-tells-us</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Jennifer Gerson at The 19th]  Musk has been seen with his child, X Æ A-Xii (or &quot;Lil X&quot; for short), at press conferences. But, as Jennifer Gerson notes here, it's not just a photo op.   &quot;Musk, a father of 12, is an avowed pronatalist, or someone who believes declining population rates are a major concern and has committed to work to remedy this by having as many children as pos</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T14:35:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2月27日【緊急対談】ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 – AIメタバース時代のアイデンティティ【Digital Space Conference 2025】</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6669/</link>
      <description>2月27日、Digital Space Conference 2025 のサイドイベントで、昨年「今年最も輝いたVTuberベスト10 【MoguLive VTuber Award 2024】で、儒烏風亭らでんさんと同率４位に選出されたバーチャル美少女ねむさんと緊急対談を行います…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T06:30:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live streaming at world-record scale with Ashutosh Agrawal</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/live-streaming-at-world-record-scale</link>
      <description>In May 2023, a live streaming world record was set with 32 million concurrent viewers watching the finale of the Indian Premier League cricket finale. A chat with the architect behind this system</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T19:00:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s still adtech</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/12/its-still-adtech/</link>
      <description>This morning Wired published This Ad-Tech Company Is Powering Surveillance of US Military Personnel. It’s a good piece, which is typical of&amp;nbsp;Wired lately. But what caught my eye was “Ad-Tech” in the headline. Some writers say “ad tech.” Others say “adtech” or “AdTech.” I’m highly leveraged in “adtech,” since I’ve now posted 160 pieces (including […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T14:27:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Buy This</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/12/dont-buy-this/</link>
      <description>Every so often a product shows up that is so bad somebody needs to sound a warning. So I’m sounding one for the&amp;nbsp;Ion Retro Glow. For the last month or so, it’s been on display and selling at the Sams Club here in Bloomington, Indiana. That’s where I shot the photo above. At first I […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T14:00:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Components</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/02/12/web-components/</link>
      <description>The JavaScript industrial complex won’t crumble anytime soon. But the stage is set for a return to an ecosystem of reusable components accessible to business developers, only this time based on the universal web platform and its core standards. How To Build Web Components Using ChatGPT LLM series at The New Stack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T12:43:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Web Foundation announces its membership in the World Wide Web Consortium</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-social-web-foundation-announces-its-membership-in-the-world</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Social Web Foundation]  The Social Web Foundation has joined the W3C:   &quot;SWF joins CDT as one of the few civil society organizations that comprise the Consortium. SWF’s membership in the W3C underscores our commitment to promoting an open and federated social web, and our alignment with the W3C mission to develop web standards through community consensus that ensures the long-</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 22:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T22:42:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr to join the fediverse after WordPress migration completes</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/tumblr-to-join-the-fediverse-after-wordpress-migration-completes</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Sarah Perez at TechCrunch]  This was a very nice surprise to see:   &quot;Automattic confirmed to TechCrunch that when the migration is complete, every Tumblr user will be able to federate their blog via ActivityPub, just as every WordPress.com user can today.&quot;   ActivityPub is the open protocol behind Mastodon and Pixelfed, among others. Threads and Ghost have also been steadily a</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T20:49:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business Case for Dynamic Authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/the-business-case-for-dynamic-authorization</link>
      <description>Authorization isn't just about security.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T18:31:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Science</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/02/11/bitcoin-science/</link>
      <description>  

 Bitcoin failed.  J.P. Koning notes in The end of El Salvador’s bitcoin payments experiment: 

  But here was a government that was going to champion the stuff, nullifying all of the headwinds against bitcoin in one stroke! The government meddling hypothesis would be put to test.

The Salvadoran government used a combination of sticks and carrots to kick-start adoption. First, let's list the ca</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T17:28:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Big Tech becoming more cutthroat?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/is-big-tech-becoming-more-cutthroat</link>
      <description>Is it the end of a golden age of Big Tech, when jobs at leading companies offered high-impact work, top compensation, and good work-life balance? More signs suggest harsh perf management is the norm</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 16:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T16:54:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Regrets and Their Absence</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/10/on-regrets-and-their-absence/</link>
      <description>Somebody just gave the 31st upvote to my answer to the Quora question “What do you regret as you get older?” So I thought it might be worth repeating. Here’s a short list: Not learning at least one other language. Not learning a musical instrument (or to sing) well enough to play in a group. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 17:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T17:06:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2月26日 PwC Digital Identity Forum 2025に出演します〜「オープンファイナンスの未来とデジタルアイデンティティの重要性」</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6664/</link>
      <description>2月26日、FIN/SUM 2025の皮切りになる「PwC Digital Identity Forum 2025」に出演します。 開催日時 2025年2月26日（水）15:00～19:00（受付開始14:45） 申し込み締め切り 2025年2月25日（火）12:00 場所 東京…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 09:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T09:51:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated OAuth Token Exchange access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/10/asp-net-core-delegated-oauth-token-exchange-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated OAuth 2.0 Token Exchange RFC 8693 flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. It looks at how the OAuth Token Exchange can be implemented and how an application can request delegated access tokens on behalf of a user and another application, providing […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 06:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T06:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fire and Rain</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/09/fire-and-rain/</link>
      <description>Twenty-fifth in the News Commons series Southern California has two seasons: Fire and Rain. Rain didn’t begin this year until a few days after Fire ended apocalyptically, incinerating much of Altadena and Pacific Palisades. Now Rain is here, with the occasional atmospheric river flowing across the faces of hills and mountains whose beards were just […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 23:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-09T23:01:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal For A Spring Break From Mind Viruses – March 13 to the Summer Solstice: Ground, Gather Energy, Reflect, Renew 5 Years Later</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/07/proposal-for-a-spring-break-from-mind-viruses-march-13-to-the-summer-solstice-ground-gather-energy-reflect-renew-5-years-later/</link>
      <description>I made a video today reflecting on how we manage (or don’t) our energy and how our engagement with digital information complicates our lives. I’m proposing that people consider dialing back their social media consumption to spend time reflecting on their thinking, what we have learned over the past five years, and how we can [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 02:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-08T02:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>個人情報保護委員会、「本人関与に係る規律の在り方」の部分について具体的な制度設計の方向性提示</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6660/</link>
      <description>2月5日の個人情報保護委員会において、1月22日資料で事務局ヒアリング結果を踏まえ特に新たに追加した部分の多い「本人関与に係る規律の在り方」の部分(同意規制の在り方、漏えい発生時の本人通知の在り方、子供の個人情報)について具体的な制度設計の方向性を示されました。 https://…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 06:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-07T06:58:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #123: Big Tech using its distribution advantage to win in AI?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-123</link>
      <description>Big Tech companies seem to have learned the lesson on how they became dominant in the past. So most of them are giving away AI functionality for free – even if this could be at loss for them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 17:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-06T17:15:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Makes an AI personal?</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/06/what-makes-an-ai-personal/</link>
      <description>The unintended risks of handing over our lives to Personal AI is the headline of the opening segment of Jamie Smith‘s newsletter today. In it he shares a post by Liz Gerber about an autonomous choice made by the AI in her self-parking car: Last night, my car automatically parked in the grocery store parking […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 12:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-06T12:27:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>そういえばEUDIW Architecture Reference Framework 1.5.0が出てますね</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/eudiw-architecture-reference-framework.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    そういえば2月4日にEUDIW ARFの1.5.0が出てますね。  https://eu-digital-identity-wallet.github.io/eudi-doc-architecture-and-reference-framework/latest/architecture-and-reference-framework-main/           GithubのCHANGELOGを見ると     The ARF is aligned with the adopted Implementing Acts, covering articles 5a and 5c of the eIDAS Regulation.&amp;nbsp;  The ARF also includes changes in response to comments provid</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T23:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Engineering with Chip Huyen</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/ai-engineering-with-chip-huyen</link>
      <description>On today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by Chip Huyen, a computer scientist, author of the freshly published O’Reilly book AI Engineering, and an expert in applied machine learning.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 17:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T17:06:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Up On Quantum Realism In Connection With Gordon Pask’s Mechanical Theatricality – Plus A “Diamond Age” Excerpt Read Aloud</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/05/follow-up-on-quantum-realism-in-connection-with-gordon-pasks-mechanical-theatricality-plus-a-diamond-age-excerpt-read-aloud/</link>
      <description>This is a follow up to yesterday’s video reiterating my thoughts about Live Action Role Play with encoded artefacts as an example of extended mind and possible future inter-dimensional information processing system. The talk goes along with two earlier talks Jason and I did on the work of Michael Mateas here. The feature image is [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:37:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/growing-democracy/</link>
      <description>There is a place, little noticed and even less understood by most Canadians, where democracy is growing stronger despite a history of violence and exploitation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:20:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Candidate Recommendation for Controlled Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2612</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group has published a Snapshot Candidate Recommendation of the Controlled Identifiers specification. This follows the five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group in December 2024. Two of these specifications, including Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE, depend upon the Controlled Identifiers spec. The planned update</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 06:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T06:30:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-platform mobile development with Expo</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/expo</link>
      <description>Expo has quietly become one of the most popular tools for cross-platform development. Why is this, and how does Expo work? A deepdive with the Expo engineering team</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T17:33:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halbguter neuer polnischer Vorschlag zur Chatkontrolle wird am Mittwoch diskutiert</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/halbguter-neuer-polnischer-vorschlag-zur-chatkontrolle-wird-am-mittwoch-diskutiert/</link>
      <description> Polen, das derzeit den Vorsitz im EU-Rat innehat, schlägt eine wichtige Änderung des viel kritisierten EU-Vorschlags zur Chatkontrolle vor: Anstatt die generelle Durchsuchung privater Chats anzuordnen soll die Chatkontrolle wie … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T10:52:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hat Tip to United</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/02/03/a-hat-tip-to-united/</link>
      <description>United Airlines details 6 big inflight entertainment updates, including all-new Control Tower map, by Zach Griff in The Points Guy, is thick with welcome news for frequent United fliers, of which my wife and I are two. (So far I have clocked 1,533,214 miles with United, and she has about double that. We are also […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 23:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T23:51:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison Reflects on Joseph Gonzalez’s Theory of Quantum Realism – A Hopeful Participatory Universe Built On Love!</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/03/alison-reflects-on-joseph-gonzalezs-theory-of-quantum-realism-a-hopeful-participatory-universe-built-on-love/</link>
      <description>Below are Joseph Gonzalez’s responses to questions I posed about his theory of quantum realism. You can find out more at his blog bantamjoe.com. I discuss these questions in the video below starting at timestamp 20 minutes. Select links from Bantamjoe.com: The Self-Aware Circle of Consciousness: Here A Holographic Reality Designed By Consciousness, Designed For [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 23:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T23:05:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is About To Come From Inside The House</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/the-call-is-about-to-come-from-inside-the-house.html</link>
      <description>You would have to be living under a rock to have missed all the talk about Agentic AI, and how it is going to revolutionize the way we live and work. AI-powered agents will be anything and everything – from personal shopper to travel concierge, executive assistant to inventory manager, medical diagnostician to customer service […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T21:45:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple client sign-in customizations using Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/03/multiple-client-sign-in-customizations-using-duende-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/duende-multi-tenant Blogs in the series Setup The solution […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 06:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T06:55:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Years of Digital Identity!</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2607</link>
      <description>Kim Cameron first told me what Digital Identity is on February 1, 2005. He said that the Internet was created without an identity layer. He encouraged me “You should come help build it with me.” I’ve been at it ever since! What I wrote about digital identity a decade ago remains as true today: An […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 02:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T02:46:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want you to do these four things right now</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/i-want-you-to-do-these-four-things-right-now-3ea064583460?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Some simple steps to keep yourself safe.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-01T21:04:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>世界のデジタルIDと認証技術のトレンド：1月31日版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/01/6651/</link>
      <description>イギリス: AIによる年齢確認 アメリカ: フィンテックでの企業買収 グローバル: デジタルトラベルクレデンシャル(DTC)の進展 アゼルバイジャン: デジタル開発コンセプト ヨーロッパ: ソーシャルメディアとデジタルIDの連携 デジタルID市場の成長 マレーシア: ブロックチェ…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 07:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-31T07:38:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #122: DeepSeek rocks the tech industry</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-122-deepseek-rocks-the</link>
      <description>Almost unknown Chinese lab releases AI model that’s open, free, and as good as ChatGPT’s best models. Oh, and it’s also cheaper to operate. This has sent shockwaves through the AI sector</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T17:40:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win Stupid Prizes</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/30/win-stupid-prizes/</link>
      <description>

 Deadly D.C. Plane Crash Comes Months After Congress Ignored Warning About Traffic at Reagan Airport 

 As the new administration is playing stupid games, yesterday morning, prior to yesterday’s aviation disaster, professor Thomas Schaller cautioned:
 

 
   An FAA employee I know confirms agency already lacks sufficient air traffic controllers. The so-called “buyouts” and other attacks on federa</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T14:44:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a best-selling game with a tiny team – with Jonas Tyroller</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/thronefall</link>
      <description>In today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by Jonas Tyroller, one of the developers behind Thronefall, a minimalist indie strategy game that blends tower defense and kingdom-building.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 16:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T16:50:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take 1... Solid Pods and Dids</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/take-1-solid-pods-and-dids.html</link>
      <description> My first attempt at building a decentralized app in this day and age will use Solid Pods and DIDs. The goal? A super simple “BooksWeLike” app—a place where I can review books and see what my friends are reading and enjoying.     What makes this app different is how it handles data. Unlike traditional apps where data lives in a centralized database, my app will let users store their own data in Sol</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T00:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking on Google search: Perplexity and Kagi</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/perplexity-and-kagi</link>
      <description>Google’s dominance of web search is being challenged by innovative, fast-moving startups. A deepdive into two promising contenders: Perplexity and Kagi</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 17:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-28T17:35:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get free access to Perplexity Pro and Kagi Ultimate</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/free-kagi-and-perplexity-access</link>
      <description>New perk for paid The Pragmatic Engineer subscribers</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 17:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-27T17:21:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1月28日(火)はPrivacy by Design Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/01/6641/</link>
      <description>Privacy by Design Conferenceとは Privacy by Design Conferenceは、Data Privacy Day (1月28日)頃に開催する国際カンファレンスです。 プライバシーに関わる、文化、法律、テクノロジー、ビジネス、オペレーション…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 07:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-27T07:18:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Works After a Disaster Happens?</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/25/what-works-after-a-disaster-happens/</link>
      <description>When Hurricane Helene hit Western North Carolina, the Swannanoa River rose three storys above its shores, all but erasing the town named after the river, and leaving hundreds homeless. But the challenge for Swannanoa was not just recovery. It was regeneration. For that, Swannanoa’s residents formed new kinds of partnerships and problem solutions that could […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 11:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-25T11:04:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #121: Netflix’s remarkable turnaround</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-121</link>
      <description>In two years, the streaming giant’s valuation increased by 4x. Also: learnings from a managed database service losing customer data, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-23T17:41:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And Now the #HughesFire</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/01/22/and-now-the-hughesfire/</link>
      <description>Twenty-fourth in the News Commons series Eigth on the #LAfires 7:35 am January 23, 2024—It’s morning now. The Hughes Fire is 17% contained but no longer interesting. The Sepulveda Fire broke out last night along the 405 freeway. It stopped at forty acres, and doesn’t matter much now. Here’s the path of one fire helicopter […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-23T00:36:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observability: the present and future, with Charity Majors</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/observability-the-present-and-future</link>
      <description>In today's episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I'm joined by Charity Majors, a well-known observability expert – as well as someone with strong and grounded opinions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T17:51:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust, Least Privilege, and Just-in-Time Access</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/zero-trust-least-privilege-and-just</link>
      <description>Security professionals have long taught that organizations should limit the access individuals have in computer systems to just those privileges necessary to perform their job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T13:55:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s developer tools roots</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/microsofts-developer-tools-roots</link>
      <description>Big Tech and startups, from the inside. Highly relevant for software engineers and managers, useful for those working in tech.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 17:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T17:24:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andreessen and Horowitz’s Debrief On Their Fairshake PAC and Sunny Days Ahead For “Little Tech” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/20/andreessen-and-horowitzs-debrief-on-their-fairshake-pac-and-sunny-days-ahead-for-little-tech-under-trump/</link>
      <description>I took notes on Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz’s post-election discussion of their Fairshake pro-crypto Pac and the coming Trump presidency about two months ago, but set them aside and other topics took precedence. Given the rising craziness in the crypto space around the inauguration, I thought it was a good time to put them [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T03:58:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T07:34:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Dance, Oscillation, And Going “Inside”</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/18/trump-dance-oscillation-and-going-inside/</link>
      <description>In this morning’s video I somehow missed the fact that the inauguration coincides with MLK Day, which is an interesting sync with the “melanin as optical material” lens. I’m going to drop a few links to old blog posts that touch on the YMCA and “out of school time learning” as as well as my [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T17:06:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestalt, Quakers and Carbon Trading – Do You See Faces Or A Vase?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/17/gestalt-quakers-and-carbon-trading-do-you-see-faces-or-a-vase/</link>
      <description>In this video I draw connections between Gestalt theory and organizational development as applied to digital groupthink in the context of Christiana Figueres, a leader in the development of carbon trading, who trained at the Gestalt Institute of Cleveland. As a young woman, she attended Swarthmore College, a Quaker institution. The first wife of her [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T06:06:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #120: What does Salesforce’s software engineering hiring freeze mean?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-120</link>
      <description>Also: how an hour-long GitHub outage is a reminder of the real cost of reliability, what Cloudflare’s recruiting statistics say about the job market, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-16T17:54:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Coding Machine” at Meta with Michael Novati</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-coding-machine-at-meta</link>
      <description>In today’s episode, I’m joined by Michael Novati, Co-founder and CTO of Formation. Michael spent eight years at Meta, where he was recognized as the top code committer company-wide for several years.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T20:46:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T08:18:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Configuration Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/01/14/the-configuration-crisis/</link>
      <description>Perhaps, even though they are not themselves explainable, AIs can help us engineer explainable systems. But I’m not optimistic. It feels like we’re on a path to keep making systems harder for humans to configure, and we keep expanding our reliance on superhuman intelligence to do that for us. The Configuration Crisis and Developer Dependency … Continue reading The Configuration Crisis</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:23:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day An Evangelical Christian Convinced ChatGPT I Was A Hippy, Schwab-Aligned Sociopathic Magician</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/14/the-day-an-evangelical-christian-convinced-chatgpt-i-was-a-hippy-schwab-aligned-sociopathic-magician/</link>
      <description>What will come of large language models when they mirror unsettled psyches defined by religious hero complexes into the cloud? We do ourselves and future generations a profound disservice when we choose not to make time to comprehend and interrogate how emerging technologies and narrative flows are being deployed to steer psychological states individually and [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:00:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-platform mobile development</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/cross-platform-mobile-development</link>
      <description>A deep dive into the most popular frameworks: React Native, Flutter, native-first, and web-based technologies, and how to pick the right approach</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T17:32:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/explaining-verifiable-credentials-and-open-badges-3-0-34ae898b98b2?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Part 2: Issuing&amp;nbsp;Badges  In part one of this series, we discussed how the trust model of Open Badges 3.0 differs from earlier versions. Credentials issued as Open Badges 3.0 are based on the W3C Verifiable Credentials data model which describes how claims made online can be&amp;nbsp;proven.  To explore this trust model, let’s explore the story of Olivia who has been taking classes at a local commu</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T15:28:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is anybody out there?</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/is-anybody-out-there.html</link>
      <description> Is blogging still a thing?  If you’re reading this, please comment or like it so I know.     I am, at heart, still the XDI Guy. My passion for robust, secure, and scalable distributed data management hasn’t waned. Building one of the first XDI implementations (shout-out to Markus Sabadello, who might have built the only other one), I learned a lot about the challenges and opportunities of distribu</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T16:20:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECDSAに対応したゼロ知識証明の論文がGoogleから出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/ecdsagoogle.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  AAMVAのモバイル運転免許証のガイドラインでも触れましたが、mdocやSD-JWTのリンク可能性へ対応するためには今後ゼロ知識証明が大切になります。  年末にGoogleの研究者が  Anonymous credentials from ECDSA  というタイトルでペーパーを出しています。  https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/2010    AIでイラスト生成すると色々とおかしなことになって面白いですねw    アブストラクトの中からポイントを抜粋すると、従来のBBS+では暗号スイートへの対応に関する要件が厳しかったのでレガシーで対応できるようにECDSAでもできるようにしたよ、ということのようですね。   Part of the difficulty arises because schemes in the literature,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T00:23:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an open web that protects us from harm</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/building-an-open-web-that-protects-us-from-harm-40a95da1d82f?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s not enough to be neutral. We must be allies.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T15:58:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI RAG with LlamaIndex, Local Embedding, and Ollama Llama 3.1 8b</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-rag-with-llamaindex-local-embedding-and-ollama-llama-3-1-8b-b0620116a715?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> In this post, I cover using LlamaIndex LlamaParse in auto mode to parse a PDF page containing a table, using a Hugging Face local embedding model, and using local Llama 3.1 8b via Ollama to perform naive Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). That’s a mouthful. I won’t go into how to setup Ollama and Llama 3.1 8b; this post assumes it is&amp;nbsp;running.  First off, you can find the code for this in m</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T14:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gregg Braden Led Me To Share My Thoughts on Quantum Coherence, Collective Computing, and Tokenized Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/10/how-gregg-braden-led-me-to-share-my-thoughts-on-quantum-coherence-collective-computing-and-tokenized-spirituality/</link>
      <description>This is a video I posted yesterday. And a follow up to clarify certain points. Sorry, I guess the youtube AI choose the “hands up” screenshot for the preview image. I do talk a lot with my hands. Here is a link to Joseph Gonzalez’s blog post on emergent information communication systems. Here are two [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T06:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorization Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/authorization-matters</link>
      <description>In 2013, poor authorization practices led to one of the largest data breaches in history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T19:36:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sqitch 1.5.0</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/sqitch-1.5.0/</link>
      <description>Sqitch v1.5.0: out now in all the usual places!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T02:30:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hockey Trivia</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/08/hockey-trivia/</link>
      <description>  

 As I just registered for a new season of beer league hockey starting this weekend, I thought about an episode of C’est comme ça que je t’aime I recently watched which is set in 1974 Sainte-Foy, Quebec City.  Nearly all the 1974 Quebec cultural references are new to me and in this episode, there is an adventure in a hockey arena and you can pause the video in a few places and see signage in the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T16:03:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OYO AI</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/01/oyo-ai.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;With over 1000 AI communities deployed in 2024, the next AI cohort begins..                                   Coding, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence, Entrepreneurial Skill Development, Teacher PD,&amp;nbsp;  With mentor support of all learners, students and teachers. Unlimited learning by design: (own root)&amp;nbsp;  OYO®&amp;nbsp; AI&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;by kidOYO®&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;at OYOclass.com, Educati</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T12:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 books</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/46-books-5f8c47016bb2?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Every book is a portal out of here.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-07T23:29:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-llamaindex-part-1-openai-e96b3efa699a?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI  I have started to experiment with LlamaIndex for use in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) document parsing and indexing. My results were mixed on the simple page provided. This is part 1, where I make a short post on LlamaIndex with OpenAI as the LLM component. I expect part 2 to be LlamaIndex with Ollama and Llama3–8b as the LLM components.  This is a very sho</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T21:15:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Second Candidate Recommendation for Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2603</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group published the Snapshot Second Candidate Recommendation of the Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE specification just before the holidays. This was one of five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group at the same time, including for the Verifiable Credentials Data Model 2.0, which I’m also an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-03T04:57:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should URI::mysql Switch to DBD::MariaDB?</title>
      <link>https://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=11163487</link>
      <description>Should Sqitch and URI::mysql use DBD::MariaDB instead of DBD::mysql? If so,
what are the implications for Sqitch deployment and usage?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T22:47:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New JSONPath Feature: SelectLocated</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/jsonpath-located/</link>
      <description>New in the jsonpath Go package and Playground: “Located” results that pair
selected values with normalized paths to their locations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:43:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wishing All A Resonant New Year – May We Have The Blessings Of New Learnings And Chances To Grow In 2025</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/01/wishing-all-a-resonant-new-year-may-we-have-the-blessings-of-new-learnings-and-chances-to-grow-in-2025/</link>
      <description>We don’t always get to choose what happens during the course of our lives, but we DO get to choose how we incorporate the unexpected into our stories. Here’s to seeing the value of complementary energies that keep this “reality” going even during times when the mixture makes us queasy. May we learn to navigate [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T06:07:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intention Economyその後</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/intention-economy.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    年末にDoc SearlsがIntention Economyについて「The Real Intention Economy」というポストをしています。かなり重要なポストだと思うので読んでおいた方が良さそうです。     https://doc.searls.com/2024/12/30/the-real-intention-economy/     彼の著書は日本語にも翻訳されていますね。  https://amzn.to/3C2PX9n        さて、今回のDocのポストに戻ると、彼がIntention Economyの考え方を発表してからもう直ぐ20年が経とうとしている現在、生成AIの文脈も相まって、Intention Economy自体が脅威となりつつある、という話です。     Intention Economyで検索すると結構ヤバ目の結果が返</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T03:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL/JSON Path Playground Update</title>
      <link>https://theory.github.io/sqljson/</link>
      <description>The Go SQL/JSON Playground has been updated with a fresh design and PostgreSQL
17 compatibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T20:40:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tintin and the fascists</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/tintin-and-the-fascists-90241c93b3c6?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    The boy reporter has a fascist origin. But something new is possible.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T16:46:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for tech, 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/predictions-for-tech-2025-4046a6331cb9?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s going to be a hard year.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T15:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>366/366 !!!</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/366366.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  ついにこの日が来ました。           去年の正月休みに某猫とのチキンレースが始まってしまったので収まりがつかなくなって惰性で描き続けていましたが気がついたら本当に1年経ってしまいました。  ↓某猫のポスト 
  ふじえさん、やっぱりやっとるな！ 毎日記事を書く366チャレンジや！ これ絶対やっとるぞ！ — 👹秋田の猫🐱 (@ritou) January 4, 2024  
    最初のうちは割と実装してみよう！的なポストが多かったのですが、中盤〜後半は忙しくなりすぎたこともあり読んでみようシリーズが大半を占めてしまったのは反省です。  ということで振り返ってみましょう。  1月のポストはこんな感じです。     この頃は結構作ってますね。まぁ、冬休みが暇だったので実装し始めたのがきっかけだったので。  あとは1月はOpenID Summit Tokyo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T23:11:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soll ich der elektronischen Patientenakte widersprechen und wie geht das?</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/soll-ich-der-elektronischen-patientenakte-widersprechen-und-wie-geht-das/</link>
      <description> Wenn du gesetzlich krankenversichert bist, wird deine Krankenkasse bis 15. Januar 2025 eine elektronische Patientenakte für dich einrichten – es sei denn, du widersprichst. Das gilt auch für private Krankenversicherungen, die … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T10:32:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑧</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01040135091.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだまだプライバシーの章が続きます。  4.5.&amp;nbsp;DELETING MDL INFORMATION FROM A DEVICE   An mDL holder must have the capability to delete the mDL holder’s mDL from the mDL holder’s device. Such deletion:      Must delete all mDL information, log information, and any metadata (e.g. settings) that could impart information </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-29T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑦</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_02108542609.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     引き続き4章のプライバシーの部分を読んでいきます。  4.3.&amp;nbsp;PROTECTING DATA   It is up to Issuing Authorities to ensure that all mDL data stored on the mDL holder’s device is adequately protected. As standards in this respect are still under development, each Issuing Authority should take great care to ensure that the design of its</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>世界のデジタルIDと認証技術の最新トレンド：12月28日版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6635/</link>
      <description>Block、分散型デジタルIDのオープンソース技術をDIFに移管 Blockは、子会社であるTBDを閉鎖したことを受けて、分散型デジタルIDのために開発したオープンソースコンポーネントを分散型アイデンティティ財団（DIF）に引き継ぐことを発表しました。 発表によると、DIDメソッ…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T16:15:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑥</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_28.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        ようやく4章の「PRIVACY AND SECURITY」に入ります。4章も結構長いんですよね。。。ただ、結構重要な章なので細かくみていきたいと思います。     4.1.&amp;nbsp;INTRODUCTION   The privacy of an mDL holder has been paramount in the mDL design process from the start. Care was and is being taken in all the work to ensure that methods and means are available to protect mDL h</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T21:57:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a framework for living well</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/creating-a-framework-for-living-well-4aafe427c74b?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Drawing upa North Star for building my life  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T17:06:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 Foundation: SDO Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/26/web-7-0-foundation-sdo-accreditation/</link>
      <description>The Web 7.0 Foundation is a relatively new organization, incorporated in Canada on May 1, 2023². It focuses on developing specifications and standards for a unified software and hardware ecosystem aimed at building resilient, trusted, and decentralized systems¹³. Source: Conversation … Continue reading →</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T23:05:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑤</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0938402867.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだ３章が続きますが今回で３章は終わりです。     3.6.&amp;nbsp;IACA ROOT CERTIFICATE   In Table B.1 of ISO/IEC 18013-5, on the table row for the “ISSUER” certificate component, replace:     stateOrProvinceName is optional. If this element is present, the element shall also be present in the end-entity certificates and hold the same va</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む④</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01062834414.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        引き続き３章を読んでいきます。  3-3.&amp;nbsp;PORTRAIT IMAGE   The portrait image is the primary means by which an mDL is matched to the person presenting the mDL in an attended transaction. The portrait image therefore needs to be of suitable quality for this purpose. ISO/IEC 18013-5 requires the portrait to comply with Ann</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-25T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む③</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0833807043.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は３章のISO/IEC 18013-5 QUALIFICATIONSです。  3.1. INTRODUCTION   Issuing authorities electing to follow the guidance in this document must adhere to ISO/IEC 18013-5, including as qualified in this document.    本文書のガイダンスに従うことを選択した発行局は、本文書で修飾されている場合を含め、ISO/IEC 18013-5 を遵守しなければならない。   3.2.&amp;nbsp;AAMVA MDL DATA ELEMEN</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-24T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む②</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_24.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は２章のmDL Solution Overviewを見ていきます。   An mDL can be described as leveraging a mobile device to transfer (or cause to be transferred) driver’s license information to an mDL verifier, who cryptographically authenticates the information using the Issuing
Authority’s public key. A visual rendering of a DL on a mo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-23T22:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む①</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日、用語を見たついでにAAMVAが出しているMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいこうと思います。          こちらが原文です。     まずはIntroductionから。   The AAMVA Joint Mobile Driver’s License (mDL) Working Group (WG) has been active around mobile identification since 2012. As the mDL evolves, the mDL WG continues to identify and address topics on which guidance to Issuing Authorities can be helpful. T</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSONTree Module and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/12/jsontree/</link>
      <description>I’m happy to announce the release of the JSONTree Go module and Wasm-powered
in-browser playground.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 21:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T21:33:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Sovereign Identity: Over before it started?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/self-sovereign-identity-over-before-it-started-661b4b0dbdc6?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Web security, symbolized Monty Pythons parrot sketch is an all time classic because it plays on a very human experience of being defenseless when someone is just blatantly refusing to acknowledge the obvious. Shared reality is a matter of perception, not objective observation. Supported also by various mental biases, including the sunk cost fallacy, and the desire to agree with people we perceive a</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T19:13:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID for Verifiable Credentials IssuanceのPublic Review期間が始まりました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/openid-for-verifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日のOpenID for Verifiable Presentationにつづき、いよいよ始まりました。ついにOpenID for Verifiable Credential Issuanceも2nd Implementer's Draftです。        https://openid.net/public-review-period-for-proposed-second-implementers-draft-of-openid-for-verifiable-credential-issuance/  こんなスケジュールです。    Implementer's Draft public review period: Friday, December 20, 2024 to Sunday, February 2, 2025 (45 days)  Imple</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T01:04:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ついに発売へ。デジタルアイデンティティのすべて</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post_21.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    週末に家に帰ったら先行して届いていました。12月27日に発売になる「デジタルアイデンティティのすべて」です。  原著と比べると少しだけ大きいですね。        こちらから予約注文できますのでどうぞ。  https://amzn.to/3P9KS2e        ついでにSoftware Designの最新号も届いていましたし、年末年始はアイデンティティとパスキーざんまいですね！        1月末には「パスキーのすべて」も発売されますので、体（頭）をあっためておきましょう。  https://amzn.to/3ZHQohg    </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-21T09:58:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Water is Death</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/12/20/no-water-is-death/</link>
      <description>

 “Extermination &amp;amp; Acts of Genocide”: Human Rights Watch on Israel Deliberately Depriving Gaza of Water 

 AMY GOODMAN: So, can I ask you, Bill Van Esveld, is this the first time that Human Rights Watch is accusing Israel of genocide in Gaza? 

 BILL VAN ESVELD: This is the first time that we’ve made a finding of genocidal acts in Gaza. It is not an accusation that we level lightly. We have no</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-20T15:06:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Foundatiion の理事選挙(2025)に立候補しました</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6631/</link>
      <description>先程、OpenID Foundatiion の理事選挙(2025)に立候補いたしました。メンバーの各位におかれましては、ぜひ推薦 (second)お願いできればと思います。 選挙のページは https://openid.net/foundation/members/electio…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-20T08:50:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>モバイル運転免許証に関する用語を見ていきます</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    こちらにも書いた通り、11月にAAMVAからMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelineの1.4がでました。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/mobile-drivers-licensemdl.html          読んでいてそういえば一般的じゃない言葉ばっかり使ってるよなぁ、と思うのでまずはTerminologyを見ておきましょう。         そもそも論のAAMVAです。    American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators   の略ですね。米国自動車管理者協会と訳されるようです。この辺の資料によると。&amp;nbsp;     EDL。enhanced driver licenseの略ですね。日本語だと</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-19T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDに関するグローバルの動向</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/id.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    OpenID FoundationのブログでElizabethが各国のデジタルIDに関する最近のトピックスを取り上げていますので紹介したいと思います。もちろん日本も含まれています。  https://openid.net/digital-identity-news-round-up-13-dec-2024/             キプロス   デジタル・シチズンとして知られるモバイル・デジタルIDアプリを開始した。  このアプリでは、バイオメトリクスIDカード、運転免許証、自動車の路上使用適格性証明書などのデジタル文書をモバイルで保持することができる。また、QRコードを使ってデジタル認証することもできる  https://www.biometricupdate.com/202412/cyprus-launches-digital-citizen-mobile</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JIPDEC、トラステッド・サービス登録（電子契約サービス）の登録基準を作成し、公開</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6627/</link>
      <description>わたしも客員研究員を努めさせていただいているJIPDECでは、電子契約サービスの信頼性向上のため、「JIPDECトラステッド・サービス登録（電子契約サービス）」の登録基準を作成し、公開いたしました。 本基準は、電子契約サービスの安全性確保に必要な項目を定めており、安心して電子契約…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T07:59:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPI2.0の最終化に向けたPublic Reviewが始まります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/fapi20public-review.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  FAPI2.0のSecurity Profile and Attacker Modelに関する仕様の最終化に関するPublic Review期間が始まっていますね。  https://openid.net/public-review-for-proposed-final-fapi-2-0-specifications/        今後はこんなスケジュールで進むようです。    Final Specification public review period: Monday, December 9, 2024 to Friday, February 7, 2025 (60 days)  Final Specification vote announcement: Saturday, January 25, 2025  Final Specification e</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T00:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumでの登壇内容を紹介します</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/taiwan-digital-identity-wallet.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先週はTaiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumで登壇してきましたので、キーノートとしてお話した内容をメモしておきたいと思います。  イベントについてはこちら  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/11/taiwan-digital-wallet-international.html          自己紹介は置いておいて、テーマは相互運用性でした。    As you know, the Digital Identity Wallet has recently become an emerging topic in the digital identity space. For example, the European Committee has started im</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph from Wikipedia in Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/building-a-knowledge-graph-from-wikipedia-in-neo4j/</link>
      <description>https://guides.neo4j.com/wiki https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/cats.csv?raw=true https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/rels.csv?raw=true</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T18:06:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Songwriter/Performer Use Case: DID Method Candidates</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/toronto-songwriter-performer-use-case-did-method-candidates/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 10:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T10:02:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>年明けはデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WG：活動報告会から</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/wg.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     年明け1/14はデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WGの活動報告会があります。  https://openid.connpass.com/event/339259/       例の本が年末に販売されることもあり、翻訳を担当したメンバーから苦労話など聞ける良い機会になると思いますのでぜひご来場ください。    </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-15T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>今年もKim Cameronアワードのノミネートが始まっています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/kim-cameron.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  これまで何度かポストした、Kim CameronアワードやVittorio Bertocciアワードですが、今年もKim Cameronアワードのノミネートが始まりました。  https://digitalidadvancement.org/awards-and-grants/kim/2025-kca/           今後のスケジュールはこんな感じなので、我こそは！という方は申請してみてはいかがでしょうか？    December 11: Call for Applications Opens  January 21: Call for Applications Closes  January 31: Awardees Notified  February 7: Awardee Confirmation of Acceptance Due  30 Days</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-14T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth Security Workshopの参加登録が始まっています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/oauth-security-workshop.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日お知らせした通り次回のOAuth Security Workshopはアイスランドで開催です。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/09/oauth-security-workshop.html     ということで参加登録が開始されていますので申し込みましょう！  https://oauth.secworkshop.events/osw2025     なお、11月後半にレイキャビクの近くで火山の噴火があったようです。Danielに聞いたら大丈夫、との話でしたが様子を見つつ参加することになりそうですね。  一応大使館のページをみると12/9に収束した、という宣言は出ていますし。  https://www.is.emb-japan.go.jp/itpr_ja/volcano.html             </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-13T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The open social web is the future of the internet. Here’s why I’m excited.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-open-social-web-is-the-future-of-the-internet-heres-why-i-m-excited-e03e3d96ad3c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It gives you back control.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 03:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-13T03:26:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Googleが公開している「４分でパスキーを理解する」動画が素晴らしい件</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/google.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     昨日はFIDO東京セミナーでしたね。私は台北にいたので参加できませんでしたが・・・  ということで悔しいので #fido でXを追いかけていましたが、えーじさんのパート（だと思う）で触れられていたっぽい「４分でパスキーを理解する」動画が素晴らしくわかりやすいかったのでメモしておこうというポストです。     ざっくりシナリオはこんな感じでした。    長らくパスワードを使ってきたけど、難しいパスワードは覚えられないし、同じパスワードの使い回しが起きるので危ないよね  そんなあなたにGoogleはパスワードマネージャを提供しているよ！  デバイスを跨いで同期されるのでとっても便利！  でも全員がパスワードマネージャに頼っているわけじゃないよね  その前にそもそもパスワードってセキュアじゃないよ  2段階認証はセキュリティ強度を上げるけど面倒だしなぁ  そんな</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-12T20:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIDI HubワシントンD.Cサミットのレポートが出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/sidi-hubdc.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日、東京サミットのレポートが出た、という話を書いた段階ではまだワシントンDCレポートが出ていなかったので順番が逆になっちゃたなぁ、みたいなことを思っていたのですが、ポストを公開した直後にワシントンDCのレポートも公開されました。     他のレポートと同じく、こちらのページからダウンロードできますので、おいおい読んでいこうと思います。  https://sidi-hub.community/summits/    </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-11T23:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSFの相互運用イベントがGartnerサミットと並列で行われています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/ssfgartner.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    今週私は台湾にいるわけですが、USではGartnerサミットが開催されています。  その場でShare Signals Frameworkの相互運用検証に関するイベント（実際に実装を持ち寄って繋いでみる）が行われています。        https://openid.net/oidf-returns-to-gartner-to-showcase-shared-signals-interoperability/     過去にも何度か実施されており、非常に良い結果が出ていますので、今回も色々な実装を繋いだ結果が出てくることを楽しみにしています。  特にSSFのような仕組みは複数の事業者の実装が相互に接続できないと何の意味もないものなので、良い取り組みだと思います。     そういえば、Identity Dance Advent Calendarの中でGoogle</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-10T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024年第4四半期ID関連ニュース総振り返り</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2024/12/6608/</link>
      <description>早いもので2024年も終わりですね。慶応大学の林さんと2024年第4四半期のID関連ニュースの振り返りを行いたいと思います。 日時：12月17日 20:00〜場所：YouTube Live @55id対象とするニュース一覧：https://www.sakimura.org/202…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-10T10:47:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra External ID with an Auth0 OpenID Connect identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/12/09/using-entra-external-id-with-an-auth0-openid-connect-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at implementing an Open ID Connect identity provider in Microsoft Entra External ID. Auth0 is used as the identity provider and an ASP.NET Core application is used to test the authentication. Microsoft Entra External ID federates to Auth0. Client code: https://github.com/damienbod/EntraExternalIdCiam Microsoft Entra External ID supports federation using OpenID Connect and was […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-09T05:39:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrity Properties for Federations</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2597</link>
      <description>I’m writing to highly recommend the article “How to link an application protocol to an OpenID Federation 1.0 trust layer” by Vladimir Dzhuvinov. In it, he defines two kinds of integrity for Federations, and describes how to achieve them: Federation Integrity, which is defined as: This ensures mutual trust between two entities is established always […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 02:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-07T02:08:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using ASP.NET Core with Azure Key Vault</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/12/02/using-asp-net-core-with-azure-key-vault/</link>
      <description>This article looks at setting up an ASP.NET Core application to use Azure Key Vault. When deployed to Azure, it works like in the Azure documentation but when working on development PCs, some changes are required for a smooth developer experience. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/UsingAzureKeyVaultInDevelopment I develop using Visual Studio and manage multiple accounts and test environments. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-02T06:34:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My OKRs for 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/my-okrs-for-2025-aa6e286ef038?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Using Objectives and Key Results to get through a difficult year  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T23:07:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three New Specs Enhancing OpenID Federation and New Contributors</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2592</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect working group recently adopted three new specifications that build upon and provide new capabilities to OpenID Federation. But I’m not only happy about these because of the engineering benefits they bring. I’m particularly happy because they bring new active contributors to the work, specifically Michael Fraser and Łukasz Jaromin, as well as […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 06:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T06:50:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Austin Indieweb at Radio Coffee</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/30/austin-indieweb-at-radio-coffee/</link>
      <description> On Wednesday 12/04 at 7pm, the Austin Indieweb Meetup returns to Radio Coffee and Beer.  Count me in. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 13:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-30T13:19:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 37. Multi-dimensional Overton Olive (MuDOO) as an ADKAR-enabled Change Management Framework (MuDOO-ADKAR)</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/29/model-37-multi-dimensional-overton-olive-mudoo-as-anadkar-enabled-change-management-framework-mudoo-adkar/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Also Checkout:</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T13:21:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 36. Overton Visual Taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/28/model-36-overton-visual-taxonomy/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Model 36. Overton Visual Taxonomy Additional Information:</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T01:18:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 35. Overton Olive Digital Twin (#OvertonOlive #DigitalTwin)</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/27/overton-olive-overtonolive/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Model 35. #OvertonOlive #DigitalTwin (click the diagram to enlarge it) Progressive Improvement through Continuous Transformation For more background on the #OvertonOlive:</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T21:51:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadening the Definition of Identity Practitioner</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2024/11/broadening-the-definition-of-identity-practitioner.html</link>
      <description>One of the wonderful, yet also daunting, aspects of being in the Identity industry is realizing just how far-reaching and all-encompassing its scope and boundaries are. It’s why we need more than just technologists and standards wonks engaged in driving the future of this industry. I’ve been on stage at Identiverse and other conferences for […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T15:49:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RFC: Extension Packaging &amp;amp; Lookup</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/rfc-extension-packaging-lookup/</link>
      <description>A proposal to modify the PostgreSQL core so that all files required for an
extension live in a directory named for the extension, along with a search
path to find extension directories.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-25T19:14:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The social cost of mediated experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/11/24/the-social-cost-of-mediated-experience/</link>
      <description>The first time I heard a critique of mediated experience, the critic was my dad. He was an avid photographer who, during our family’s year in India, when I was a young child, used his 35mm Exacta to capture thousands of photos that became carousels of color slides we viewed for many years thereafter. It … Continue reading The social cost of mediated experience</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 04:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-25T04:25:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Toni Price</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/23/rip-toni-price/</link>
      <description>

 We made a roadtrip one last time to Wimberly to see her perform at the Devil’s Backbone Tavern in August 2023. 

 There was no one like Toni Price. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 16:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-23T16:59:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core BFF using OpenID Connect and Vue.js</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/11/18/asp-net-core-bff-using-openid-connect-and-vue-js/</link>
      <description>This article shows how to implement a secure web application using Vue.js and ASP.NET Core. The web application implements the backend for frontend security architecture (BFF) and deploys both technical stacks as one web application. HTTP only secure cookies are used to persist the session. OpenIddict is used as the identity provider and the token […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-18T07:07:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I want from Mozilla</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/what-i-want-from-mozilla-703cf5ce06fb?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    A people-first, safe, independent web.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 18:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-15T18:49:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye Twitter</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/bye-twitter/</link>
      <description>I finally deleted all my Twitter accounts, notably @theory. If you see that
username, it’s not me.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 23:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-14T23:47:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ein Jahr Absage an die Chatkontrolle</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/ein-jahr-absage-an-die-chatkontrolle/</link>
      <description> Heute vor einem Jahr haben wir im Ausschuss für bürgerliche Freiheiten, Justiz und Inneres (LIBE) des EU-Parlaments eine fraktionsübergreifende Position gegen anlasslose Chatkontrolle beschlossen. Damit haben wir den wahnwitzigen Überwachungsplänen … </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-14T20:02:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 / TDW Decentralized Identifier (DID Method) Clusters Model 0.1: Specification Development Framework</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/11/catergories-of-decentralized-identifiers-dids/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2018-2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode To learn how to join the did-methods DIF Working Group, click https://github.com/decentralized-identity/did-methods. 0. Prime Objective/Directive #Chickens, #Eggs, and #Roosters: A #NorthStar for the Global Decent</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 22:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-11T22:47:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webfinger in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/08/webfinger-in-the-wild/</link>
      <description> Today, a post in my feed included a mention and its webfinger verification threw a WebFinger::BadRequest exception: 

  Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  WebFinger::BadRequest (Bad Request):
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM 
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:79:in `fetch_and_create_mastodon_account'
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:367:in `block in create_status!'
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:36</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-08T15:50:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Identity Workshop XXXIX Report</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/internet-identity-workshop-xxxix</link>
      <description>The 39th edition of the Internet Identity Workshop wrapped up last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-08T14:39:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A hypothesis about the Democrats</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/a-hypothesis-about-the-democrats-8a783f70924a?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>  Have they been culturally outmaneuvered?  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-07T15:04:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indieweb Meetup Austin today</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/06/indieweb-meetup-austin-today/</link>
      <description> After some time off IndieWeb Meetup Austin is back at Mozart’s Coffee tonight at 7pm.  I guess a few things have transpired since the last meeting so I’m looking forward to learning about what’s going on again. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 11:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-06T11:41:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing RFC 9535 Go JSONPath and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/go-jsonpath-playground/</link>
      <description>I’ve made a RFC 9535 JSONPath JSONPath Go package, and compiled it into Wasm to
build an in-browser playground for it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T18:23:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYTimes Tech Guild on Strike</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/nytimes-tech-guild-on-strike/</link>
      <description>My former colleagues in the New York Times Tech Guild have gone on strike in response to a number of unfair labor practice violations and management’s inability to bargain in good faith.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T16:20:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agents Craft Hackathon and Inspiration Block</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/agents-craft-hackathon-and-inspiration-block-88c1481d3043?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> When you want to do a hackathon but am missing the perfect&amp;nbsp;idea. Compliments of Flux.1&amp;nbsp;Schnell You likely know the saying, “Don’t let the perfect be the enemy of the good/done.” Sometimes, I have a hard time living that, and an existing effort is one example. I have registered for an AI agent hackathon, Agents Craft Hackathon. I don’t plan to be competitive but I doubt that is the goal o</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T13:18:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My IETF 121 Agenda</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2024/11/04/7/ietf-121</link>
      <description>Here's where you can find me at IETF 121 in Dublin!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T09:18:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core and Angular BFF using a YARP downstream API protected using certificate authentication</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/11/04/asp-net-core-and-angular-bff-using-a-yarp-downstream-api-protected-using-certificate-authentication/</link>
      <description>This article demonstrates how to implement a downstream API protected by certificate authentication using Microsoft YARP reverse proxy in an ASP.NET Core web application. The application uses Angular for its UI and secures both the UI and the ASP.NET Core backend through a backend-for-frontend security architecture. The downstream API is secured with certificate authentication and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T06:43:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Create Software Diagrams With ChatGPT and Claude</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/11/02/how-to-create-software-diagrams-with-chatgpt-and-claude/</link>
      <description>Earlier efforts to diagram software with LLM assistance weren’t fruitful, but this time around things went really well. I ended up with exactly what I needed to explain the architecture of a browser extension, and along the way I learned a lot about a couple of formats — Mermaid and Graphviz — as well as … Continue reading How To Create Software Diagrams With ChatGPT and Claude</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-02T15:18:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VSCode and Debugging Python in Virtual Environments</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/vscode-and-debugging-python-in-virtual-environments-d975125b455c?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>AI generated image of a&amp;nbsp;beetle This post is really for me more than anyone else. I will be able to come back here and find it. If it helps you as well, then&amp;nbsp;great.  I have historically not been a Python programmer. Additionally, I have historically used Visual Studio versus VSCode. Lately, I have been doing Python in VSCode. I need to learn my way&amp;nbsp;around.  I recently found how to deb</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-01T12:40:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Presentations at October 2024 OpenID Workshop and IIW plus New Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2584</link>
      <description>I gave the following presentation on work in the OpenID Connect working group at the Monday, October 28, 2024 OpenID Workshop at Microsoft: OpenID Connect Working Group Update (PowerPoint) (PDF) I also gave this invited “101” session presentation at the Internet Identity Workshop (IIW) on Tuesday, October 29, 2024: Introduction to OpenID Connect (PowerPoint) (PDF) […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 05:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-30T05:25:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGConf &amp;amp; Extension Ecosystem Summit EU 2024</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/10/pgconf-extension-summit-eu/</link>
      <description>Notes and links from the Extension Ecosystem Summit EU 2024 and my first time
at PGConf EU. Plus thoughts and photos from ancient sites and archeological
museums I visited.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 22:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-29T22:04:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Voting Secure?</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/is-voting-secure</link>
      <description>I'm fairly certain that what I write here won't change the minds that need changing. But I feel like I need to make a statement anyway: your vote is secure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-28T21:41:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrewAI, Simple Enough but It Once Made 100 API Calls Instead of 1</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/crewai-simple-enough-but-it-once-made-100-api-calls-instead-of-1-0e316da4a25c?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>AI generated crew image. Note that some folks are backwards.&amp;nbsp;:-) I continued my experimentation with CrewAI this weekend. To see the code, take a look at the following repo and path: Starter CrewAI Series and the day_04 folder specifically. In the day_04 package, I created a simple custom tool, one that uses Tavily. The two agent, two task package queries for news information on CrewAI and the</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-28T11:46:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earth Data Rescue 2025</title>
      <link>https://cybersocialstructure.org/2024/10/26/earth-data-rescue-2025/</link>
      <description>2016 was a different election: 2024 is so much more important The election of a climate-change denying US president in 2016 gave rise to the potential for administrative policies that would obstruct the public’s use of government-held Earth data. Very soon after taking office, the Trump administration instructed that government websites be scrubbed of climate … Continue reading Earth Data Rescue&amp;nb</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 16:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-26T16:21:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Claude and ChatGPT can see on your screen</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/10/25/what-claude-and-chatgpt-can-see-on-your-screen/</link>
      <description>“If you work with these cloud platforms every day, you have doubtless forgotten that you ever had questions like these. But every newcomer does. And on a continuing basis, we are all newcomers to various aspects of applications and services. In so many ways, the experience boils down to: I am here, what do I … Continue reading What Claude and ChatGPT can see on your screen</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 16:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-25T16:35:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPJ Head Condemns Israel's Deadly War on Journalists</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/10/24/cpj-head-condemns-israels-deadly-war-on-journalists/</link>
      <description>

 Jodie Ginsberg, CPJ’s chief executive officer: 

 
   No journalist from outside Gaza has been allowed in since the start of that war, and that’s highly unusual. I speak to lots of war correspondents who’s covered many, many wars over decades, and all of them talk about how unprecedented this is to not have any access whatsoever. And that, of course, puts additional pressure on these journalists</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 23:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-24T23:14:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LM Studio and CrewAI with Llama</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-lm-studio-and-crewai-with-llama-8f8e712e659b?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> I was recently experimenting with CrewAI, but in one experiment I wanted to use a local LLM hosted by LM Studio. Why LMStudio? Well… because that was the experiment. I wanted to see how I’d use LMStudio to host my model versus Ollama and then use it from CrewAI. Below is a very simple setup for doing&amp;nbsp;this.  It’s good to point out that CrewAI uses LiteLLM under the hood as a sort of proxy. Thi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-21T12:34:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata Specification in RFC Editor Queue</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2582</link>
      <description>I’m pleased to report that the “OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata” specification has been approved by the IESG and is now in the RFC Editor queue. The version approved by the IESG and sent to the RFC Editor is: https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-oauth-resource-metadata-13.html It joins OAuth 2.0 Security Best Current Practice and JWT Response for OAuth Token Introspection, […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-17T19:05:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Greatly Exaggerated Demise of SSI: A Rebuttal to Premature Eulogies</title>
      <link>https://decentralgabe.xyz/the-greatly-exaggerated-demise-of-ssi-a-rebuttal-to-premature-eulogies/</link>
      <description>   💡  This is written in response to a post titled &quot;Why Verifiable Credentials Aren't Widely Adopted &amp;amp; Why Trinsic Pivoted&quot;   A forewarning—there will be no tears here and, please, no hugging. credit, XKCD https://xkcd.com/386/ The post I'm responding to </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 04:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-16T04:32:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Verifiable Credentials Aren’t Widely Adopted &amp; Why Trinsic Pivoted</title>
      <link>https://rileyparkerhughes.medium.com/why-verifiable-credentials-arent-widely-adopted-why-trinsic-pivoted-aee946379e3b?source=rss-bd548551c0bf------2</link>
      <description>A presentation I gave at IIW38, in April&amp;nbsp;2024. At the Internet Identity Workshop 38, I announced my talk with a description something like&amp;nbsp;this:  Five years ago at this conference, Trinsic’s first product (our self-sovereign identity wallet app) was launched. Today, I’m hosting a session called “SSI didn’t work. Trinsic is pivoting.”  I knew it was a provocative title — and I fully consid</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-15T16:49:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI “its got legs”</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-its-got-legs-49f6f3f54aea?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>Compliments of FLUX&amp;nbsp;schnell This last week I spoke with two folks on AI intersection within their work and how their work intersects with one another. One was a CPO for a startup that is bringing AI into their life sciences products in a forefront way. The other was a compliance manager for a pharma company. The second happens to be my wife. For me, their work intersects. They both certainly g</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 14:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-13T14:33:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/social/2024/10/12/77276/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 21:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-12T21:27:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mix Human Expertise With LLM Assistance for Easier Coding</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/10/10/mix-human-expertise-with-llm-assistance-for-easier-coding/</link>
      <description>There are plenty of ways to use LLMs ineffectively. For best results, lean into your own intelligence, experience, and creativity. Delegate the boring and routine stuff to closely supervised assistants whose work you can easily check. Mix Human Expertise With LLM Assistance for Easier Coding Part of the LLM series at The New Stack.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-10T23:37:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNAP: A Conversation of Authorization</title>
      <link>https://justinsecurity.medium.com/gnap-a-conversation-of-authorization-5b603d850fe9?source=rss-ce3fbf1372f2------2</link>
      <description> After five years of standardization work, GNAP is now officially RFC9635! This long and intense process actually started a few years prior to that, when I was talking with a lot of folks in the security industry about some of the shortcomings of OAuth 2.0, and what we could do about them as an industry. These conversations led to the XYZ proposal (and implementations) which eventually led to the f</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 19:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T19:50:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGXN v2 Update</title>
      <link>https://tembo.io/blog/pgxn-v2-update</link>
      <description>A lot has happened in he five months since the last PGXN v2 update. The time
has been used for continuing community discussions, planning, designs, and the
start of implementation. Read on for a full accounting.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 17:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-09T17:14:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch: Postgres ABI and API Guidance</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/06/abi-api-guidance/</link>
      <description>Dear Postgres extension developers: Please review and give feedback on the
proposed patch adding ABI and API guidance to the C language documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-06-27T18:05:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>