<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Identosphere Identity Blogcatcher: Personal</title>
    <link>https://identosphere.com</link>
    <description>Personal blogs of individuals working in decentralized identity.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Sam Altman</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/28/sam-altman/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  the last couple of GPT-4o updates have made the personality too sycophant-y and annoying (even though there are some very good parts of it), and we are working on fixes asap, some today and some this week.  
 — Sam Altman 

     Tags: sam-altman, generative-ai, openai, chatgpt, ai, llms </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 03:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-28T03:24:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New dashboard: alt text for all my images</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/28/dashboard-alt-text/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> New dashboard: alt text for all my images 
I got curious today about how I'd been using alt text for images on my blog, and realized that since I have Django SQL Dashboard running on this site and PostgreSQL is capable of parsing HTML with regular expressions I could probably find out using a SQL query. 
 I pasted my PostgreSQL schema into Claude and gave it a pretty long prompt: 
 
 Give this Pos</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 01:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-28T01:22:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/28/im-very-happy-that-costco.html</link>
      <description> I’m very happy that Costco is finally cracking the beer market - and with Descheutes no less. Just one thing. Elizabeth should have popped into her local Costco to take the snap .. 
 Trolley/Flatbed ✅ Shopping Basket ❌ 
12 Pack ✅ Loose Cans❌ 
12 Pounds of Spring Onions ✅ a couple of stems of same ❌ 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-27T12:00:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/27/you-often-see-leaf-even.html</link>
      <description> You often see 3 leaf … even 4 leaf clovers .. but 5 leaves? Very fancy. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 11:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-27T11:47:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/27/god-help-us-what-on.html</link>
      <description> God help us .. what on earth makes anyone think he’s right .. he’s operating as if this is BAU .. he got the ‘B’ right .. BS .. we need new blood .. and when I say new I mean not OLD. 

 Same conference where we are reminded that the Dems .. that would be the Chuck Brigade .. lost to the orange clown twice .. and the tactics at the top still haven’t  changed. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 11:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-27T11:45:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/27/233526.html</link>
      <description> 💬 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 11:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-27T11:35:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unauthorized Experiment on CMV Involving AI-generated Comments</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/unauthorized-experiment-on-cmv/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Unauthorized Experiment on CMV Involving AI-generated Comments 
r/changemyview is a popular (top 1%) well moderated subreddit with an extremely well developed set of rules designed to encourage productive, meaningful debate between participants. 
 The moderators there just found out that the forum has been the subject of an undisclosed four month long (November 2024 to March 2025) research project</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 22:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T22:34:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Eliot Higgins</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/elliot-higgins/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  We've been seeing if the latest versions of LLMs are any better at geolocating and chronolocating images, and they've improved dramatically since we last tested them in 2023. [...] 
 Before anyone worries about it taking our job, I see it more as the difference between a hand whisk and an electric whisk, just the same job done quicker, and either way you've got to check if your peaks are stiff at</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 20:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T20:40:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calm Down—Your Phone Isn’t Listening to Your Conversations. It’s Just Tracking Everything You Type, Every App You Use, Every Website You Visit, and Everywhere You Go in the Physical World</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/calm-downyour-phone-isnt-listening-to-your-conversations-its-jus/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Calm Down—Your Phone Isn’t Listening to Your Conversations. It’s Just Tracking Everything You Type, Every App You Use, Every Website You Visit, and Everywhere You Go in the Physical World 
Perfect headline on this piece by Jonathan Zeller for McSweeney’s.

     Via limbero on Hacker News 


     Tags: microphone-ads-conspiracy </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 18:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T18:22:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting dynomight</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/dynomight/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  I don’t have a “mission” for this blog, but if I did, it would be to slightly increase the space in which people are calm and respectful and care about getting the facts right. I think we need more of this, and I’m worried that society is devolving into “trench warfare” where facts are just tools to be used when convenient for your political coalition, and everyone assumes everyone is distorting </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 17:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T17:05:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GeoGuessr StreetView meta-game</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/geoguessr/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> My post on o3 guessing locations from photos made it to Hacker News and by far the most interesting comments are from SamPatt, a self-described competitive GeoGuessr player. 
 In a thread about meta-knowledge of the StreetView card uses in different regions: 
 
 The photography matters a great deal - they're categorized into &quot;Generations&quot; of coverage. Gen 2 is low resolution, Gen 3 is pretty good </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T16:56:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watching o3 guess a photo's location is surreal, dystopian and wildly entertaining</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/o3-photo-locations/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Watching OpenAI's new o3 model guess where a photo was taken is one of those moments where decades of science fiction suddenly come to life. It's a cross between the Enhance Button and Omniscient Database TV Tropes. 
 The process is simple. Snap a photograph of somewhere, ideally without putting any obvious landmarks in there. Feed it to ChatGPT o3 or o4-mini (currently only available on the $20/m</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 12:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T12:59:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/26/i-cant-think-of-any.html</link>
      <description> I can’t think of any meaning of the word ‘moot’ that makes any sense. Then again - who knows? 
 The source is a well known center for deep thinking behind military strategy and socio-political thinking. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 04:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T04:11:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/26/did-odd-leave.html</link>
      <description> Did @odd leave? </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 03:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T03:36:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/26/i-just-added-albums-to.html</link>
      <description> I just added 5 albums to my ‘🎵 Neo Progressive’ (don’t you just love pretentious genres) list on AlbumWhale. 
 
 The List of Posts that start on AlbumWhale 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 03:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T03:19:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/26/tara-copp-of-the-associated.html</link>
      <description> 
 Tara Copp of the Associated Press reported that Hegseth directed staffers to install Signal on his desktop computer so he could use Signal in a secure area where his own cell phone was not allowed. The computer was connected to the internet on an unsecured commercial line, making it highly susceptible to hacking. 
 </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 02:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T02:21:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another rant about companies not spying on you through your phone's microphone to serve you ads</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/26/rant/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Last September I posted a series of long ranty comments on Lobste.rs about the latest instance of the immortal conspiracy theory (here it goes again) about apps spying on you through your microphone to serve you targeted ads. 
 On the basis that it's always a great idea to backfill content on your blog, I just extracted my best comments from that thread and turned them into this full post here, ba</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 02:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T02:07:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Public Key Encryption (HPKE) for JOSE incorporating feedback from IETF 122</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2657</link>
      <description>The “Use of Hybrid Public-Key Encryption (HPKE) with JSON Object Signing and Encryption (JOSE)” specification has updated to incorporate feedback from IETF 122 in Bangkok. Per the History entries, the changes were: Use &quot;enc&quot;:&quot;int&quot; for integrated encryption. Described the reasons for excluding authenticated HPKE. Stated that mutually known private information MAY be used as the […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-26T00:27:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I wrote to the address in the GPLv2 license notice and received the GPLv3 license</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/25/i-wrote-to-the-address/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I wrote to the address in the GPLv2 license notice and received the GPLv3 license 
Fun story from Mendhak who noticed that the GPLv2 license used to include this in the footer: 
 
 You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301, USA. 
 
 So they w</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-25T20:40:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backfill your blog</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/25/backfill-your-blog/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Fun fact: there's no rule that says you can't create a new blog today and backfill (and backdate) it with your writing from other platforms or sources, even going back many years. 
 I'd love to see more people do this! 
 (Inspired by this tweet by John F. Wu introducing his new blog. I did this myself when I relaunched this blog back in 2017.) 

     Tags: blogging </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-25T15:30:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $20,000 American-made electric pickup with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-20000-american-made-electric-pickup-with-no-paint-no-stereo</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Tim Stevens at The Verge]  It's rare these days that I see a new product and think, this is really cool, but seriously, this is really cool:   &quot;Meet the Slate Truck, a sub-$20,000 (after federal incentives) electric vehicle that enters production next year. It only seats two yet has a bed big enough to hold a sheet of plywood. It only does 150 miles on a charge, only comes in </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 13:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-25T13:30:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terminations</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/24/terminations/</link>
      <description>Looks like The Terminator took out a bunch of Starlink satellites. (SpaceWeather.com)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 22:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-24T22:09:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Datasette for Newsrooms</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/24/introducing-datasette-for-newsrooms/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Introducing Datasette for Newsrooms 
We're introducing a new product suite today called Datasette for Newsrooms - a bundled collection of Datasette Cloud features built specifically for investigative journalists and data teams. We're describing it as an all-in-one data store, search engine, and collaboration platform designed to make working with data in a newsroom easier, faster, and more transpa</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 21:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-24T21:51:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI: Introducing our latest image generation model in the API</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/24/openai-images-api/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> OpenAI: Introducing our latest image generation model in the API 
The astonishing native image generation capability of GPT-4o - a feature which continues to not have an obvious name - is now available via OpenAI's API. 
 It's quite expensive. OpenAI's estimates are: 
 
 Image outputs cost approximately $0.01 (low), $0.04 (medium), and $0.17 (high) for square images 
 
 Since this is a true multi-</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-24T19:04:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Promptfoo via Dave Guarino's SNAP evals</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/24/exploring-promptfoo/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I used part three (here's parts one and two) of Dave Guarino's series on evaluating how well LLMs can answer questions about SNAP (aka food stamps) as an excuse to explore Promptfoo, an LLM eval tool. 
 SNAP (Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program) is a very high stakes domain to be operating in, but also one where LLM-powered question answering can provide very material value to people who nee</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 18:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-24T18:58:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump ‘Alarmists’ Were Right. We Should Say So.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/trump-alarmists-were-right-we-should-say-so</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Toby Buckle at LiberalCurrents]  This resonates for me too.  About the Tea Party, the direction the Republican Party took during the Obama administration, and then of Trump first riding down the escalator to announce his candidacy:   &quot;If you saw in any of this a threat to liberal democracy writ large, much less one that could actually succeed, you were looked at with the kind </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-24T14:53:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IIW Participants Value Most</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/what-iiw-participants-value-most</link>
      <description>Last week, I posted a report on IIW XL, our fortieth event.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T21:52:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata is now RFC 9728</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2653</link>
      <description>The OAuth 2.0 Protected Resource Metadata specification has been published as RFC 9728! This is certainly the longest that any RFC that I have worked on has taken from initial individual draft to RFC – August 2016 to April 2025 – 8 years and 8 months. As we discussed at the 2025 OAuth Security Workshop […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T21:27:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diane, I wrote a lecture by talking about it</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/23/diane/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Diane, I wrote a lecture by talking about it 
Matt Webb dictates notes on into his Apple Watch while out running (using the new-to-me Whisper Memos app), then runs the transcript through Claude to tidy it up when he gets home. 
 His Claude 3.7 Sonnet prompt for this is: 
 
 you are Diane, my secretary. please take this raw verbal transcript and clean it up. do not add any of your own material. bec</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 19:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T19:58:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A swan won't prevent a hurricane</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/23/meaning-slop/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> In today's example of how Google's AI overviews are the worst form of AI-assisted search (previously, hallucinating Encanto 2), it turns out you can type in any made-up phrase you like and tag &quot;meaning&quot; on the end and Google will provide you with an entirely made-up justification for the phrase. 
 I tried it with &quot;A swan won't prevent a hurricane meaning&quot;, a nonsense phrase I came up with just now</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 19:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T19:56:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/24/ever-wondered-how-fake-news.html</link>
      <description> Ever wondered how fake news took hold? 
 Found Line … 
 
 Re defining meaning after the fact so that the narrative aligns with the outcomes was the modus operandi of corporations long before the political class adopted it as their own. 
 
 Corporate Marketing - where fake news was invented. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 19:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T19:23:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/24/someone-far-wiser-than-i.html</link>
      <description> Someone far wiser than I needs to explain why it’s better for me that Google don’t own Chrome and openAI does. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T17:53:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/24/about-that-trade-war.html</link>
      <description> 💬 About that trade war … 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T17:47:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/24/not-sure-how-far-back.html</link>
      <description> 💬 Not sure how far back this quote goes. But on investment - even today, the unspoken request lurks … when are you moving here? If you happen to live outside the US .. good luck with the visa. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T17:47:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/24/pretty-much-describing-pay-and.html</link>
      <description> 💬 Pretty much describing Pay and Play .. not Purpise or Passion. And the commercially viable part .. isn’t that just a twist on others perceiving value. #Thinking 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T17:41:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llm-fragment-symbex</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/23/llm-fragment-symbex/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-fragment-symbex 
I released a new LLM fragment loader plugin that builds on top of my Symbex project. 
 Symbex is a CLI tool I wrote that can run against a folder full of Python code and output functions, classes, methods or just their docstrings and signatures, using the Python AST module to parse the code. 
 llm-fragments-symbex brings that ability directly to LLM. It lets you do things like</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T14:25:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grumpy morning thoughts</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/grumpy-morning-thoughts</link>
      <description> 
 I earn 5-10X what I did when I lived in the UK, but my quality of life is markedly worse. My whole thing boils down to: how can America have the same standard of living I grew up with?  For a lot of people, the idea of prosperity boils down to, “I can buy what I want,” not, “I can live how I want.” The latter is the one that matters: that’s what freedom actually is.  National healthcare works (o</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 12:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T12:58:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Reddit’s iOS and Android app</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/building-reddits-ios-and-android</link>
      <description>Reddit’s mobile engineers share how they completely rebuilt the iOS and Android app, introducing a new core tech stack, modern architecture, and improved testing strategies at massive scale.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T12:56:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/23/why-is-india-going-to.html</link>
      <description> Why is India going to trust Vance? </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 06:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T06:34:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Gergely Orosz</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/23/gergely-orosz/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Despite being rusty with coding (I don't code every day these days): since starting to use Windsurf / Cursor with the recent increasingly capable models: I am SO back to being as fast in coding as when I was coding every day  &quot;in the zone&quot; [...] 
 When you are driving with a firm grip on the steering wheel - because you know exactly where you are going, and when to steer hard or gently - it is ju</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 02:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T02:43:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trick to feel less like cheating when you use LLMs</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/23/cheating/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> An underestimated challenge in making productive use of LLMs is that it can feel like cheating. 
 One trick I've found that helps is to make sure that I am putting in way more text than the LLM is spitting out . 
 This goes for code: I'll pipe in a previous project for it to modify, or ask it to combine two, or paste in my research notes. 
 It also goes for writing. I hardly ever publish material </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 02:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-23T02:38:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/23/no-pictures-so-no-embarrassment.html</link>
      <description> No pictures - so no embarrassment. 
 One guy on the ladder nailing a bit of wood to a beam. 
 4 guys on ground, who I assume are; 
- the ladder stabiliser 
- design lead - ‘left side needs to go up a bit mate’ 
- health and safety 
- supervisor 
 If they happen to spot this - after you’re done - could you pop across the road and fix the escalator that has been broken for the past ten days? 
 Thank</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 21:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T21:11:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/23/content-slop-end-of-but.html</link>
      <description> 💬 content = slop. END OF. 
 But if you present me an essay, book, article, video, pithy comment, observation, slice of humour .. that broadens my mind, my thinking or entertains me .. I’m all over it. 
 Cannot wait for the filters to arrive. To allow me to train my AI to throw content into the trash. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T19:47:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/23/just-a-reminder.html</link>
      <description> 💬 Just a reminder. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 19:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T19:41:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pasts and Futures</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/22/pasts-and-futures/</link>
      <description>The Airbus 390 is gigantic. Like a cruise ship for the sky. Except, I gather, it’s not real. Pope Francis dies on Easter Monday. For a sense of what Francis embodied and meant, I recommend Jonathan Rauch’s Cross Purposes: Christianity’s Broken Bargain with Democracy.&amp;nbsp; I’m in the midst of listening to Rauch on Russ Roberts’ […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 18:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T18:54:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ellie Huxtable</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/22/ellie-huxtable/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  I was against using AI for programming for a LONG time. It never felt effective. 
 But with the latest models + tools, it finally feels like a real performance boost 
 If you’re still holding out, do yourself a favor: spend a few focused hours actually using it  
 — Ellie Huxtable 

     Tags: ai-assisted-programming, llms, ai, generative-ai </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T17:51:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClickHouse gets lazier (and faster): Introducing lazy materialization</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/22/clickhouse-lazy-materializati/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> ClickHouse gets lazier (and faster): Introducing lazy materialization 
Tom Schreiber describe's the latest optimization in ClickHouse, and in the process explores a whole bunch of interesting characteristics of columnar datastores generally. 
 As I understand it, the new &quot;lazy materialization&quot; feature means that if you run a query like this: 
 select id, big_col1, big_col2
from big_table order by </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T17:05:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abusing DuckDB-WASM by making SQL draw 3D graphics (Sort Of)</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/22/duckdb-wasm-doom/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Abusing DuckDB-WASM by making SQL draw 3D graphics (Sort Of) 
Brilliant hack by Patrick Trainer who got an ASCII-art Doom clone running in the browser using convoluted SQL queries running against the WebAssembly build of DuckDB. Here’s the live demo, and the code on GitHub. 
 

 

 The SQL is so much fun. Here’s a snippet that implements ray tracing as part of a SQL view: 
 CREATE OR REPLACE VIEW </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 16:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T16:29:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than one million readers</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/one-million</link>
      <description>A massive milestone hit, which seemed barely possible when I launched The Pragmatic Engineer Newsletter a little over 3 years ago...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T14:58:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A5</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/22/a5/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> A5 
A5 is a new &quot;global, equal-area, millimeter-accurate geospatial index&quot; by Felix Palmer: 
 
 It is the pentagonal equivalent of other DGGSs, like S2 or H3, but with higher accuracy and lower distortion. 
 
 Effectively it's a way of dividing the entire world into pentagons where each one covers the same physical area (to within a 2% threshold) - like Uber's H3 but a bit weirder and more fun. An</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T14:37:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building our &quot;native-AI newsroom&quot;</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/building-our-native-ai-newsroom</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Henry Blodget]  Henry Blodget, former co-founder of Business Insider, has started a new, &quot;AI-native&quot; newsroom. It's not, in my opinion, a positive use of AI, but it does indicate how some people are thinking about using the technology.  This apparently includes harassing your newly-created virtual employees:   &quot;This might be an inappropriate and unprofessional thing to say. An</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T13:41:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/22/content-the-miracle-worker.html</link>
      <description> 💬 Content - the miracle worker … 
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T11:00:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working Through the Fear of Being Seen</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/22/working-through-the-fear-of-being-seen/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Working Through the Fear of Being Seen 
Heartfelt piece by Ashley Willis about the challenge of overcoming self-doubt in publishing online: 
 
 Part of that is knowing who might read it. A lot of the folks who follow me are smart, opinionated, and not always generous. Some are friends. Some are people I’ve looked up to. And some are just really loud on the internet. I saw someone the other day dra</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 06:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-22T06:40:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/22/dear-kiwis-a-true-story.html</link>
      <description> Dear Kiwis .. a true story 
 🔗 Why These Hawaii Travelers Were Jailed And Deported. 
 Holy mackerel .. German kids on a world adventure, fly from New Zealand to the U.S.A. .. port of entry .. Honolulu … and are arrested, handcuffed, locked up and deported .. the crime seems to be that they hadn’t firm-plans on the specific places they were going to stay, whilst in the U.S.A.. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 19:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T19:58:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI o3 and o4-mini System Card</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/21/openai-o3-and-o4-mini-system-card/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> OpenAI o3 and o4-mini System Card 
I'm surprised to see a combined System Card for o3 and o4-mini in the same document - I'd expect to see these covered separately. 
 The opening paragraph calls out the most interesting new ability of these models (see also my notes here). Tool usage isn't new, but using tools in the chain of thought appears to result in some very significant improvements: 
 
 The</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 19:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T19:13:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decentralizing Schemes</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/21/decentralizing-schemes/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Decentralizing Schemes 
Tim Bray discusses the challenges faced by decentralized Mastodon in that shared URLs to posts don't take into account people accessing Mastodon via their own instances, which breaks replies/likes/shares etc unless you further copy and paste URLs around yourself. 
 Tim proposes that the answer is URIs: a registered fedi://mastodon.cloud/@timbray/109508984818551909 scheme co</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 18:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T18:48:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Inadequate AI Solution</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/21/an-inadequate-ai-solution/</link>
      <description>Let’s take the example of printers, which&amp;nbsp;tend to suck. Here is one example of suckage at work, and the instructive hell it put me through: The Canon MG3600 is my wife’s. It sits by her desk and does a good-enough job. The Epson WF-3520 is mine. It sits by my desk and leaks black ink. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T17:58:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 4: The User POV</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306682918/</link>
      <description>Join our fine panel on Wednesday at Extension Mini Summit #4 to hear all about
“The User POV” — for better and for worse!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T17:26:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Identity Workshop XL Report</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/internet-identity-workshop-xl-report</link>
      <description>This past week, we held the 40th Internet Identity Workshop—a milestone event that brought together a global community of builders, dreamers, and implementers focused on the future of digital identity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T14:10:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI assisted search-based research actually works now</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/21/ai-assisted-search/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> For the past two and a half years the feature I've most wanted from LLMs is the ability to take on search-based research tasks on my behalf. We saw the first glimpses of this back in early 2023, with Perplexity (first launched December 2022, first prompt leak in January 2023) and then the GPT-4 powered Microsoft Bing (which launched/cratered spectacularly in February 2023). Since then a whole bunc</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 12:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T12:57:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/21/i-was-saved-by-god.html</link>
      <description> 
 “I was saved by God to make America great again” 
 
 💬 Tяump 
 Maybe. Then again … 
 
 When fascism comes to America it will be wrapped in the flag and carrying a cross. 
 
 💬 attributed to Sinclair Lewis - but actually unknown' 
 Related ….🔗 A poem from 2011 by Terry Ehret </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 10:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T10:11:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement client assertions for OAuth client credential flows in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/04/21/implement-client-assertions-for-oauth-client-credential-flows-in-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>This blog implements client assertions using an OAuth client credential flow in ASP.NET Core. Client assertions provide a secure way for client authentication without sharing a secret, enhancing the security the OAuth client credentials flow. By using JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) client assertions, this approach ensures strong client identity (application) verification and mitigates risks associated […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 08:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T08:24:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/21/a-public-policy-framework-the.html</link>
      <description> A Public Policy Framework 
  
 🔗 The Thought 
 Another doc prompted by something on LinkedIN - this one around a twenty year old doc called ‘Public Policy Framework for the New Zealand Innovation System’ 
 I was curious as to 
 
 
 how well we had done - not well. 
 
 
 how well we could do - hard - but not impossible 
 
 
 how much the analysis connected to my own experiences and thinking - a lot</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 04:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T04:18:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/21/stop-calling-it-content-the.html</link>
      <description> Stop Calling It Content 
  
 🔗 The Thought 
 Content&amp;nbsp;is a non differentiated, horrible, generic, cheap, replaceable kind of word. 
 Content is stored in silos - with grains and other commodities. 
 Content has minimal&amp;nbsp;value. 
 Get The Full List of The Articles 🖇️🔎 Hand Crafted With Love </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 01:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T01:48:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>📺 Black Mirror ★★★★</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/21/black-mirror.html</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-21T00:30:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/21/the-resistance-protesters-poured-into.html</link>
      <description> The Resistance … 
 
 Protesters poured into the streets of cities and towns across the United States again on Saturday, in the second wave of protests this month. 
 
 Michael Moore: 🔗 PROTEST EVERYWHERE — Saturday, April 19 
 The NYT: 🔗 What’s Happening Is Not Normal. America Needs an Uprising That Is Not Normal. 
 The Guardian: 🔗 Protesters fill the streets in cities across the US to denounce Tru</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 23:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T23:57:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/04/21/good-read-from-jason-fried.html</link>
      <description> Good read from Jason Fried … 
 🔗 Doing what you think, not what you thought 
 Extending the thought as a Haiku 
 Good read from Jason Fried 
Plans fade, but now is clearer 
Decide in the breeze. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 23:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T23:44:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elf — A Social Card Game of Collaboration, Deception, and Suspense</title>
      <link>https://theblockstalk.medium.com/elf-a-social-card-game-of-collaboration-deception-and-suspense-730c107bccf3?source=rss-d8f296833e37------2</link>
      <description> Elf — A Social Card Game of Collaboration, Deception, and&amp;nbsp;Suspense  In 2015, deep in Patagonia, I was taught a unique and little-known card game called by a group of Israeli travelers they called Elf. Since then, while teaching it to friends, family and complete strangers it has captivated the hearts of all players! To this day, it remains undocumented — until&amp;nbsp;now.  Elf is a hybrid of te</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 19:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T19:26:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ethan Mollick</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/20/ethan-mollick/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  In some tasks, AI is unreliable. In others, it is superhuman. You could, of course, say the same thing about calculators, but it is also clear that AI is different. It is already demonstrating general capabilities and performing a wide range of intellectual tasks, including those that it is not specifically trained on. Does that mean that o3 and Gemini 2.5 are AGI? Given the definitional problems</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 16:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T16:35:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Note on 20th April 2025</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/20/janky-license/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Now that Llama has very real competition in open weight models (Gemma 3, latest Mistrals, DeepSeek, Qwen) I think their janky license is becoming much more of a liability for them. It's just limiting enough that it could be the deciding factor for using something else. 

     Tags: meta, open-source, generative-ai, llama, ai, llms, qwen </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 16:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T16:10:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llm-fragments-github 0.2</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Apr/20/llm-fragments-github/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-fragments-github 0.2 
I upgraded my llm-fragments-github plugin to add a new fragment type called issue. It lets you pull the entire content of a GitHub issue thread into your prompt as a concatenated Markdown file.  
 (If you haven't seen fragments before I introduced them in Long context support in LLM 0.24 using fragments and template plugins.) 
 I used it just now to have Gemini 2.5 Pro pr</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 14:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-20T14:01:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The goal of a protest song is to make people feel strong and alive’: Ani DiFranco on Broadway, Fugazi and 30 years of activism</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-goal-of-a-protest-song-is-to-make-people</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Ani DiFranco interviewed by Kate Hutchinson in The Guardian]  Ani DiFranco, the artist I've seen live more than any other, answered my question as part of this Guardian Q&amp;amp;A. It's about a sobering topic, but still, this made me very happy.  Here's what I asked:   &quot;Woody Guthrie wrote “this machine kills fascists” on his guitar as a symbol of the power of words and music to </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 21:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-19T21:43:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOGE Is Building a Master Database to Surveil and Track Immigrants</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/doge-is-building-a-master-database-to-surveil-and-track</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Makena Kelly and Vittoria Elliott at WIRED]  The Holocaust was organized on IBM punch cards. Hitler gave the head of IBM, Watson, a medal for his services; they met in person so that Watson could receive the award. Later, they named their AI tech after him.  Anyway, in unrelated news:   &quot;DOGE is knitting together immigration databases from across DHS and uploading data from ou</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 13:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-19T13:27:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPICEy Developments</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2650</link>
      <description>This week saw several useful developments in the IETF Secure Patterns for Internet CrEdentials (SPICE) working group. Two new drafts were adopted and an individual draft was published also intended for later adoption by the working group. Here’s the tour… GLobal Unique Enterprise (GLUE) Identifiers was adopted. The specification’s abstract is: This specification establishes an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T23:19:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I ran Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/if-i-ran-mastodon</link>
      <description> 
   This is the second part in a three-part series. Part one was about Bluesky. To make sure you get part three, make sure you’re subscribed.  In 2011, I sat on a panel at SXSW Interactive with Blaine Cook, the former Twitter CTO who had demonstrated an decentralized integration with the social media platform Jaiku, and Christian Sandvig, who at the time was the founder of the Center for People an</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 18:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T18:54:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Halts Data Collection on Drug Use, Maternal Mortality, Climate Change, More</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/trump-halts-data-collection-on-drug-use-maternal-mortality-climate</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Alec MacGillis at ProPublica]  The statistics that help us navigate our world are under thread:   &quot;Every year, year after year, workers in agencies that many of us have never heard of have been amassing the statistics that undergird decision-making at all levels of government and inform the judgments of business leaders, school administrators and medical providers nationwide. </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-18T17:54:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #131: why is every company is launching its own coding agent?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-131</link>
      <description>Also: CVE program nearly axed, restored at the 11th hour, Rippling rescinds signed offer the candidate-to-join already handed in their resignation, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 17:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-17T17:03:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Call: “Cosmetic” changes in MLSpin delivering consumer savings?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/last-call-cosmetic-changes-in-mlspin-delivering-consumer-savings/</link>
      <description> The clock is ticking on the Nosalek vs MLSpin lawsuit, one of an estimated 20 against the real estate cartel (aka #RECartel), but arguably the… 
The post Last Call: “Cosmetic” changes in MLSpin delivering consumer savings? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 14:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-17T14:59:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today’s Tabs</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/17/todays-tabs-2/</link>
      <description>Overheard: &quot;AI is bullshit's superpower.&quot; Big topic at IIW last week:&amp;nbsp;What MCP’s Rise Really Shows: A Tale of Two Ecosystems.&amp;nbsp;This may also relate:&amp;nbsp; AI Agents x Law Initiative—A New Stanford and Industry Initiative Launched Yesterday. The best take on Adolescence I've seen so far. HT Dave Winer. My photos from Day One and Day Two […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 13:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-17T13:52:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creator economy businesses - a correction</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/creative-economy-businesses---a-correction</link>
      <description> 
 I realized I misspoke in today’s piece about Bluesky product strategy. In it, I said this:   I’m generally not bullish about creator economy services.   What I meant to say is that I’m generally not bullish about venture-funded creative economy services. It’s the need for venture scale and sky-high valuations that makes these a tough nut to crack. In a vacuum, there’s nothing wrong with these bu</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 23:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T23:03:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fix Postgres strchrnul Compile Error on macOS 15.4</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/fix-postgres-strchrnul/</link>
      <description>A fix for the error: 'strchrnul' is only available on macOS 15.4 or newer
Postgres compile error.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T19:03:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working at Amazon as a software engineer – with Dave Anderson</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/working-at-amazon-as-a-software-engineer</link>
      <description>Dave Anderson, formerly Tech Director at Amazon, shares an inside look at Amazon's engineering culture—from hiring and promotions to team autonomy and extreme frugality.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T17:02:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I ran Bluesky Product</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/if-i-ran-bluesky-product</link>
      <description> 
   A lifetime or two ago, Biz Stone was showing me and my co-founder around South Park in San Francisco. The Twitter office was sat there, a weird building with glass bricks across the road from what would later be the Instagram office. We grabbed a coffee at Caffe Centro and talked social media; two founders talking shop with a member of our advisory board.  He was particularly excited about the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T15:36:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where we're at</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/where-were-at</link>
      <description> 
 A quick aside:  I now believe it’s going to get a lot worse before it gets better (if it gets better). I’m not going to enumerate what’s been going on; you’re either paying attention or you’re not, but we’re less than one hundred days in and the lurch towards real fascism has been notable.  24 years ago, we experienced a lurch towards a surveillance state in the wake of 9/11. George W Bush, thro</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 11:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-16T11:41:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Policy Languages Feel So Hard?</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/why-do-policy-languages-feel-so-hard</link>
      <description>Permit.io just published the results of a survey they conducted with over 200 developers on access control. There's lots of good data there, but one thing that struck me is that over 50% of developers said that they've never used any of the popular policy languages. I was wondering why that could be and came up with a few reasons why policy languages often feel foreign and frustrating:</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-15T16:04:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech hiring: is this an inflection point?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/tech-hiring-inflection-point</link>
      <description>We might be seeing the end of remote interviews as we know them, and a return of in-person interviews, trial weeks and longer trial periods. Could hiring be returning to pre-pandemic norms?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 15:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-15T15:53:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 3 Transcript: Apt Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/mini-summit-three/</link>
      <description>Last week Christoph Berg, who maintains PostgreSQL’s APT packaging system,
gave a very nice talk on that system. Herein lie the transcript and links to
the slides and video.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 22:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T22:48:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes to a diverse community.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/yes-to-a-diverse-community</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Tony Stubblebine on The Medium Blog]  In the midst of some challenging cultural times, Tony Stubblebine and Medium are doing the right thing:   &quot;Over the past several months, I’ve gotten questions from the Medium community asking if we’re planning to change our policies in reaction to recent political pressure against diversity, equity, and inclusion. As some companies dismant</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 21:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T21:48:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differences</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/14/differences-2/</link>
      <description>Peacocks in Pasadena. Well, that’s the alliterative way of putting it. More accurately speaking, they were strutting southbound across Lombardy Road just east of Santa Anita Avenue in San Marino. All errands today here in Pasadena, which is one of my favorite places in SoCal. Or hell, the world. Check out City Hall. Looks like […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T15:31:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating a News Publication Into the Fediverse</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/integrating-a-news-publication-into-the-fediverse</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Sean Tilley]  Sean has been integrating We Distribute with the fediverse for years. It's been hard - particularly at the beginning, which is the plight of the very early adopter. This rundown is incredibly useful for anyone who wants to integrate their own publication with the network, and highlights again how important the work Ghost has been doing really is.  The findings ar</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 14:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T14:46:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CaMeL offers a promising new direction for mitigating prompt injection attacks</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/camel-offers-a-promising-new-direction-for-mitigating-prompt-injection</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Simon Willison]  Prompt injection attacks have been one of the bugbears for modern AI models: it's an unsolved problem that has meant that it can be quite dangerous to expose LLMs to direct user input, among other things. A lot of people have worked on the problem, but progress hasn't been promising.  But as Simon points out, this is changing:   &quot;In the two and a half years th</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T13:52:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU issues US-bound staff with burner phones over spying fears</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/eu-issues-us-bound-staff-with-burner-phones-over-spying-fears</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Andy Bounds in the Financial Times]  The last few months have radically changed the risk assessment for people traveling to the US from abroad - as well as Americans who plan to cross the US border.  In this case, it's European Commission staff:   &quot;The European Commission is issuing burner phones and basic laptops to some US-bound staff to avoid the risk of espionage, a measur</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-14T13:17:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Perugia: journalism, values, and building the web we need</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/notes-from-perugia-journalism-values-and-building-the-web-we</link>
      <description> 
   As I write this, I’m flying home from the&amp;nbsp;International Journalism Festival in Perugia, Italy. Now in its 19th year, it’s an annual meeting of newsrooms, journalists, and news professionals from all over the world.  I wasn’t sure what to expect, but I was blown away by the whole event.  Perugia in itself is a beautiful city: ancient, cobblestoned alleyways weave their way between the old </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 15:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-13T15:48:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Security Administration Is Gutting Regional Staff and Shifting All Public Communications to X</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-social-security-administration-is-gutting-regional-staff-and-shifting</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Zoë Schiffer at WIRED]  The Social Security Administration is changing its communications strategy in a surprising way:   ““We are no longer planning to issue press releases or those dear colleague letters to inform the media and public about programmatic and service changes,” said SSA regional commissioner Linda Kerr-Davis in a meeting with managers earlier this week. “Instea</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 06:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-13T06:19:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who will take care of you in your time of need?</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/04/12/who-will-take-care-of-you-in-your-time-of-need/</link>
      <description>This Fresh Air interview with Hanif Kureishi had me riveted from the beginning, for one reason, and then at the end for a different reason. Kureishi is best known as the author of the 1985 British rom-com My Beautiful Laundrette. During an illness in 2022 he fainted, fell on his face, broke his neck, and … Continue reading Who will take care of you in your time of need?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 16:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-12T16:55:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After leaving Substack, writers are making more money elsewhere</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/after-leaving-substack-writers-are-making-more-money-elsewhere</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Alexander Lee at Digiday]  Substack isn't the best deal in town for independent journalists:   &quot;A year after leaving Substack in early 2024, newsletter writers are making more money peddling their words on other platforms.  [...] Since leaving Substack, some writers’ subscriber counts have plateaued over the past year, while others have risen — but in both cases, creators said</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-11T11:33:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing First Person Digital Trust</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/establishing-first-person-digital</link>
      <description>I've spent the better part of the week thinking about the idea of first-person identity and verifiable relationship credentials after Drummond Reed spoke about them on Monday at VRM day.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T19:16:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #130: Google releases AI-powered IDE</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-130-google-releases-ai</link>
      <description>Also: Git turns 20, a new trend of AI cost saving pressure at developer agencies, John Carmack on how LLMs will impact the industry, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T16:51:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finishing the OpenID Connect EAP ACR Values specification</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2646</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect Extended Authentication Profile (EAP) ACR Values 1.0 specification has started its 60-day review to become an OpenID Final Specification. Recent steps leading up to this were: I added Context Class definitions to the Authentication Context Class Reference Values (“acr” values) defined by the specification, which enabled me to finally register them in […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 01:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-10T01:53:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Presentations at April 2025 OpenID Workshop and IIW</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2644</link>
      <description>As has become traditional, I gave the following presentation at the Monday, April 7, 2025 OpenID Workshop at Google: OpenID Connect Working Group Update (PowerPoint) (PDF) I also gave this invited “101” session presentation at the Internet Identity Workshop (IIW) on Tuesday, April 8, 2025: Introduction to OpenID Connect (PowerPoint) (PDF)</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 22:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T22:42:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fool in White House creating Greater Fool’s Housing Market?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/fool-in-white-house-creating-greater-fools-housing-market/</link>
      <description> Trying to forecast interest rates can make a fool of all of us, but Peter Schiff argues: “If Trump’s secret agenda is to crash the… 
The post Fool in White House creating Greater Fool’s Housing Market? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 17:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T17:13:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Philosophy of Software Design – with John Ousterhout</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-philosophy-of-software-design</link>
      <description>Stanford professor John Ousterhout explains why thoughtful software design matters more than ever as AI tools transform coding practices and developer workflows.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 16:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-09T16:25:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP Protocol: a new AI dev tools building block</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/mcp</link>
      <description>The Model Context Protocol - that extends IDEs’ AI capabilities - is &amp;nbsp;gaining rapid popularity. Why is this, and why should us developers pay attention to it?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T16:27:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denial</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/denial</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Jeremy Keith]  Jeremy Keith highlights the hammering that the public service internet is getting from LLM vendors:   &quot;When we talk about the unfair practices and harm done by training large language models, we usually talk about it in the past tense: how they were trained on other people’s creative work without permission. But this is an ongoing problem that’s just getting wor</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T16:09:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Workshop 速報</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6927/</link>
      <description>本日日本時間午前４時半〜８時、カリフォリニアのGoogleキャンパスでOpenID財団ワークショップが行われました。近々ビデオとスライドも公開される予定ですが、まずは速報です。 Gail Hodges（OpenID財団エグゼクティブディレクター）による概況報告 Gail Hodg…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 06:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T06:58:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/07/days/</link>
      <description>It isn’t how the ball bounces. It’s how you play. There comes a time in high-stakes basketball games when a team melts. That’s what happened to Duke. You could see it in the players’ body language, all through the closing half. They were playing not to lose. Houston was playing to win, with wicked, committed […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 02:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T02:02:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Foundation Workshopクィックレビュー</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/04/openid-foundation-workshop.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    今年もInternet Identity Workshop（IIW）に参加するためにMountainViewに来ています。     今日は前日ということで例年通りOpenID FoundationのWorkshopとDCP Working Groupの対面会議がありました。     ということで書ける範囲でクィックレビューを。（主にOIDF Workshopについて）       今回の会場はGoogleのオフィスでした。いつものことながらチャリが可愛い。乗って帰ろうかと思いました。      ということで中身に。     OIDF Milestones in the last 6 Months: Gail  まずはOpenID FoundationのExecutive DirectorのGailからここ半年のOpenID Foundationのアクティビティ</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-08T01:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/first-person-identity</link>
      <description>I'm sitting in VRM day listening to Drummond Reed talk about his First Person Project.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T23:56:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 3: APT Extension Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306682786/</link>
      <description>Join us at PostgresSQL Extension Mini Summit #3 this week, where PostgreSQL
Debian packaging maintainer Christoph Berg will takes on a tour of APT
extension packaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 18:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T18:33:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What was Quartz?</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/what-was-quartz</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Zach Seward]  I first met Zach Seward when he was running Quartz, the news startup with the quippy haiku notifications that had, at the time, captured a lot of the media world's attention. It was really good. This piece, by Zach, is written on the heels of the last writers having been fired by G/O Media, with the empty husk sold on to another buyer for the email list.   &quot;Still</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T17:58:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Security’s website keeps crashing, as DOGE demands cuts to IT staff</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/social-securitys-website-keeps-crashing-as-doge-demands-cuts-to</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Lisa Rein, Hannah Natanson and Elizabeth Dwoskin at The Washington Post]  More &quot;efficiency&quot; from DOGE:   &quot;Retirees and disabled people are facing chronic website outages and other access problems as they attempt to log in to their online Social Security accounts, even as they are being directed to do more of their business with the agency online.  [...] The problems come as th</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T14:00:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tumblr revival is real—and Gen Z is leading the charge</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-tumblr-revival-is-realand-gen-z-is-leading-the</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Eve Upton-Clark at Fast Company]  I love this. Tumblr is so back:   &quot;Thanks to Gen Z, the site has found new life. As of 2025, Gen Z makes up 50% of Tumblr’s active monthly users and accounts for 60% of new sign-ups, according to data shared with Business Insider’s Amanda Hoover, who recently reported on the platform’s resurgence.  [...] Perhaps Tumblr’s greatest strength is t</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 13:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T13:48:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How X Is Benefiting as Musk Advises Trump</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/how-x-is-benefiting-as-musk-advises-trump</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Kate Conger in The New York Times]  Here's one way Elon Musk is gaining from his involvement in the current administration:   &quot;The positioning of X as a powerful government mouthpiece has helped bolster the platform, even as the company continues to struggle.&quot;   It's worth remembering that xAI just bought X in an all-stock transaction - he's also gaining by pointing his AI eng</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 13:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-07T13:37:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Vinny Afternoon</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/06/sunny-vinny-afternoon/</link>
      <description>I’m here (a short drive south of San Jose) for the afternoon, if any local friends feel like stopping by. Tomorrow it’s VRM Day. Tuesday to Thursday, it’s IIW. See you theres.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 21:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-06T21:13:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hear in Near L.A.</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/06/hear-in-near-l-a/</link>
      <description>Just loving the hang time we got yesterday with Tony after two long flights and one short drive from LAX.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 20:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-06T20:35:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gumroad’s Interestingly Timed “Open-Source” Play</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/gumroads-interestingly-timed-open-source-play</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Ernie Smith at Tedium]  Ernie Smith points out the creator-economy platform Gumroad open sourced its platform at a surprising time:   &quot;But if that’s all Gumroad was doing, I wouldn’t feel compelled to say anything. The reason I’m speaking up is because of this Wired story, released on the very same day Gumroad announced its “open source” license, which may have had the effect </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 19:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-06T19:32:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Who is the best show ever made. Here’s why.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/doctor-who-is-the-best-show-ever-made-heres-why-f2619aed7a46?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    62 years of trying to be nice, always being kind.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 19:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T19:27:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Who is the best show ever made. Here's why.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/doctor-who-is-the-best-show-ever-made-heres-why</link>
      <description> 
   The world is full of darkness. So much is going wrong. Experts agree that America has succumbed to right-wing authoritarianism; call it fascism or something else, these are extraordinarily difficult times.  This post is a break from all of that. At least kind of.  In this piece, I will try and convince you that Doctor Who is the best TV show ever made, explain to you why it matters, and why it</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 19:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T19:27:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDの進化：OpenID4VPの重要な仕様変更</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6912/</link>
      <description>重要なポイント 静かな革命：デジタルIDにおける重要な変更 2025年4月、デジタルID技術の世界で大きな転換点が静かに訪れました。OpenID for Verifiable Presentations（OpenID4VP）の仕様から「Presentation Exchange」…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 10:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T10:25:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Significant Event Without Fanfare</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2638</link>
      <description>A significant event in digital identity occurred without fanfare today. Presentation Exchange was removed from the OpenID for Verifiable Presentations specification. It had once-upon-a-time been the only query language used for verifiable credential presentation. In October 2024, the Digital Credential Query Language (DCQL) was added alongside it. Today, after much discussion by the working group, </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-05T06:54:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fry Day</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/04/fry-day/</link>
      <description>Subscription economy suckage. Just made my annual call to The New Yorker, to get a better subscription deal than what they offer with automatic renewal. So, instead of paying $169.99, I'm getting a new subscriber promotional rate of $99.99. I've been a new subscriber every year since the 1960s. Bonus link from 10 years ago. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 20:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-04T20:32:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's fix OAuth in MCP</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2025/04/03/15/oauth-for-model-context-protocol</link>
      <description>Let's not overthink auth in MCP.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 23:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T23:39:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #129: new trend of EMs quitting to be startup founders using AI</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-129-new-trend-of-ems-quitting</link>
      <description>Also: Trump tariffs to hit tech, Gemini Pro 2.5 might be the best coding model yet, tips on using LLMs to code, and leaked startup recruitment guidelines reveal how much pedigree matters</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 15:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T15:50:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What-Happenedings</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/04/03/what-happenedings/</link>
      <description>Though it may take longer. Usually does. I say some stuff I trust will eventually prove true in Pew's Imagining the Digital Future report on being human ten years from now. Be theres. In&amp;nbsp;The False Intention Economy: How AI Systems Are Replacing Human Will with Modeled Behavior,&amp;nbsp;Katalin Bártfai-Walcott lays out the battlefield between the real […]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 12:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T12:55:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>商業登記電子証明書の手数料引き下げ〜１か月500円からに</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6906/</link>
      <description>この４月１日から、商業登記電子証明書の手数料が改定されました。 有効期間1か月の電子証明書が500円で発行可能に、有効期間3か月～27か月の電子証明書も、最大1,000円の値下げされました。 500円でできるなら、一回申請してみようかなと思います。Windows PCからじゃない…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-03T06:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Live RSS</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/long-live-rss</link>
      <description>Like many, I've grown increasingly disinterested in social media over the last year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T20:00:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy ≠ Freedom (but it should)</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/privacy-freedom/</link>
      <description>The data is in. Privacy is not correlated to Freedom. It is time to rethink how we write privacy laws.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T16:32:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stacked diffs and tooling at Meta with Tomas Reimers</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/stacked-diffs-and-tooling-at-meta</link>
      <description>Tomas Reimers, ex-Meta engineer and Graphite co-founder, shares how Meta’s custom developer tools pioneered practices like stacked diffs and monorepos—shaping industry standards and the future of AI-assisted coding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T16:27:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【4月1日】預貯金口座付番制度等が拡充拡充されました</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6901/</link>
      <description>2025年4月1日から預貯金口座付番制度（口座管理法制度）拡充されました。この制度は、個人の同意を前提として、マイナンバーと金融機関の預貯金口座を紐付けるものであり、主に相続時や災害時における手続きの簡略化を目的としています。 【資料】 主なメリット: 相続時・災害時の手続き簡略…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 02:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-02T02:58:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Postgres Extensions Mini Summit Two</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/04/mini-summit-two/</link>
      <description>A transcript of from the second PostgreSQL Extension Mini Summit,
“Implementing an Extension Search Path”, by Peter Eisentraut.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 19:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T19:32:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reality of Tech Interviews in 2025</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-reality-of-tech-interviews</link>
      <description>Interview processes are changing in a tech market that’s both cooling AND heating up at the same time. A deepdive with Hello Interview founders, Evan King and Stefan Mai</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 16:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T16:33:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>アップル、フランス当局から242億円の罰金を科される〜プライバシー保護の名のもとに市場支配力を強化？</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6895/</link>
      <description>フランス競争当局（FCA）は3月31日、アップルに対して1億5000万ユーロ（約242億円）という高額な罰金を科しました。問題となったのは、2021年から2023年にかけてアップルが導入した「App Tracking Transparency（ATT）」と呼ばれるプライバシー保護…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 11:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T11:30:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【デジタル庁】本人確認ガイドラインの改定に向けた有識者会議（令和6年度）の取りまとめが公表されました</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/04/6889/</link>
      <description>4月1日、デジタル庁から本人確認ガイドラインの改定に向けた有識者会議（令和6年度）の取りまとめが公表されました。「DS-500 行政手続におけるオンラインによる本人確認の手法に関するガイドライン」（通称「本人確認ガイドライン」）は、行政手続きをデジタル化する時に、安全に本人確認す…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 09:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-04-01T09:51:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GビズIDの大幅アップデートとOpenID Connect for Identity Assuranceへの対応</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/03/gidopenid-connect-for-identity-assurance.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    いわゆる法人共通認証基盤と呼ばれる、デジタル庁が提供しているGビズIDの大幅アップデートが公開されましたね。     出典）デジタル庁 - GビズID&amp;nbsp;https://gbiz-id.go.jp/top/         GビズIDについてはこれまでもOpenIDファウンデーションジャパンのイベント等に古くは経産省、デジタル庁へ移管されてからはデジタル庁の方々にお越しいただき技術仕様やトラストフレームワークについてご発表いただいてきました。      OpenID Summit Tokyo 2020 - 2020/1/24  https://www.openid.or.jp/summit/2020/     OpenID BizDay #14 - 2021/1/27  https://openid.connpass.com/event/200742/</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-30T01:37:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #128: Mishandled security vulnerability in Next.js</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-128</link>
      <description>Cloudflare stepped up to deliver a fix for the vulnerability, following unexpected silence from the Next.js team. Also: OpenAI’s new image generation feature shows how Japan has lax copyright laws</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 17:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-27T17:32:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web3 is Reintroducing Cross-Origin Tracking Accidentally</title>
      <link>https://kyledenhartog.com/recreating-web3-cross-origin-tracking/</link>
      <description>We should expect that when the user shares their address that will act as implied consent for cross-origin tracking in the same way cookie notices act as a prompt for tracking.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Figma Slides with Noah Finer and Jonathan Kaufman</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/building-figma-slides-with-noah-finer</link>
      <description>Figma engineers Jonathan Kaufman and Noah Finer share how they built Figma Slides from a hackathon project into a polished product, covering key engineering decisions, challenges, and practices.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 17:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-26T17:05:11+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oktaベンチャーが選ぶThe Identity 25の2025年版に選ばれました。</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6865/</link>
      <description>そう、あのニューヨークのタイムズスクエアにでかでかと顔がでるやつです。（写真１）参照。去年は３月２１日に出ていたようですが、今年はどうなるでしょうね。 日本からは他に、CTCの富士榮さんが入っていますね。あとは、EU DI ARFを作っている Paolo de Rosaとか、SP…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 03:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-26T03:39:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Okta Venturesが選ぶ、今年のアイデンティティ界の25人（The Identity 25）に選ばれました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/03/okta-ventures25the-identity-25.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    どうやらOkta Venturesが2024年から始めた今年のアイデンティティ界の25人（The Identity 25）に選ばれました。        https://www.okta.com/resources/datasheet-the-identity-25/        このプログラム、2024年からスタートしたもののようで、昨年はSPRIN-Dにいる安田クリスチーナやMicrosoftのPam DIngle、YubicoのJohn Bradleyなどが選ばれていました。     今年はOpenID FoundationのExecutive DirectorのGail HodgesやChairの崎村さんらの錚々たるメンバの中に何故か私も加えていただけたようです。     しかし、最初Okta Ventures側から連絡をもらった時はよくある詐欺かと</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T20:18:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Engineering in the real world</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/ai-engineering-in-the-real-world</link>
      <description>What does AI engineering look like in practice? Hands-on examples and learnings from software engineers turned “AI engineers” at seven companies</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T16:57:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated Microsoft OBO access token management (Entra only)</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/25/asp-net-core-delegated-microsoft-obo-access-token-management-entra-only/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated Microsoft On-Behalf-Of flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. The solution uses Microsoft.Identity.Web to implement the different flows and it really simple to implement, when you know how to use the Nuget package and use the correct Microsoft documentation. The application can […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 12:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-25T12:45:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key themes going into IIW XL (40) </title>
      <link>https://identitywoman.net/key-themes-going-into-iiw-xl-40/</link>
      <description> We are heading into the 40th Internet Identity Workshop, an event that I cofounded with Doc Searls and Phil Windley 20 years ago. I am not sure we ever thought it would last this long but it has. We continue to be the world’s leading innovation forum for decentralized digital identity focused on a range […] 
 The post Key themes going into IIW XL (40)&amp;nbsp; appeared first on Identity Woman. </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T23:27:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Summit 2: Extension Search Path Patch</title>
      <link>https://www.meetup.com/postgres-extensions-ecosystem-mini-summits/events/306569342/</link>
      <description>Join us at PostgresSQL Extension Mini Summit #2 this week, where PostgreSQL
committer Peter Eisentraut will discuss the extension search path patch.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T21:14:27+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Postgres Extensions Mini Summit One</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/mini-summit-one/</link>
      <description>A rough transcript of my talk “State of the Extension Ecosystem”.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T20:46:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is proposed MLSpin Settlement the April Fool’s Day joke #RECartel doesn’t want consumers retelling?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/is-proposed-mlspin-settlement-the-april-fools-day-joke-recartel-doesnt-consumers-retelling/</link>
      <description> Homebuyers &amp;amp; sellers, intend to buy or sell this Spring and talking to real estate agents about their fees? Have any mentioned that is just… 
The post Is proposed MLSpin Settlement the April Fool’s Day joke #RECartel doesn’t want consumers retelling? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T17:23:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタル庁とJR西日本、マイナンバーカードを活用した在学証明の実証実験：オンライン学割乗車券購入の実現へ</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6825/</link>
      <description>デジタル学生証明による学割サービスの話は、かなり前から検討されている話題です。わたしの周りでも、遅くとも2012年には Student Identity Trust Framework として国立情報学研究所（NII）との間で検討がなされてきました。 今回発表されたものは、これら…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-24T09:38:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Growth Engineering?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/what-is-growth-engineering</link>
      <description>A deep dive into the field of growth engineering, which is often positioned between product engineering and marketing. With former head of growth engineering at MasterClass, Alexey Komissarouk</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-20T16:53:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcing people back to the office was a choice. I’m making mine.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/forcing-people-back-to-the-office-was-a-choice-im-making-mine-e1e7b8dd0af4?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Here’s why I won’t RTO.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-19T20:32:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Linux is built with Greg Kroah-Hartman</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/how-linux-is-built-with-greg-kroah</link>
      <description>Greg Kroah-Hartman, a longtime Linux kernel maintainer, breaks down the inner workings of Linux development, from its unique trust model to the benefits of open-source contribution.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-19T16:43:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survey: What’s in your tech stack?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/what-is-in-your-tech-stack</link>
      <description>We’d like to share a realistic snapshot of the industry – and need your help. Those filling out the survey will receive a report before anyone else and some additional analysis.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-18T16:30:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Version of FIDO2 Client to Authenticator Protocol (CTAP 2.2) Now a Standard</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2631</link>
      <description>The FIDO Alliance has completed the CTAP 2.2 Specification. The closely-related third version of the W3C Web Authentication (WebAuthn) specification is also nearing final status; this WebAuthn Level 3 working draft is currently going through the review steps to become a W3C Recommendation. So what’s new in the third versions? Changes between CTAP 2.1 and […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-18T07:15:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【告知】3/29「分人経済革命」ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 徹底対談【次世代ネットの扉を開く革命の起こしかた】</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6797/</link>
      <description>LIVE告知です。メタバース進化論の著者のバーチャル美少女ねむさんとYouTube Live を行います。 ・配信日時：3月29日（土）21:00より1.5時間程度予定・YouTube LIVEにて無料配信・配信URL：「分人経済革命」ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 徹底対談【次世代ネットの…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-17T11:23:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognition, Identity, and AI: Building Trust in Digital Agents</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/03/recognition-identity-and-ai-building.html</link>
      <description> My first love was self-sovereign distributed data, where each person owns and controls their data, hosting it wherever they choose and permissioning it under their own terms. But I got lost in the complexity of building a robust distributed identity infrastructure. How can you give permission to someone if you can’t 'name' them in a way that is verifiable and resistant to subversion? There's no po</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T16:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #127: Typescript compiler rewritten in Go</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-127</link>
      <description>Why did Microsoft choose a language developed by Google, instead of its own, C#? Also: OpenAI’s dev tools for agents looking complex, the PR/FAQ for AWS Lambda, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T17:27:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOV.UK WalletとOne Login</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6766/</link>
      <description>GOV.UK Wallet とは GOV.UK Walletは、デジタル運転免許証のコンテキストで1月21日に明らかになったイギリス政府が開発中のデジタル文書管理アプリで、2025年2月5日にはピーター・カイル科学・イノベーション・技術担当国務長官によりその詳細が発表が行われまし…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T19:13:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Experience at Uber with Gautam Korlam</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/developer-experience-at-uber</link>
      <description>Gautam Korlam, former principal engineer at Uber and co-founder of Gitar, joins the podcast to discuss scaling engineering teams, the challenges of monorepos, and how AI is reshaping developer productivity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T15:57:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI fakers exposed in tech dev recruitment: postmortem</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/ai-fakers</link>
      <description>A full-remote security startup nearly hired a backend engineer who doesn’t exist, after a candidate used an AI filter as an on-screen disguise in video interviews. Learnings for tech companies</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T17:54:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Hiatus – Look For Me In The Garden</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/03/11/on-hiatus-look-for-me-in-the-garden/</link>
      <description>Today I realized that even though the Web3 program is ramping up as demonstrated by Silicon Valley’s plans to turn Argentina into a “network state,” few understand what is unfolding with cybernetic governance. For that reason, I decided to take time off this spring to work on my garden and simply be with real people [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T04:32:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms Specification Addressing Area Director Feedback</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2627</link>
      <description>Orie Steele and I want to thank Deb Cooley for her Area Director review of the “Fully-Specified Algorithms for JOSE and COSE” specification. Addressing it simplified the exposition, while preserving the essence of what the draft accomplishes. Specifically, the resulting draft significantly simplified the fully-specified encryption description and removed the appendix on polymorphic ECDH algorithms.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 05:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T05:44:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEDI Details for Identity Nerds</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/sedi-details-for-identity-nerds-e1949af5cc30?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> This post is a more technical follow-up to the post announcing the passing of SB 260 in Utah, establishing the principles for state-endorsed digital identity (SEDI). While SEDI does not mandate any particular technology, its mandated principles close the door for technologies that do not comply, and open the door for technologies that do. This article explores what SEDI makes technically possible,</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T00:15:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utah Blazes New Trail for SSI: SEDI</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/utah-blazes-new-trail-for-ssi-sedi-441d8ce65ab8?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Finally!  On March 4, 2025, the Utah legislature unanimously passed SB 260, a groundbreaking digital identity bill that carries this description:  “This bill enacts provisions related to a state-endorsed digital identity” (SEDI).  Now it’s off to the governor for signature, who has been publicly positive about it. Huge credit to Sen. Cullimore, the bill’s sponsor, and Christopher Bramwell, the sta</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T23:30:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/03/07/making-the-fediverse-more-accessible-with-claude-3-7-sonnet/</link>
      <description>A few years ago I abandoned Twitter in favor of Mastodon. Recent events validate that choice and underscore the strategic importance of a decentralized fediverse that can’t be owned by a single corporate or state actor. But while Mastodon meets my needs, much of the Twitter diaspora has gone to Bluesky. That’s fine for now … Continue reading Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonn</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T17:54:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extension Ecosystem Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/extension-ecosystem-summit/</link>
      <description>We’re doing it again! The PostgreSQL Extension Ecosystem Summit returns to
PGConf.dev. We’ll again be looking at indexing, discovery, packaging, and
core support. And we’ll once again be hosting a series of “Mini Summits”
leading up to the event. Join us!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T00:35:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2621</link>
      <description>Emil Lundberg and I have published the COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing specification. Its abstract is: This specification defines COSE algorithm identifiers used when the signing operation is performed cooperatively between two parties. When performing two-party signing, the first party typically hashes the data to be signed and the second party signs the hashed data […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 02:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-04T02:47:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCC at the 2025 1EdTech Digital Credentials Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/dcc-at-the-2025-1edtech-digital-credentials-summit-e506d7c8051c?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> LCW Experience Badge &amp;amp; Introduction to Open Badges 3.0 Course at Participate  This week is the 2025 Digital Credentials Summit hosted by the organization that shepherds the Open Badges 3.0 standard. This is a great space to meet with implementers, educators, technologists, funders, and policy makers from all over the world to&amp;nbsp;connect.  I will be attending this year and have the privilege </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:13:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Badges 3.0 Basics: Watch, Learn, and Earn on Participate</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/open-badges-3-0-basics-watch-learn-and-earn-on-participate-660c2bf922dd?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Join the Digital Credentials Consortium Learning&amp;nbsp;Hub  The Digital Credential has started a series of short posts explaining the characteristics and trust models of W3C Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0. To accompany this series, we collaborated with our colleagues as Participate to create the The Digital Credentials Consortium Learning Hub and offer a short course, “Introduction to O</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:12:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A future for Self Sovereign Identity?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/a-future-for-self-sovereign-identity-c237caa5e46f?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Symbolic representation of Web Security applied to&amp;nbsp;SSI. Many children in Europe grew up with the tales of Baron Münchhausen, who claims to have lifted himself and his horse out of a mire by pulling his own hair. The image is so powerful because the problem of the circular dependency is so clearly visible. In real life, circular dependencies are often far less&amp;nbsp;obvious.  Which is why the fi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The LCW Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/the-lcw-experience-6a5bef5cca4d?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> The Digital Credentials Consortium, our team and our members, are aiming to advance the understanding &amp;amp; use of privacy-enhanced, portable, verifiable digital credentials like Open Badges 3.0. We’ve noticed that while many are interested in the opportunities LERs as digital credentials may offer, many haven’t yet experienced what it is like to claim and accept an Open Badge 3.0 credential with </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:14:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement Phone verification, 2FA using ASP.NET Core Identity</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/03/implement-phone-verification-2fa-using-asp-net-core-identity/</link>
      <description>This post shows how to implement phone (SMS) verification and two-factor authentication (2FA) using ASP.NET Core Identity. The solution integrates phone-based verification and 2FA mechanisms. The implementation uses ASP.NET Core Identity’s extensibility to incorporate SMS-based verification during user registration and login processes. SMS is no longer a recommended authentication method due to sec</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T06:05:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The web was always about redistribution of power. Let’s bring that back.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-web-was-always-about-redistribution-of-power-lets-bring-that-back-d3d855509f9c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s time to rekindle the movement.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T15:00:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cambrian Explosion of OAuth and OpenID Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2615</link>
      <description>Vladimir Dzhuvinov and I led a discussion on The Cambrian Explosion of OAuth and OpenID Specifications at the 2025 OAuth Security Workshop in Reykjavík. The abstract for the session was: The number of OAuth and OpenID specifications continues to grow. At present there are 30 OAuth RFCs, two more in the RFC Editor queue, 13 […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 12:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T12:42:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Im The Problem, You Might Be The Reason</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/02/if-im-problem-you-might-be-reason.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;Tune your metaphors..&amp;nbsp;             &amp;nbsp;From where I dance and glance in America...   All over the world, men and women are not having the same experience. Generational conflicts are arising, influencing everything, causing chaos to status quo, and making clear that the ability to r/w/rw is not shared equally. Computational supremacy, computational illiteracy, what does the data say? W</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T22:08:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatkontrolle: EU-Bürgerbeauftragte kritisiert Drehtürwechsel von Europol-Beamten zu Chatkontrolle-Lobbyist Thorn</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/chatkontrolle-eu-buergerbeauftragte-kritisiert-drehtuerwechsel-von-europol-beamten-zu-chatkontrolle-lobbyist-thorn/</link>
      <description> Die scheidende EU-Bürgerbeauftragte Emily O’Reilly hat es auf die Beschwerde des ehemaligen Europaabgeordneten der Piratenpartei Patrick Breyer als “Missstand” bewertet, dass ein Europol-Beamter trotz potenzieller Interessenskonflikte ohne jegliche Auflagen zum … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T12:20:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with a Hybrid Heat Pump Water Heater</title>
      <link>https://altmode.org/2025/02/24/my-experience-with-a-hybrid-heat-pump-water-heater/</link>
      <description>In October 2023, my wife emerged from the bathroom one morning to report that we had no hot water. I found that our gas-fired, on-demand water heater had failed and was leaking a small amount. I called our plumber, who confirmed we needed a new water heater. We immediately faced the following decision: Should we […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 01:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T01:16:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are political &amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/how-are-political-economic-uncertainty-impacting-real-estate-consumers/</link>
      <description> Writing that he knows “a bunch of people who held their nose and voted for Trump,” the president of HousingWire media issued this challenge on… 
The post How are political &amp;amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 16:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T16:14:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in OpenID Connect and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/24/use-client-assertions-in-openid-connect-and-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>Client assertions is a method of client authentication which can be used in OpenID Connect. This provides an alternative to client secrets. This approach enhances security by using signed tokens (JWTs) to authenticate clients during the token request process or the OAuth PAR request. In ASP.NET Core, client assertions is not supported per default, a […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T06:43:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPIとVerifiable Credentialsに関するイベントをやります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/fapiverifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  3月頭はFintech Weekということもあり、あちこちでFintech系のイベントが開催されますね。そのうちの一つである4F（Future Frontier Fes by FINOLAB）の一コマをいただきAuthlete川崎さんと一緒にFAPIとVerifiable Credentialsの話をします。  こちらのイベントですね。  https://4f-otmcbldg.tokyo/2025-jp/       このうち、3/4の午前中のセッションです。    セッションの詳細と申し込みはこちらからしていただけます。  https://fapi-vc.peatix.com/        &amp;nbsp;私は慶應の鈴木先生と一緒に先日発行したデジタルクレデンシャルの管理要件に関するディスカッションペーパーの中身の話を解説させていただきます。みなさん色々とデジ</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T02:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Visit To Tulsa With Microtuble Symbolic Communication + Thoughts on DOGE Against A UPenn “Quaker Kabbalah” Backdrop</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/19/a-visit-to-tulsa-with-microtuble-symbolic-communication-thoughts-on-doge-against-a-upenn-quaker-kabbalah-backdrop/</link>
      <description>Posting this late, so I won’t be writing an introduction. As is the case for me lately, the offering is a somewhat rambling discussion that surfaces quiet a few nuggets for you to chew on.&amp;nbsp; Life in this absurdist improvisational theater might easier if we can practice the Tao of Pooh. Smile. Here’s a link [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 04:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-20T04:55:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signing Off from Uniken: Thank You for the Adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/signing-off-from-uniken-thank-you-for-the-adventure.html</link>
      <description>It’s the end of an era: after eight incredible years, it felt like the right time to close the chapter on my story at Uniken. When I joined as CTO, Uniken was an ambitious startup with a unique core technology and a vision to make a global impact. What made the ensuing journey so rewarding […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T15:11:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing a single client sign-in using parameters in Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/17/customizing-a-single-client-sign-in-using-parameters-in-duende-identityserver/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. In the previous post, the UI was customized per […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T06:34:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/multiply-tiny-house-love-story-with-million-backyard-march/</link>
      <description> After a post about a college that’s teaching students how to build their own tiny houses for just $5,000 drew a lot of attention, decided… 
The post Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-14T21:49:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Components</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/02/12/web-components/</link>
      <description>The JavaScript industrial complex won’t crumble anytime soon. But the stage is set for a return to an ecosystem of reusable components accessible to business developers, only this time based on the universal web platform and its core standards. How To Build Web Components Using ChatGPT LLM series at The New Stack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T12:43:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business Case for Dynamic Authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/the-business-case-for-dynamic-authorization</link>
      <description>Authorization isn't just about security.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T18:31:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Science</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/02/11/bitcoin-science/</link>
      <description>  

 Bitcoin failed.  J.P. Koning notes in The end of El Salvador’s bitcoin payments experiment: 

  But here was a government that was going to champion the stuff, nullifying all of the headwinds against bitcoin in one stroke! The government meddling hypothesis would be put to test.

The Salvadoran government used a combination of sticks and carrots to kick-start adoption. First, let's list the ca</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T17:28:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated OAuth Token Exchange access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/10/asp-net-core-delegated-oauth-token-exchange-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated OAuth 2.0 Token Exchange RFC 8693 flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. It looks at how the OAuth Token Exchange can be implemented and how an application can request delegated access tokens on behalf of a user and another application, providing […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 06:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T06:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal For A Spring Break From Mind Viruses – March 13 to the Summer Solstice: Ground, Gather Energy, Reflect, Renew 5 Years Later</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/07/proposal-for-a-spring-break-from-mind-viruses-march-13-to-the-summer-solstice-ground-gather-energy-reflect-renew-5-years-later/</link>
      <description>I made a video today reflecting on how we manage (or don’t) our energy and how our engagement with digital information complicates our lives. I’m proposing that people consider dialing back their social media consumption to spend time reflecting on their thinking, what we have learned over the past five years, and how we can [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 02:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-08T02:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>そういえばEUDIW Architecture Reference Framework 1.5.0が出てますね</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/eudiw-architecture-reference-framework.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    そういえば2月4日にEUDIW ARFの1.5.0が出てますね。  https://eu-digital-identity-wallet.github.io/eudi-doc-architecture-and-reference-framework/latest/architecture-and-reference-framework-main/           GithubのCHANGELOGを見ると     The ARF is aligned with the adopted Implementing Acts, covering articles 5a and 5c of the eIDAS Regulation.&amp;nbsp;  The ARF also includes changes in response to comments provid</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T23:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Up On Quantum Realism In Connection With Gordon Pask’s Mechanical Theatricality – Plus A “Diamond Age” Excerpt Read Aloud</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/05/follow-up-on-quantum-realism-in-connection-with-gordon-pasks-mechanical-theatricality-plus-a-diamond-age-excerpt-read-aloud/</link>
      <description>This is a follow up to yesterday’s video reiterating my thoughts about Live Action Role Play with encoded artefacts as an example of extended mind and possible future inter-dimensional information processing system. The talk goes along with two earlier talks Jason and I did on the work of Michael Mateas here. The feature image is [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:37:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/growing-democracy/</link>
      <description>There is a place, little noticed and even less understood by most Canadians, where democracy is growing stronger despite a history of violence and exploitation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:20:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Candidate Recommendation for Controlled Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2612</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group has published a Snapshot Candidate Recommendation of the Controlled Identifiers specification. This follows the five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group in December 2024. Two of these specifications, including Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE, depend upon the Controlled Identifiers spec. The planned update</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 06:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T06:30:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halbguter neuer polnischer Vorschlag zur Chatkontrolle wird am Mittwoch diskutiert</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/halbguter-neuer-polnischer-vorschlag-zur-chatkontrolle-wird-am-mittwoch-diskutiert/</link>
      <description> Polen, das derzeit den Vorsitz im EU-Rat innehat, schlägt eine wichtige Änderung des viel kritisierten EU-Vorschlags zur Chatkontrolle vor: Anstatt die generelle Durchsuchung privater Chats anzuordnen soll die Chatkontrolle wie … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T10:52:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison Reflects on Joseph Gonzalez’s Theory of Quantum Realism – A Hopeful Participatory Universe Built On Love!</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/03/alison-reflects-on-joseph-gonzalezs-theory-of-quantum-realism-a-hopeful-participatory-universe-built-on-love/</link>
      <description>Below are Joseph Gonzalez’s responses to questions I posed about his theory of quantum realism. You can find out more at his blog bantamjoe.com. I discuss these questions in the video below starting at timestamp 20 minutes. Select links from Bantamjoe.com: The Self-Aware Circle of Consciousness: Here A Holographic Reality Designed By Consciousness, Designed For [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 23:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T23:05:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is About To Come From Inside The House</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/the-call-is-about-to-come-from-inside-the-house.html</link>
      <description>You would have to be living under a rock to have missed all the talk about Agentic AI, and how it is going to revolutionize the way we live and work. AI-powered agents will be anything and everything – from personal shopper to travel concierge, executive assistant to inventory manager, medical diagnostician to customer service […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T21:45:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple client sign-in customizations using Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/03/multiple-client-sign-in-customizations-using-duende-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/duende-multi-tenant Blogs in the series Setup The solution […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 06:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T06:55:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Years of Digital Identity!</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2607</link>
      <description>Kim Cameron first told me what Digital Identity is on February 1, 2005. He said that the Internet was created without an identity layer. He encouraged me “You should come help build it with me.” I’ve been at it ever since! What I wrote about digital identity a decade ago remains as true today: An […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 02:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T02:46:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want you to do these four things right now</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/i-want-you-to-do-these-four-things-right-now-3ea064583460?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Some simple steps to keep yourself safe.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-01T21:04:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win Stupid Prizes</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/30/win-stupid-prizes/</link>
      <description>

 Deadly D.C. Plane Crash Comes Months After Congress Ignored Warning About Traffic at Reagan Airport 

 As the new administration is playing stupid games, yesterday morning, prior to yesterday’s aviation disaster, professor Thomas Schaller cautioned:
 

 
   An FAA employee I know confirms agency already lacks sufficient air traffic controllers. The so-called “buyouts” and other attacks on federa</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T14:44:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take 1... Solid Pods and Dids</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/take-1-solid-pods-and-dids.html</link>
      <description> My first attempt at building a decentralized app in this day and age will use Solid Pods and DIDs. The goal? A super simple “BooksWeLike” app—a place where I can review books and see what my friends are reading and enjoying.     What makes this app different is how it handles data. Unlike traditional apps where data lives in a centralized database, my app will let users store their own data in Sol</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T00:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust, Least Privilege, and Just-in-Time Access</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/zero-trust-least-privilege-and-just</link>
      <description>Security professionals have long taught that organizations should limit the access individuals have in computer systems to just those privileges necessary to perform their job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T13:55:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andreessen and Horowitz’s Debrief On Their Fairshake PAC and Sunny Days Ahead For “Little Tech” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/20/andreessen-and-horowitzs-debrief-on-their-fairshake-pac-and-sunny-days-ahead-for-little-tech-under-trump/</link>
      <description>I took notes on Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz’s post-election discussion of their Fairshake pro-crypto Pac and the coming Trump presidency about two months ago, but set them aside and other topics took precedence. Given the rising craziness in the crypto space around the inauguration, I thought it was a good time to put them [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T03:58:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T07:34:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Dance, Oscillation, And Going “Inside”</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/18/trump-dance-oscillation-and-going-inside/</link>
      <description>In this morning’s video I somehow missed the fact that the inauguration coincides with MLK Day, which is an interesting sync with the “melanin as optical material” lens. I’m going to drop a few links to old blog posts that touch on the YMCA and “out of school time learning” as as well as my [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T17:06:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestalt, Quakers and Carbon Trading – Do You See Faces Or A Vase?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/17/gestalt-quakers-and-carbon-trading-do-you-see-faces-or-a-vase/</link>
      <description>In this video I draw connections between Gestalt theory and organizational development as applied to digital groupthink in the context of Christiana Figueres, a leader in the development of carbon trading, who trained at the Gestalt Institute of Cleveland. As a young woman, she attended Swarthmore College, a Quaker institution. The first wife of her [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T06:06:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T08:18:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Configuration Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/01/14/the-configuration-crisis/</link>
      <description>Perhaps, even though they are not themselves explainable, AIs can help us engineer explainable systems. But I’m not optimistic. It feels like we’re on a path to keep making systems harder for humans to configure, and we keep expanding our reliance on superhuman intelligence to do that for us. The Configuration Crisis and Developer Dependency … Continue reading The Configuration Crisis</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:23:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day An Evangelical Christian Convinced ChatGPT I Was A Hippy, Schwab-Aligned Sociopathic Magician</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/14/the-day-an-evangelical-christian-convinced-chatgpt-i-was-a-hippy-schwab-aligned-sociopathic-magician/</link>
      <description>What will come of large language models when they mirror unsettled psyches defined by religious hero complexes into the cloud? We do ourselves and future generations a profound disservice when we choose not to make time to comprehend and interrogate how emerging technologies and narrative flows are being deployed to steer psychological states individually and [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:00:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/explaining-verifiable-credentials-and-open-badges-3-0-34ae898b98b2?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Part 2: Issuing&amp;nbsp;Badges  In part one of this series, we discussed how the trust model of Open Badges 3.0 differs from earlier versions. Credentials issued as Open Badges 3.0 are based on the W3C Verifiable Credentials data model which describes how claims made online can be&amp;nbsp;proven.  To explore this trust model, let’s explore the story of Olivia who has been taking classes at a local commu</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T15:28:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is anybody out there?</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/is-anybody-out-there.html</link>
      <description> Is blogging still a thing?  If you’re reading this, please comment or like it so I know.     I am, at heart, still the XDI Guy. My passion for robust, secure, and scalable distributed data management hasn’t waned. Building one of the first XDI implementations (shout-out to Markus Sabadello, who might have built the only other one), I learned a lot about the challenges and opportunities of distribu</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T16:20:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECDSAに対応したゼロ知識証明の論文がGoogleから出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/ecdsagoogle.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  AAMVAのモバイル運転免許証のガイドラインでも触れましたが、mdocやSD-JWTのリンク可能性へ対応するためには今後ゼロ知識証明が大切になります。  年末にGoogleの研究者が  Anonymous credentials from ECDSA  というタイトルでペーパーを出しています。  https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/2010    AIでイラスト生成すると色々とおかしなことになって面白いですねw    アブストラクトの中からポイントを抜粋すると、従来のBBS+では暗号スイートへの対応に関する要件が厳しかったのでレガシーで対応できるようにECDSAでもできるようにしたよ、ということのようですね。   Part of the difficulty arises because schemes in the literature,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T00:23:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an open web that protects us from harm</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/building-an-open-web-that-protects-us-from-harm-40a95da1d82f?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s not enough to be neutral. We must be allies.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T15:58:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI RAG with LlamaIndex, Local Embedding, and Ollama Llama 3.1 8b</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-rag-with-llamaindex-local-embedding-and-ollama-llama-3-1-8b-b0620116a715?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> In this post, I cover using LlamaIndex LlamaParse in auto mode to parse a PDF page containing a table, using a Hugging Face local embedding model, and using local Llama 3.1 8b via Ollama to perform naive Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). That’s a mouthful. I won’t go into how to setup Ollama and Llama 3.1 8b; this post assumes it is&amp;nbsp;running.  First off, you can find the code for this in m</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T14:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gregg Braden Led Me To Share My Thoughts on Quantum Coherence, Collective Computing, and Tokenized Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/10/how-gregg-braden-led-me-to-share-my-thoughts-on-quantum-coherence-collective-computing-and-tokenized-spirituality/</link>
      <description>This is a video I posted yesterday. And a follow up to clarify certain points. Sorry, I guess the youtube AI choose the “hands up” screenshot for the preview image. I do talk a lot with my hands. Here is a link to Joseph Gonzalez’s blog post on emergent information communication systems. Here are two [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T06:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorization Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/authorization-matters</link>
      <description>In 2013, poor authorization practices led to one of the largest data breaches in history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T19:36:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sqitch 1.5.0</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/sqitch-1.5.0/</link>
      <description>Sqitch v1.5.0: out now in all the usual places!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T02:30:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hockey Trivia</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/08/hockey-trivia/</link>
      <description>  

 As I just registered for a new season of beer league hockey starting this weekend, I thought about an episode of C’est comme ça que je t’aime I recently watched which is set in 1974 Sainte-Foy, Quebec City.  Nearly all the 1974 Quebec cultural references are new to me and in this episode, there is an adventure in a hockey arena and you can pause the video in a few places and see signage in the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T16:03:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OYO AI</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/01/oyo-ai.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;With over 1000 AI communities deployed in 2024, the next AI cohort begins..                                   Coding, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence, Entrepreneurial Skill Development, Teacher PD,&amp;nbsp;  With mentor support of all learners, students and teachers. Unlimited learning by design: (own root)&amp;nbsp;  OYO®&amp;nbsp; AI&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;by kidOYO®&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;at OYOclass.com, Educati</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T12:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 books</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/46-books-5f8c47016bb2?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Every book is a portal out of here.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-07T23:29:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-llamaindex-part-1-openai-e96b3efa699a?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI  I have started to experiment with LlamaIndex for use in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) document parsing and indexing. My results were mixed on the simple page provided. This is part 1, where I make a short post on LlamaIndex with OpenAI as the LLM component. I expect part 2 to be LlamaIndex with Ollama and Llama3–8b as the LLM components.  This is a very sho</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T21:15:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Second Candidate Recommendation for Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2603</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group published the Snapshot Second Candidate Recommendation of the Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE specification just before the holidays. This was one of five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group at the same time, including for the Verifiable Credentials Data Model 2.0, which I’m also an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-03T04:57:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should URI::mysql Switch to DBD::MariaDB?</title>
      <link>https://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=11163487</link>
      <description>Should Sqitch and URI::mysql use DBD::MariaDB instead of DBD::mysql? If so,
what are the implications for Sqitch deployment and usage?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T22:47:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New JSONPath Feature: SelectLocated</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/jsonpath-located/</link>
      <description>New in the jsonpath Go package and Playground: “Located” results that pair
selected values with normalized paths to their locations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:43:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intention Economyその後</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/intention-economy.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    年末にDoc SearlsがIntention Economyについて「The Real Intention Economy」というポストをしています。かなり重要なポストだと思うので読んでおいた方が良さそうです。     https://doc.searls.com/2024/12/30/the-real-intention-economy/     彼の著書は日本語にも翻訳されていますね。  https://amzn.to/3C2PX9n        さて、今回のDocのポストに戻ると、彼がIntention Economyの考え方を発表してからもう直ぐ20年が経とうとしている現在、生成AIの文脈も相まって、Intention Economy自体が脅威となりつつある、という話です。     Intention Economyで検索すると結構ヤバ目の結果が返</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T03:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL/JSON Path Playground Update</title>
      <link>https://theory.github.io/sqljson/</link>
      <description>The Go SQL/JSON Playground has been updated with a fresh design and PostgreSQL
17 compatibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T20:40:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tintin and the fascists</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/tintin-and-the-fascists-90241c93b3c6?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    The boy reporter has a fascist origin. But something new is possible.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T16:46:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for tech, 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/predictions-for-tech-2025-4046a6331cb9?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s going to be a hard year.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T15:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>366/366 !!!</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/366366.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  ついにこの日が来ました。           去年の正月休みに某猫とのチキンレースが始まってしまったので収まりがつかなくなって惰性で描き続けていましたが気がついたら本当に1年経ってしまいました。  ↓某猫のポスト 
  ふじえさん、やっぱりやっとるな！ 毎日記事を書く366チャレンジや！ これ絶対やっとるぞ！ — 👹秋田の猫🐱 (@ritou) January 4, 2024  
    最初のうちは割と実装してみよう！的なポストが多かったのですが、中盤〜後半は忙しくなりすぎたこともあり読んでみようシリーズが大半を占めてしまったのは反省です。  ということで振り返ってみましょう。  1月のポストはこんな感じです。     この頃は結構作ってますね。まぁ、冬休みが暇だったので実装し始めたのがきっかけだったので。  あとは1月はOpenID Summit Tokyo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T23:11:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soll ich der elektronischen Patientenakte widersprechen und wie geht das?</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/soll-ich-der-elektronischen-patientenakte-widersprechen-und-wie-geht-das/</link>
      <description> Wenn du gesetzlich krankenversichert bist, wird deine Krankenkasse bis 15. Januar 2025 eine elektronische Patientenakte für dich einrichten – es sei denn, du widersprichst. Das gilt auch für private Krankenversicherungen, die … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T10:32:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑧</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01040135091.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだまだプライバシーの章が続きます。  4.5.&amp;nbsp;DELETING MDL INFORMATION FROM A DEVICE   An mDL holder must have the capability to delete the mDL holder’s mDL from the mDL holder’s device. Such deletion:      Must delete all mDL information, log information, and any metadata (e.g. settings) that could impart information </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-29T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑦</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_02108542609.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     引き続き4章のプライバシーの部分を読んでいきます。  4.3.&amp;nbsp;PROTECTING DATA   It is up to Issuing Authorities to ensure that all mDL data stored on the mDL holder’s device is adequately protected. As standards in this respect are still under development, each Issuing Authority should take great care to ensure that the design of its</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑥</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_28.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        ようやく4章の「PRIVACY AND SECURITY」に入ります。4章も結構長いんですよね。。。ただ、結構重要な章なので細かくみていきたいと思います。     4.1.&amp;nbsp;INTRODUCTION   The privacy of an mDL holder has been paramount in the mDL design process from the start. Care was and is being taken in all the work to ensure that methods and means are available to protect mDL h</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T21:57:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a framework for living well</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/creating-a-framework-for-living-well-4aafe427c74b?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Drawing upa North Star for building my life  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T17:06:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 Foundation: SDO Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/26/web-7-0-foundation-sdo-accreditation/</link>
      <description>The Web 7.0 Foundation is a relatively new organization, incorporated in Canada on May 1, 2023². It focuses on developing specifications and standards for a unified software and hardware ecosystem aimed at building resilient, trusted, and decentralized systems¹³. Source: Conversation … Continue reading →</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T23:05:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑤</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0938402867.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだ３章が続きますが今回で３章は終わりです。     3.6.&amp;nbsp;IACA ROOT CERTIFICATE   In Table B.1 of ISO/IEC 18013-5, on the table row for the “ISSUER” certificate component, replace:     stateOrProvinceName is optional. If this element is present, the element shall also be present in the end-entity certificates and hold the same va</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む④</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01062834414.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        引き続き３章を読んでいきます。  3-3.&amp;nbsp;PORTRAIT IMAGE   The portrait image is the primary means by which an mDL is matched to the person presenting the mDL in an attended transaction. The portrait image therefore needs to be of suitable quality for this purpose. ISO/IEC 18013-5 requires the portrait to comply with Ann</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-25T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む③</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0833807043.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は３章のISO/IEC 18013-5 QUALIFICATIONSです。  3.1. INTRODUCTION   Issuing authorities electing to follow the guidance in this document must adhere to ISO/IEC 18013-5, including as qualified in this document.    本文書のガイダンスに従うことを選択した発行局は、本文書で修飾されている場合を含め、ISO/IEC 18013-5 を遵守しなければならない。   3.2.&amp;nbsp;AAMVA MDL DATA ELEMEN</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-24T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む②</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_24.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は２章のmDL Solution Overviewを見ていきます。   An mDL can be described as leveraging a mobile device to transfer (or cause to be transferred) driver’s license information to an mDL verifier, who cryptographically authenticates the information using the Issuing
Authority’s public key. A visual rendering of a DL on a mo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-23T22:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む①</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日、用語を見たついでにAAMVAが出しているMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいこうと思います。          こちらが原文です。     まずはIntroductionから。   The AAMVA Joint Mobile Driver’s License (mDL) Working Group (WG) has been active around mobile identification since 2012. As the mDL evolves, the mDL WG continues to identify and address topics on which guidance to Issuing Authorities can be helpful. T</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSONTree Module and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/12/jsontree/</link>
      <description>I’m happy to announce the release of the JSONTree Go module and Wasm-powered
in-browser playground.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 21:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T21:33:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Sovereign Identity: Over before it started?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/self-sovereign-identity-over-before-it-started-661b4b0dbdc6?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Web security, symbolized Monty Pythons parrot sketch is an all time classic because it plays on a very human experience of being defenseless when someone is just blatantly refusing to acknowledge the obvious. Shared reality is a matter of perception, not objective observation. Supported also by various mental biases, including the sunk cost fallacy, and the desire to agree with people we perceive a</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T19:13:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID for Verifiable Credentials IssuanceのPublic Review期間が始まりました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/openid-for-verifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日のOpenID for Verifiable Presentationにつづき、いよいよ始まりました。ついにOpenID for Verifiable Credential Issuanceも2nd Implementer's Draftです。        https://openid.net/public-review-period-for-proposed-second-implementers-draft-of-openid-for-verifiable-credential-issuance/  こんなスケジュールです。    Implementer's Draft public review period: Friday, December 20, 2024 to Sunday, February 2, 2025 (45 days)  Imple</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T01:04:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ついに発売へ。デジタルアイデンティティのすべて</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post_21.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    週末に家に帰ったら先行して届いていました。12月27日に発売になる「デジタルアイデンティティのすべて」です。  原著と比べると少しだけ大きいですね。        こちらから予約注文できますのでどうぞ。  https://amzn.to/3P9KS2e        ついでにSoftware Designの最新号も届いていましたし、年末年始はアイデンティティとパスキーざんまいですね！        1月末には「パスキーのすべて」も発売されますので、体（頭）をあっためておきましょう。  https://amzn.to/3ZHQohg    </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-21T09:58:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Water is Death</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/12/20/no-water-is-death/</link>
      <description>

 “Extermination &amp;amp; Acts of Genocide”: Human Rights Watch on Israel Deliberately Depriving Gaza of Water 

 AMY GOODMAN: So, can I ask you, Bill Van Esveld, is this the first time that Human Rights Watch is accusing Israel of genocide in Gaza? 

 BILL VAN ESVELD: This is the first time that we’ve made a finding of genocidal acts in Gaza. It is not an accusation that we level lightly. We have no</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-20T15:06:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>モバイル運転免許証に関する用語を見ていきます</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    こちらにも書いた通り、11月にAAMVAからMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelineの1.4がでました。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/mobile-drivers-licensemdl.html          読んでいてそういえば一般的じゃない言葉ばっかり使ってるよなぁ、と思うのでまずはTerminologyを見ておきましょう。         そもそも論のAAMVAです。    American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators   の略ですね。米国自動車管理者協会と訳されるようです。この辺の資料によると。&amp;nbsp;     EDL。enhanced driver licenseの略ですね。日本語だと</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-19T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDに関するグローバルの動向</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/id.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    OpenID FoundationのブログでElizabethが各国のデジタルIDに関する最近のトピックスを取り上げていますので紹介したいと思います。もちろん日本も含まれています。  https://openid.net/digital-identity-news-round-up-13-dec-2024/             キプロス   デジタル・シチズンとして知られるモバイル・デジタルIDアプリを開始した。  このアプリでは、バイオメトリクスIDカード、運転免許証、自動車の路上使用適格性証明書などのデジタル文書をモバイルで保持することができる。また、QRコードを使ってデジタル認証することもできる  https://www.biometricupdate.com/202412/cyprus-launches-digital-citizen-mobile</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPI2.0の最終化に向けたPublic Reviewが始まります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/fapi20public-review.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  FAPI2.0のSecurity Profile and Attacker Modelに関する仕様の最終化に関するPublic Review期間が始まっていますね。  https://openid.net/public-review-for-proposed-final-fapi-2-0-specifications/        今後はこんなスケジュールで進むようです。    Final Specification public review period: Monday, December 9, 2024 to Friday, February 7, 2025 (60 days)  Final Specification vote announcement: Saturday, January 25, 2025  Final Specification e</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T00:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumでの登壇内容を紹介します</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/taiwan-digital-identity-wallet.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先週はTaiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumで登壇してきましたので、キーノートとしてお話した内容をメモしておきたいと思います。  イベントについてはこちら  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/11/taiwan-digital-wallet-international.html          自己紹介は置いておいて、テーマは相互運用性でした。    As you know, the Digital Identity Wallet has recently become an emerging topic in the digital identity space. For example, the European Committee has started im</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph from Wikipedia in Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/building-a-knowledge-graph-from-wikipedia-in-neo4j/</link>
      <description>https://guides.neo4j.com/wiki https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/cats.csv?raw=true https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/rels.csv?raw=true</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T18:06:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Songwriter/Performer Use Case: DID Method Candidates</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/toronto-songwriter-performer-use-case-did-method-candidates/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 10:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T10:02:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>年明けはデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WG：活動報告会から</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/wg.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     年明け1/14はデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WGの活動報告会があります。  https://openid.connpass.com/event/339259/       例の本が年末に販売されることもあり、翻訳を担当したメンバーから苦労話など聞ける良い機会になると思いますのでぜひご来場ください。    </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-15T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Shape Our Tools then Our Tools Shape Us</title>
      <link>https://kyledenhartog.com/tools-shape-us/</link>
      <description>the methods we choose to communicate with affects not only the cohesiveness of the community, but also the norms and the values reflected.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>