<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Identosphere Identity Blogcatcher: Personal</title>
    <link>https://identosphere.com</link>
    <description>Personal blogs of individuals working in decentralized identity.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/16/nbc-the-poll-doesnt-have.html</link>
      <description> NBC 
 
 The poll doesn’t have good news for Democrats, either. The Democratic Party has reached an all-time low in popularity, with only 27% of respondents holding a positive view — its lowest positive rating in NBC News polling dating back to 1990. And the slump is partially driven by fed-up Democrats who want the party to fight Trump harder. 
 </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 02:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-17T02:35:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now you don’t even need code to be a programmer. But you do still need expertise</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/16/john-naughton/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Now you don’t even need code to be a programmer. But you do still need expertise 
My recent piece on how I use LLMs to help me write code got a positive mention in John Naughton's column about vibe-coding in the Guardian this weekend. 
 My hunch about Apple Intelligence Siri features being delayed due to prompt injection also got a mention in the most recent episode of the New York Times Hard Fork</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 23:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T23:07:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My (New) Daily Blog</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/my-new-daily-blog</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Om Malik]  This is an ongoing trend. Om Malik has now moved to sharing on his blog first rather than posting directly to social media:   &quot;The inspiration for the newly rebooted “daily blog” comes from Dave Winer, who maintains a “Links” blog. I’ve been using his new project, Wordland, for publishing to the “links” blog, in addition to using MarsEdit. I have also taken a cue fr</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 22:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T22:17:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to hide a painting</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/how-to-hide-a-painting</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mike Monteiro]  On whether it's always been this bad in America:   &quot;America was born in blood, genocide, kidnapping, and death. Behind every story we were told about America’s greatness, there is a secret second painting. A thing America doesn’t want you to see. Behind every “from sea to shining sea” there is a Trail of Tears. Behind every first pitch at Dodger Stadium there’s</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 22:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T22:14:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/16/dave-asked-the-question-about.html</link>
      <description> @Dave asked the question about Wordland as to whether I was surprised that having posted something … the screen didn’t clear. I get it and understand why the decision was made .. but it still caught me out. 
 @om is using Wordland to create a new kind of Daily post. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 19:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T19:07:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/16/om-has-a-new-idea.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 Om has a new idea that utilises Wordland .. which is pretty darn close to what I do here on Micro Blog. 
 That said .. I would still like a simple way that allows me in ‘view blog mode’ to quickly edit what I am looking at .. rather than the hoop jumping I need to do. 
 And then I would like whatever changes I make on the blog to ricochet into the social media platforms .. but I know that’s a di</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T18:31:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/16/chuck-schumer-bob-writing-what.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 Chuck Schumer 
 Bob writing what the Democrats should understand. But do they? </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T18:25:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/16/inspired-by-people-muhammad-ali.html</link>
      <description> 🕵💬 Inspired By People | 🌐 Muhammad Ali 

 🔍 All The Posts can be found here, or scroll through the quotes below. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T17:36:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gag of America</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/16/gag-of-america/</link>
      <description>Here is what a Google News search for Voice of America looks like right now: ‘Bloody Saturday’ at Voice of America and other U.S.-funded networks, by David Folkenflik at NPR, begins with this: Journalists showed up at the Voice of America today to broadcast their programs only to be told they had been locked out: […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T17:12:25+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backstory on the default styles for the HTML dialog modal</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/16/backstory/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Backstory on the default styles for the HTML dialog modal 
My TIL about Styling an HTML dialog modal to take the full height of the viewport (here's the interactive demo) showed up on Hacker News this morning, and attracted this fascinating comment from Chromium engineer Ian Kilpatrick. 
 
 There's quite a bit of history here, but the abbreviated version is that the dialog element was originally a</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T16:36:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mlx-community/OLMo-2-0325-32B-Instruct-4bit</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/16/olmo2/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> mlx-community/OLMo-2-0325-32B-Instruct-4bit 
OLMo 2 32B claims to be &quot;the first fully-open model (all data, code, weights, and details are freely available) to outperform GPT3.5-Turbo and GPT-4o mini&quot;. Thanks to the MLX project here's a recipe that worked for me to run it on my Mac, via my llm-mlx plugin. 
 To install the model: 
 llm install llm-mlx
llm mlx download-model mlx-community/OLMo-2-032</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 03:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T03:30:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/not-disappointed-but-not-what.html</link>
      <description> Not disappointed - but not what I was hoping for … ☹️ </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-16T00:19:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/so-much-for-and-done.html</link>
      <description> So much for ‘3 and done’. You know what I am talking about. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 19:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T19:10:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barbie, 2023 - ★★★★</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/barbie.html</link>
      <description>    Finally got around to it and … Marvelous .. and I’m not even a fan of ‘musicals’. &amp;nbsp;So good that it needs to be rereleased. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 18:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T18:58:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/heard-in-a-show-that.html</link>
      <description> Heard in a show that I can’t recall the name of …. 
 
 Underneath anger there is always a sadness - what are you grieving? 
 </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 18:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T18:55:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/the-keys-to-leading-today.html</link>
      <description> 🔗 The 4 Keys to Leading Today - Rishad Tobaccowala </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 18:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T18:55:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/totally-legit-steal-my-tesla.html</link>
      <description> Totally legit. 
 🔗 Steal My Tesla </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 18:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T18:53:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Up</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/15/lightning-up/</link>
      <description>What you see above is a line of storms that is moving northeastward from southern Louisiana across all of Mississippi, western Tennessee, all of Kentucky, southern Indiana (where I am), and western Ohio. It is provided by Weatherbug. If you go there and slide the Weather Overlay up to the Storm Tracker view, the map […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 18:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T18:42:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/15/inspired-by-people-zig-ziglar.html</link>
      <description> 🕵💬 Inspired By People | 🌐 Zig Ziglar 

 🔍 All The Posts can be found here, or scroll through the quotes below. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 18:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T18:04:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognition, Identity, and AI: Building Trust in Digital Agents</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/03/recognition-identity-and-ai-building.html</link>
      <description> My first love was self-sovereign distributed data, where each person owns and controls their data, hosting it wherever they choose and permissioning it under their own terms. But I got lost in the complexity of building a robust distributed identity infrastructure. How can you give permission to someone if you can’t 'name' them in a way that is verifiable and resistant to subversion? There's no po</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T16:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Andrew Ng</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/15/andrew-ng/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Some people today are discouraging others from learning programming on the grounds AI will automate it. This advice will be seen as some of the worst career advice ever given. I disagree with the Turing Award and Nobel prize winner who wrote, “It is far more likely that the programming occupation will become extinct [...] than that it will become all-powerful. More and more, computers will progra</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 14:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T14:44:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/14/remember-these-names-dinos-ultimately.html</link>
      <description> Remember these names. #DINOs 
 
 Ultimately, Schumer was joined in voting to advance the measure by Democratic Sens.   Catherine Cortez Masto of Nevada,   Dick Durbin of Illinois,   John Fetterman of Pennsylvania,   Kirsten Gillibrand of New York,   Maggie Hassan of New Hampshire,   Gary Peters of Michigan,   Brian Schatz of Hawaii,   Jeanne Shaheen of New Hampshire, and  Angus King, a Maine indep</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 03:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-15T03:58:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Styling an HTML dialog modal to take the full height of the viewport</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/14/styling-an-html-dialog/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> TIL: Styling an HTML dialog modal to take the full height of the viewport 
I spent some time today trying to figure out how to have a modal &amp;lt;dialog&amp;gt; element present as a full height side panel that animates in from the side. The full height bit was hard, until Natalie helped me figure out that browsers apply a default max-height: calc(100% - 6px - 2em); rule which needs to be over-ridden. 
 </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 23:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T23:13:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/14/day-zero-its-here.html</link>
      <description> 🎵 Day Zero. It’s here. </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T21:44:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/14/a-while-back-there-was.html</link>
      <description> A while back there was a micro blog error in the share sheet .. when sharing links they broke  .. it got fixed .. but now seems to be back. Or is it just me? More exploration needed. </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T21:36:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple’s Siri Chief Calls AI Delays Ugly and Embarrassing, Promises Fixes</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/14/ai-delays/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Apple’s Siri Chief Calls AI Delays Ugly and Embarrassing, Promises Fixes 
Mark Gurman reports on some leaked details from internal Apple meetings concerning the delays in shipping personalized Siri. This note in particular stood out to me: 
 
 Walker said the decision to delay the features was made because of quality issues and that the company has found the technology only works properly up to tw</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T21:35:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/14/inspired-by-people-anita-roddick.html</link>
      <description> 🕵💬 Inspired By People | 🌐 Anita Roddick 

 🔍 All The Posts can be found here, or scroll through the quotes below. 
  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T21:09:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How ProPublica Uses AI Responsibly in Its Investigations</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/14/propublica-ai/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> How ProPublica Uses AI Responsibly in Its Investigations 
Charles Ornstein describes how ProPublic used an LLM to help analyze data for their recent story A Study of Mint Plants. A Device to Stop Bleeding. This Is the Scientific Research Ted Cruz Calls “Woke.” by Agnel Philip and Lisa Song. 
 They ran ~3,400 grant descriptions through a prompt that included the following: 
 
 As an investigative j</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T21:04:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/14/you-know-how-i-hate.html</link>
      <description> 🔗🔎 You know how I hate that word ‘content’ .. it’s getting worse. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T20:48:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something Is Rotten in the State of Cupertino</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/14/something-is-rotten/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Something Is Rotten in the State of Cupertino 
John Gruber's blazing takedown of Apple's failure to ship many of the key Apple Intelligence features they've been actively promoting for the past twelve months. 
 
 The fiasco here is not that Apple is late on AI. It's also not that they had to announce an embarrassing delay on promised features last week. Those are problems, not fiascos, and problem</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T20:15:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merklemap runs a 16TB PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/14/merklemap-runs-a-16tb-postgresql/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Merklemap runs a 16TB PostgreSQL 
Interesting thread on Hacker News where Pierre Barre describes the database architecture behind Merklemap, a certificate transparency search engine. 
 
 I run a 100 billion+ rows Postgres database [0], that is around 16TB, it's pretty painless! 
 There are a few tricks that make it run well (PostgreSQL compiled with a non-standard block size, ZFS, careful VACUUM p</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T20:13:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Short History of Now</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/14/a-short-history-of-now/</link>
      <description>So there must be something to it. Watch how often people interrupt each other with “So—.” Also watch for speeches starting with “So—.” The first speaker I heard do that was Larry Lessig, one of the world’s best, back in the aughts. Which is why the Web is still for writers. All writers. The Longing&amp;nbsp;is […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T14:40:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tonight’s Lunar Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/13/tonights-lunar-eclipse/</link>
      <description>They call it a blood moon, because it looks like this: But that came later. Right now still in the evening of March 13th in the Eastern time zone, the Moon is as full as it can get without moving into the shadow of Earth . Which it will. Shortly. Here is where Earth’s shadow […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 02:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T02:20:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Steve Klabnik</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/14/steve-klabnik/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  [...] in 2013, I did not understand that the things I said had meaning. I hate talking about this because it makes me seem more important than I am, but it’s also important to acknowledge. I saw myself at the time as just Steve, some random guy. If I say something on the internet, it’s like I’m talking to a friend in real life, my words are just random words and I’m human and whatever. It is what</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-14T00:40:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding AI-generated descriptions to my tools collection</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/tools-colophon/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> The /colophon page on my tools.simonwillison.net site lists all 78 of the HTML+JavaScript tools I've built (with AI assistance) along with their commit histories, including links to prompting transcripts. I wrote about how I built that colophon the other day. It now also includes a description of each tool, generated using Claude 3.7 Sonnet. 
  
 This is the single largest chunk of AI-generated te</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 23:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T23:48:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/13/who-is-jasmine-mooney-ice.html</link>
      <description> 🔗Who is Jasmine Mooney? ICE detains Canadian entrepreneur at US border, sends her to Arizona facility ‘in chains’ - Hindustan Times 
 I am finding this story being reported in a number of places .. though no where in US media. 
 More to come as I triangulate. </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 23:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T23:19:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Evan Miller</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/evan-miller/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  One of the most essential practices for maintaining the long-term quality of computer code is to write automated tests that ensure the program continues to act as expected, even when other people (including your future self) muck with it.  
 — Evan Miller 

     Tags: testing, evan-miller </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 22:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T22:50:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xata Agent</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/xata-agent/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Xata Agent 
Xata are a hosted PostgreSQL company who also develop the open source pgroll and pgstream schema migration tools. 
 Their new &quot;Agent&quot; tool is a system that helps monitor and optimize a PostgreSQL server using prompts to LLMs. 
 Any time I see a new tool like this I go hunting for the prompts. It looks like the main system prompts for orchestrating the tool live here - here's a sample: </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 22:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T22:27:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ai2</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/ai2/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Today we release OLMo 2 32B, the most capable and largest model in the OLMo 2 family, scaling up the OLMo 2 training recipe used for our 7B and 13B models released in November. It is trained up to 6T tokens and post-trained using Tulu 3.1. OLMo 2 32B is the first fully-open model (all data, code, weights, and details are freely available) to outperform GPT3.5-Turbo and GPT-4o mini on a suite of p</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 21:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T21:10:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic API: Text editor tool</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/anthropic-api-text-editor-tool/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Anthropic API: Text editor tool 
Anthropic released a new &quot;tool&quot; today for text editing. It looks similar to the tool they offered as part of their computer use beta API, and the trick they've been using for a while in both Claude Artifacts and the new Claude Code to more efficiently edit files there. 
 The new tool requires you to implement several commands: 
 
 view - to view a specified file - </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T20:53:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Command A: Max performance, minimal compute</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/command-a/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Introducing Command A: Max performance, minimal compute 
New LLM release from Cohere. It's interesting to see which aspects of the model they're highlighting, as an indicator of what their commercial customers value the most (highlights mine): 
 
 Command A delivers maximum performance with minimal hardware costs when compared to leading proprietary and open-weights models, such as GPT-4o and Deep</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T20:37:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #127: Typescript compiler rewritten in Go</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-127</link>
      <description>Why did Microsoft choose a language developed by Google, instead of its own, C#? Also: OpenAI’s dev tools for agents looking complex, the PR/FAQ for AWS Lambda, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T17:27:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoke test your Django admin site</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/13/smoke-test-your-django-admin/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Smoke test your Django admin site 
Justin Duke demonstrates a neat pattern for running simple tests against your internal Django admin site: introspect every admin route via django.urls.get_resolver() and loop through them with @pytest.mark.parametrize to check they all return a 200 HTTP status code. 
 This catches simple mistakes with the admin configuration that trigger exceptions that might oth</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T15:02:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/trying-to-understand-starmers-tariff.html</link>
      <description> Trying to understand Starmer’s tariff response - don’t. But I’m sure he has a cunning plan. (#baldrick .. I wonder if Rick really is bald?) </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 01:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T01:49:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/i-dont-know-this-for.html</link>
      <description> I don’t know this for a fact but that post from John Gruber about AI must be close to one of his longest - saved for later. </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-13T00:43:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/a-different-view-of-the.html</link>
      <description> A different view of the Windmillls 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 22:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T22:19:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/bbye-now-thanks-for-the.html</link>
      <description> B-Bye now. Thanks for the hang. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 21:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T21:47:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/dear-leader-is-not-just.html</link>
      <description> ‘Dear Leader’ is not just a sign of enforced affection .. but in the UK, is also an expression that signifies the overall cost to both people and country. 
 
 “Ooh they’re dear.” 
 
 .. a Brit might say when looking seeing the price of eggs in the U.S.A. #LanguageEfficiency </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 20:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T20:21:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOV.UK WalletとOne Login</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6766/</link>
      <description>GOV.UK Wallet とは GOV.UK Walletは、デジタル運転免許証のコンテキストで1月21日に明らかになったイギリス政府が開発中のデジタル文書管理アプリで、2025年2月5日にはピーター・カイル科学・イノベーション・技術担当国務長官によりその詳細が発表が行われまし…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T19:13:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/i-think-ill-leave-the.html</link>
      <description> I think I’ll leave the muskrat to kiss your dad’s feet Lara - of course - your dad will definitely have to return the favour .. I mean it’s what the President expects. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T17:55:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://john.philpin.com/2025/03/12/took-in-some-desert-x.html</link>
      <description> Took in some Desert X the other day .. my favourite from the ones I saw. Will try to post some more later. 
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T17:48:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Google's Gemma 3</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/12/gemma-3/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Google's Gemma team released an impressive new model today (under their not-open-source Gemma license). Gemma 3 comes in four sizes - 1B, 4B, 12B, and 27B - and while 1B is text-only the larger three models are all multi-modal for vision: 
 
 Gemma 3 introduces multimodality, supporting vision-language input and text outputs. It handles context windows up to 128k tokens, understands over 140 langu</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T16:15:19+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Experience at Uber with Gautam Korlam</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/developer-experience-at-uber</link>
      <description>Gautam Korlam, former principal engineer at Uber and co-founder of Gitar, joins the podcast to discuss scaling engineering teams, the challenges of monorepos, and how AI is reshaping developer productivity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T15:57:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/12/thoughts/</link>
      <description>An important extinction. Overheard (between veteran unemployed journalists): “I’m not a has-been. I’m a still-was.” Because you’re the only one who might employ you. “DIY journalism” just got uttered in a call I’m on. Its the windows, mostly. I didn’t like Boeing’s 787 eight years ago, and still don’t like it now. That’s my response […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T14:18:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musical Moments</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/11/musical-moments/</link>
      <description>I need to learn French.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This is lovely. Who is this girl? Here's one clue. Another. Look for more. Never heard of her before today. Hello, I still love you. The Doors are 60 this year. Or would have been. Good and legendary as they were, I think they are woefully underrated. Manzarek, Densmore, and Krieger […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 03:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-12T03:53:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Agents SDK</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/11/openai-agents-sdk/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> OpenAI Agents SDK 
OpenAI's other big announcement today (see also) - a Python library (openai-agents) for building &quot;agents&quot;, which is a replacement for their previous swarm research project. 
 In this project, an &quot;agent&quot; is a class that configures an LLM with a system prompt an access to specific tools. 
 An interesting concept in this one is the concept of handoffs, where one agent can chose to </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T21:58:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI API: Responses vs. Chat Completions</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/11/responses-vs-chat-completions/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> OpenAI API: Responses vs. Chat Completions 
OpenAI released a bunch of new API platform features this morning under the headline &quot;New tools for building agents&quot; (their somewhat mushy interpretation of &quot;agents&quot; here is &quot;systems that independently accomplish tasks on behalf of users&quot;). 
 A particularly significant change is the introduction of a new Responses API, which is a slightly different shape</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 21:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T21:47:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Ryan Cavanaugh</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/11/ryan-cavanaugh/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  Languages that allow for a structurally similar codebase offer a significant boon for anyone making code changes because we can easily port changes between the two codebases. In contrast, languages that require fundamental rethinking of memory management, mutation, data structuring, polymorphism, laziness, etc., might be a better fit for a ground-up rewrite, but we're undertaking this more as a p</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T19:32:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI fakers exposed in tech dev recruitment: postmortem</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/ai-fakers</link>
      <description>A full-remote security startup nearly hired a backend engineer who doesn’t exist, after a candidate used an AI filter as an on-screen disguise in video interviews. Learnings for tech companies</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T17:54:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation with ChatGPT About Personal AI</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/11/a-conversation-with-chatgpt-about-personal-ai/</link>
      <description>What follows is a conversation I’m having with ChatGPT about personal AI. I guarantee it’s unlike any conversation about AI you’ll find anywhere else. It’s copied and pasted, and full of weird HTML that later I’ll run through a text editor or something to fix. Meanwhile the “You said” and “ChatGPT said”&amp;nbsp; don’t show in […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T14:58:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Riding on Rivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/11/riding-on-rivers/</link>
      <description>Just learned about this, here. Thank you, Andy Sylvester!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T14:27:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's how I use LLMs to help me write code</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/11/using-llms-for-code/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Online discussions about using Large Language Models to help write code inevitably produce comments from developers who's experiences have been disappointing. They often ask what they're doing wrong - how come some people are reporting such great results when their own experiments have proved lacking? 
 Using LLMs to write code is difficult and unintuitive. It takes significant effort to figure ou</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T14:09:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New German, Swiss, And Austrian Guidelines Recommend Trans Youth Care, Slam Cass Review</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/new-german-swiss-and-austrian-guidelines-recommend-trans-youth-care</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Erin In The Morning]  While America is destroying the ability for trans people to participate in public life, over in Europe they're (rightly) improving care for trans people.   &quot;In recent years, U.S. politicians have selectively framed European healthcare policies to justify restrictions on transgender care, seizing on a handful of conservative policies to claim that “Europe </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T12:42:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Hiatus – Look For Me In The Garden</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/03/11/on-hiatus-look-for-me-in-the-garden/</link>
      <description>Today I realized that even though the Web3 program is ramping up as demonstrated by Silicon Valley’s plans to turn Argentina into a “network state,” few understand what is unfolding with cybernetic governance. For that reason, I decided to take time off this spring to work on my garden and simply be with real people [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-11T04:32:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>llm-openrouter 0.4</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/10/llm-openrouter-04/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> llm-openrouter 0.4 
I found out this morning that OpenRouter include support for a number of (rate-limited) free API models. 
 I occasionally run workshops on top of LLMs (like this one) and being able to provide students with a quick way to obtain an API key against models where they don't have to setup billing is really valuable to me! 
 This inspired me to upgrade my existing llm-openrouter plu</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 21:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T21:40:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leader of student protests at Columbia facing deportation</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/leader-of-student-protests-at-columbia-facing-deportation</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Jake Offenhartz, Cedar Attanasio and Philip Marcelo at The Associated Press]  This seems completely in line with the First Amendment's protections against restrictions on speech and assembly by the US government:   &quot;President Donald Trump warned Monday that the arrest and possible deportation of a Palestinian activist who helped lead protests at Columbia University will be the</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 20:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T20:42:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OECD: AI時代におけるデータのアクセスおよび共有の促進</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/03/6757/</link>
      <description>ちょっと旧聞になりますが、去る2月5日に、OECDから面白い文書が出ています。 以下はその内容を大まかにまとめたものです。詳しくは原文を御覧ください。 概要 データガバナンスの主要概念 データアクセスと共有の強化のための原則 実践的な応用と影響 データ共有インフラの強化 競争当局…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T16:50:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Items</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/10/items/</link>
      <description>Death sells. So far today, this blog post has had 13 visits. Meanwhile, Radio’s Death Knells has had 356. Since I need to go out, I’ll call it a day and put a picture on top. See what happens. What was Indiana thinking?&amp;nbsp;These days sunrise in Bloomington is about four hours before noon, and sunset […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T13:28:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Terrorgram Collective Influencers Groomed a Killer</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/how-terrorgram-collective-influencers-groomed-a-killer</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [A.C. Thompson, ProPublica and FRONTLINE, James Bandler, ProPublica, and Lukáš Diko, Investigative Center of Jan Kuciak]  A tragic story of a teenager recruited by a network of extremists, who ultimately murdered multiple people before taking his own life. It's also an example of why moderation and safety processes on social platforms are so important.   &quot;And so in August 2019,</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T12:54:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Thane Ruthenis</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/10/thane-ruthenis/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  It seems to me that &quot;vibe checks&quot; for how smart a model feels are easily gameable by making it have a better personality. 
 My guess is that it's most of the reason Sonnet 3.5.1 was so beloved. Its personality was made much more appealing, compared to e. g. OpenAI's corporate drones. [...] 
 Deep Research was this for me, at first. Some of its summaries were just pleasant to read, they felt so in</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 01:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T01:50:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musictown</title>
      <link>https://doc.searls.com/2025/03/09/musictown/</link>
      <description>The final round of the 10th Indiana International Guitar Competition just happened, here, as well as in the natural world. We saw it in the latter. Amazing performances. Bloomington is a fabulous small city anyway, but the Jacobs School of Music—and the whole music scene here—puts Bloomington over the top for us. In addition to […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 01:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T01:12:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Websites With Lots of Little HTML Pages</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/10/building-websites-with-llms/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Building Websites With Lots of Little HTML Pages 
Jim Nielsen coins a confusing new acronym - LLMS for (L)ots of (L)ittle ht(M)l page(S). He's using this to describe his latest site refresh which makes extensive use of cross-document view transitions - a fabulous new progressive enhancement CSS technique that's supported in Chrome and Safari (and hopefully soon in Firefox). 
 
 With cross-document</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-10T00:38:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 journalist’s digital security checklist</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-2025-journalists-digital-security-checklist</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Davis Erin Anderson and Dr. Martin Shelton at the Freedom of the Press Foundation]  These security tips are designed for journalists but are good ideas for everyone (and particularly activists or anyone working in a sensitive field):   &quot;In tumultuous times, we believe in being prepared, not scared. Sound digital security practice often involves forming and relying on good habi</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 21:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-09T21:44:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feedback loops</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/feedback-loops</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Joe Woods]  This is good, actionable advice:   &quot;As an engineering leader, you should be constantly working to reduce the amount of time it takes to complete one cycle of a feedback loop.  What do I mean by feedback loop? This is anything where you do work, and then you need to await a result in order to be able to do more work.&quot;   Some of these will be easier than others to ob</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 17:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-09T17:42:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fediverse House</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/fediverse-house</link>
      <description> 
 If you're in Austin, visiting Fediverse House at 412 Congress Ave today and tomorrow is what you need to be doing.  You don’t need a&amp;nbsp;SXSW ticket - just show up and meet some of the key people building and thinking about the most important thing happening on the web right now.  Unfortunately, I’m preparing for a team summit in New York this week, so I’m unable to attend. The good news for me</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 15:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-09T15:49:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quoting Steve Yegge</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/9/steve-yegge/#atom-everything</link>
      <description>  I've been using Claude Code for a couple of days, and it has been absolutely ruthless in chewing through legacy bugs in my gnarly old code base. It's like a wood chipper fueled by dollars. It can power through shockingly impressive tasks, using nothing but chat. [...] 
 Claude Code's form factor is clunky as hell, it has no multimodal support, and it's hard to juggle with other tools. But it does</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 15:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-09T15:30:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wolf-h3-viewer.glitch.me</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/9/h3-viewer/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> wolf-h3-viewer.glitch.me 
Neat interactive visualization of Uber's H3 hexagonal geographical indexing mechanism. 
  
 Here's the source code. 
 Why does H3 use hexagons? Because Hexagons are the Bestagons: 
 
 When hexagons come together, they form three-sided joints 120 degrees apart. This, for the least material, is the most mechanically stable arrangement. 
 
 Only triangles, squares, and hexag</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 14:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-09T14:51:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What's new in the world of LLMs, for NICAR 2025</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/nicar-llms/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> I presented two sessions at the NICAR 2025 data journalism conference this year. The first was this one based on my review of LLMs in 2024, extended by several months to cover everything that's happened in 2025 so far. The second was a workshop on Cutting-edge web scraping techniques, which I've written up separately. 

 Here are the slides and detailed notes from my review of what's new in LLMs, </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 23:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T23:19:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cutting-edge web scraping techniques at NICAR</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/cutting-edge-web-scraping/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Cutting-edge web scraping techniques at NICAR 
Here's the handout for a workshop I presented this morning at NICAR 2025 on web scraping, focusing on lesser know tips and tricks that became possible only with recent developments in LLMs. 
 For workshops like this I like to work off an extremely detailed handout, so that people can move at their own pace or catch up later if they didn't get everythi</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 19:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T19:25:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politico: 5 Questions for Jack Clark</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/questions-for-jack-clark/#atom-everything</link>
      <description> Politico: 5 Questions for Jack Clark 
I tend to ignore statements with this much future-facing hype, especially when they come from AI labs who are both raising money and trying to influence US technical policy. 
 Anthropic's Jack Clark has an excellent long-running newsletter which causes me to take him more seriously than many other sources. 
 Jack says: 
 
 In 2025 myself and @AnthropicAI will </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 17:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T17:13:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World's first 'body in a box' biological computer uses human brain cells with silicon-based computing</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/worlds-first-body-in-a-box-biological-computer-uses-human</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Kunal Khullar at Tom's Hardware]  Straight into my nightmares:   &quot;Australian biotech company Cortical Labs has introduced what it claims to be &quot;the world’s first code deployable biological computer,&quot; which combines human brain cells with traditional silicon-based computing. The system, known as CL1, was presented at the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona and is being explored </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T13:47:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Specified Algorithms Specification Addressing Area Director Feedback</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2627</link>
      <description>Orie Steele and I want to thank Deb Cooley for her Area Director review of the “Fully-Specified Algorithms for JOSE and COSE” specification. Addressing it simplified the exposition, while preserving the essence of what the draft accomplishes. Specifically, the resulting draft significantly simplified the fully-specified encryption description and removed the appendix on polymorphic ECDH algorithms.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 05:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T05:44:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEDI Details for Identity Nerds</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/sedi-details-for-identity-nerds-e1949af5cc30?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> This post is a more technical follow-up to the post announcing the passing of SB 260 in Utah, establishing the principles for state-endorsed digital identity (SEDI). While SEDI does not mandate any particular technology, its mandated principles close the door for technologies that do not comply, and open the door for technologies that do. This article explores what SEDI makes technically possible,</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-08T00:15:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utah Blazes New Trail for SSI: SEDI</title>
      <link>https://rufftimo.medium.com/utah-blazes-new-trail-for-ssi-sedi-441d8ce65ab8?source=rss-11906019170a------2</link>
      <description> Finally!  On March 4, 2025, the Utah legislature unanimously passed SB 260, a groundbreaking digital identity bill that carries this description:  “This bill enacts provisions related to a state-endorsed digital identity” (SEDI).  Now it’s off to the governor for signature, who has been publicly positive about it. Huge credit to Sen. Cullimore, the bill’s sponsor, and Christopher Bramwell, the sta</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T23:30:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/03/07/making-the-fediverse-more-accessible-with-claude-3-7-sonnet/</link>
      <description>A few years ago I abandoned Twitter in favor of Mastodon. Recent events validate that choice and underscore the strategic importance of a decentralized fediverse that can’t be owned by a single corporate or state actor. But while Mastodon meets my needs, much of the Twitter diaspora has gone to Bluesky. That’s fine for now … Continue reading Making the Fediverse More Accessible With Claude 3.7 Sonn</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-07T17:54:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #126: Startup asks for a lot, offers little → struggles to hire</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-126</link>
      <description>Also: Cloufflare’s self-critical, transparent postmortem, additional signs of Big Tech becoming more cutthroat, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-06T17:41:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Techdirt Is Now A Democracy Blog (Whether We Like It Or Not)</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/why-techdirt-is-now-a-democracy-blog-whether-we-like</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mike Masnick at Techdirt]  Mike Masnick on why tech journalism has a huge part to play in decoding current events right now:   &quot;We’ve spent decades documenting how technology and entrepreneurship can either strengthen or undermine democratic institutions. We understand the dangers of concentrated power in the digital age. And we’ve watched in real-time as tech leaders who once</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 14:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-06T14:09:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s USCIS wants to review all prospective citizens’ social media accounts</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/trumps-uscis-wants-to-review-all-prospective-citizens-social-media</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Gaby Del Valle at The Verge]  This is dystopian:   &quot;The Trump administration may soon demand the social media accounts of people applying for green cards, US citizenship, and asylum or refugee status. US Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) — the federal agency that oversees legal migration, proposed the new policy in the Federal Register this week — calling this infor</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 02:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-06T02:44:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design-first software engineering: Craft – with Balint Orosz</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/design-first-software-engineering</link>
      <description>Balint Orosz, founder of Craft, shares his journey from startup to award-winning app, discussing software design, frontend vs. backend priorities, and local-first computing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 18:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T18:18:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About my Tesla</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/about-my-tesla</link>
      <description> 
 So, yes, hi, I have a Tesla. It’s a long range Model 3 which I bought in 2021.  After a career spent working on open source and mission-drive projects — right now I work for a non-profit newsroom; once upon a time I built a social networking platform for education — it might shock you to learn that I am not rich. I have never had a significant tech company equity package; I have never seen the b</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 14:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T14:47:48+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How DOGE’s IRS Cuts Could Cost More Than DOGE Will Ever Save</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/how-doges-irs-cuts-could-cost-more-than-doge-will</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Andy Kroll at ProPublica]  Cutting the IRS has nothing to do with government efficiency:   &quot;Unlike with other federal agencies, cutting the IRS means the government collects less money and finds fewer tax abuses. Economic studies have shown that for every dollar spent by the IRS, the agency returns between $5 and $12, depending on how much income the taxpayer declared. A 2024 </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 14:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T14:19:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Okay, You Try Thinking of a Better Way to Protest President Nyarlathotep’s Terror Telecast</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/okay-you-try-thinking-of-a-better-way-to-protest</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Andrew Paul at McSweeney's]   &quot;I gotta be honest with you, though. I think the Outer God got the message loud and clear. Our tasteful combination of fashionably coordinated clothes, tiny paper fans with BAD! printed on them, and some of our sternest looks of disapproval to date really drove home the fact that we aren’t jazzed by all this cosmic cruelty. I can’t think of anythi</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 13:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T13:32:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extension Ecosystem Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/03/extension-ecosystem-summit/</link>
      <description>We’re doing it again! The PostgreSQL Extension Ecosystem Summit returns to
PGConf.dev. We’ll again be looking at indexing, discovery, packaging, and
core support. And we’ll once again be hosting a series of “Mini Summits”
leading up to the event. Join us!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-05T00:35:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trimodal Nature of Tech Compensation in the US, UK and India</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/trimodal</link>
      <description>Deepdive into the distribution of software engineering compensation, based on more than 20,000 data points from Levels.fyi</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-04T16:40:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decentralizing the cloud: separating software from infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/rethinking-the-cloud-separating-software-from-infrastructure</link>
      <description> 
   Much of the last decade or two of the tech industry has been dominated by the idea of&amp;nbsp;the cloud: the simple, powerful idea that all of your applications and data can be accessed from any device with an internet connection. Enterprise businesses around the world have decommissioned server rooms in favor of subscribing to services maintained by other people, reducing overheads of all kinds.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-04T16:17:56+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2621</link>
      <description>Emil Lundberg and I have published the COSE Algorithms for Two-Party Signing specification. Its abstract is: This specification defines COSE algorithm identifiers used when the signing operation is performed cooperatively between two parties. When performing two-party signing, the first party typically hashes the data to be signed and the second party signs the hashed data […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 02:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-04T02:47:38+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Viable Startup Operations</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/minimum-viable-startup-operations</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Jean Hsu and Jen Dennard]  This is a good inaugural post from two people who really have lived the startup operations life many times over:   &quot;We think of the operations part of a startup like getting dinner on the table. Sure, some days, you might try a new and involved recipe, but most days, you just need to get something good enough on the table FAST, so that you can devote</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 22:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T22:41:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCC at the 2025 1EdTech Digital Credentials Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/dcc-at-the-2025-1edtech-digital-credentials-summit-e506d7c8051c?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> LCW Experience Badge &amp;amp; Introduction to Open Badges 3.0 Course at Participate  This week is the 2025 Digital Credentials Summit hosted by the organization that shepherds the Open Badges 3.0 standard. This is a great space to meet with implementers, educators, technologists, funders, and policy makers from all over the world to&amp;nbsp;connect.  I will be attending this year and have the privilege </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:13:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Badges 3.0 Basics: Watch, Learn, and Earn on Participate</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/open-badges-3-0-basics-watch-learn-and-earn-on-participate-660c2bf922dd?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Join the Digital Credentials Consortium Learning&amp;nbsp;Hub  The Digital Credential has started a series of short posts explaining the characteristics and trust models of W3C Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0. To accompany this series, we collaborated with our colleagues as Participate to create the The Digital Credentials Consortium Learning Hub and offer a short course, “Introduction to O</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 15:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T15:12:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A future for Self Sovereign Identity?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/a-future-for-self-sovereign-identity-c237caa5e46f?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Symbolic representation of Web Security applied to&amp;nbsp;SSI. Many children in Europe grew up with the tales of Baron Münchhausen, who claims to have lifted himself and his horse out of a mire by pulling his own hair. The image is so powerful because the problem of the circular dependency is so clearly visible. In real life, circular dependencies are often far less&amp;nbsp;obvious.  Which is why the fi</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The LCW Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/the-lcw-experience-6a5bef5cca4d?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> The Digital Credentials Consortium, our team and our members, are aiming to advance the understanding &amp;amp; use of privacy-enhanced, portable, verifiable digital credentials like Open Badges 3.0. We’ve noticed that while many are interested in the opportunities LERs as digital credentials may offer, many haven’t yet experienced what it is like to claim and accept an Open Badge 3.0 credential with </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T14:14:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement Phone verification, 2FA using ASP.NET Core Identity</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/03/03/implement-phone-verification-2fa-using-asp-net-core-identity/</link>
      <description>This post shows how to implement phone (SMS) verification and two-factor authentication (2FA) using ASP.NET Core Identity. The solution integrates phone-based verification and 2FA mechanisms. The implementation uses ASP.NET Core Identity’s extensibility to incorporate SMS-based verification during user registration and login processes. SMS is no longer a recommended authentication method due to sec</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-03T06:05:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please see Soundtrack to a Coup d'Etat</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/please-see-soundtrack-to-a-coup-detat</link>
      <description> 
 It’s Oscars day! I haven’t seen very many of the nominees this year, but of the ones I have, I need to make this recommendation:  Soundtrack to a Coup d’Etat, nominated for best documentary picture, is brilliant. It’s an under-told part of American history, still highly relevant and ongoing today, told through the lens of its surprising intersection with the jazz musicians of the time. One of th</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 23:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T23:28:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warp factor 5, Mr. Sulu</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/warp-factor-5-mr-sulu</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Ghost]  Another really great update from the Ghost team about their progress implementing ActivityPub:   &quot;In our logs, that looks like our average request time dropping from 5+ seconds, to ~50ms:  [...] There are still a few places where we're using the old database architecture that remain slow. We're not out of the woods just yet. Within the next couple of weeks, though, the</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 22:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T22:43:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The web was always about redistribution of power. Let’s bring that back.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-web-was-always-about-redistribution-of-power-lets-bring-that-back-d3d855509f9c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s time to rekindle the movement.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T15:00:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The web was always about redistribution of power. Let's bring that back.</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-web-was-always-about-redistribution-of-power-lets-bring</link>
      <description> 
   I’ve seen a lot&amp;nbsp;of this sentiment lately, and can relate:   I miss being excited by technology. I wish I could see a way out of the endless hype cycles that continue to elicit little more than cynicism from me. The version of technology that we’re mostly being sold today has almost nothing to do with improving lives, but instead stuffing the pockets of those who already need for nothing. </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-02T15:00:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GSA eliminates 18F</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/gsa-eliminates-18f</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Natalie Alms at Nextgov/FCW]  I'd say this was an unbelievable own-goal. But, unfortunately, it's believable:   &quot;The General Services Administration deleted 18F, a government tech consultancy that helps other agencies with their technology, early Saturday morning.  The office has been deemed “non-critical,” Thomas Shedd, director of GSA’s Technology Transformation Services, em</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 15:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-03-01T15:31:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groups helping LGBTQ+ victims of violence could face loss of federal funds</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/groups-helping-lgbtq-victims-of-violence-could-face-loss-of</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Mel Leonor Barclay and Jasmine Mithani at The 19th]  The impact of this will be severe:   &quot;Organizations that provide services to LGBTQ+ victims of domestic and intimate partner violence expect much of the federal funding they rely on to dry up as the Trump administration’s executive orders target the work they have been carrying out for years.  [...] Groups that focus specifi</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T16:37:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-Washington Post editor Marty Baron rebukes Bezos: ‘betrayal of free expression’</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/ex-washington-post-editor-marty-baron-rebukes-bezos-betrayal-of-free</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Anna Betts in The Guardian]  He's not wrong:   &quot;Marty Baron, a highly regarded former editor of the Washington Post, has said that Jeff Bezos’s announcement that the newspaper’s opinion section would narrow its editorial focus was a “betrayal of the very idea of free expression” that had left him “appalled”.&quot;   &quot;Democracy dies in darkness&quot; indeed:   &quot;“If you’re trying to advan</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 14:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T14:51:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla’s New Terms of Service and Updated Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/mozillas-new-terms-of-service-and-updated-privacy-policy</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Bill Fitzgerald]  What a missed opportunity. As Bill Fitzgerald points out:   &quot;Mozilla has given a masterclass, yet again, in how to erode trust among people who have loved your work.&quot;   Mozilla rolled out a new terms of service and privacy policy that rolled back a key promise never to sell user data. And then complained that people were making a big deal of it.  As Bill poin</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 14:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T14:46:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of the internet is likely smaller communities, with a focus on curated experiences</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/the-future-of-the-internet-is-likely-smaller-communities-with</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Edwin Wong and Andrew Melnizek at The Verge]  This is much-needed research:   &quot;The Verge partnered with Vox Media’s Insights and Research team, along with Two Cents Insights, to better understand how American consumers are embracing this shift. The goal of the work was to redefine what online communities will be in a post-social media era of emerging AI and Google Zero. And as</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 14:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T14:40:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cambrian Explosion of OAuth and OpenID Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2615</link>
      <description>Vladimir Dzhuvinov and I led a discussion on The Cambrian Explosion of OAuth and OpenID Specifications at the 2025 OAuth Security Workshop in Reykjavík. The abstract for the session was: The number of OAuth and OpenID specifications continues to grow. At present there are 30 OAuth RFCs, two more in the RFC Editor queue, 13 […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 12:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T12:42:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>世界のデジタルIDと認証技術のトレンド：2月28日版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6772/</link>
      <description>しばらく時間が空いてしまいましたが、デジタルIDと認証技術のトレンドをお届けします。 日本 英国 EU オーストラリア アメリカ合衆国 エチオピア 新バイオメトリック・パスポートの発行が始まる。制作はTOPPANが51%の株式をもつToppan Ethiopiaが担当。パスポート…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T11:25:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 月4日 FAPIとVCの世界動向　～FAPI2.0 &amp; Verifiable Credentials~</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6731/</link>
      <description>3月4日(火) 10:00-12:40に「FAPIとVCの世界動向　～FAPI2.0 &amp;amp; Verifiable Credentials~」と題されたセミナーがFINOLABイベントスペースで開催されます。私もちょっとだけでます。 金融機関におけるKYC等にそれらデジタル資…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 06:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-28T06:32:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Im The Problem, You Might Be The Reason</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/02/if-im-problem-you-might-be-reason.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;Tune your metaphors..&amp;nbsp;             &amp;nbsp;From where I dance and glance in America...   All over the world, men and women are not having the same experience. Generational conflicts are arising, influencing everything, causing chaos to status quo, and making clear that the ability to r/w/rw is not shared equally. Computational supremacy, computational illiteracy, what does the data say? W</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T22:08:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #125: swarm of AI coding tool launches</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-125</link>
      <description>Anthropic, GitHub, and Google launch new AI coding tools for devs, DeepSeek bucks expectations by triggering higher GPU demand, VC funding down with AI funding up, and more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-27T17:15:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The man behind the Big Tech comics – with Manu Cornet</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-man-behind-the-big-tech-comics</link>
      <description>In today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I am joined by a senior software engineer and cartoonist, Manu Cornet.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T17:10:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington Post opinion chief quits as Bezos makes new editorial demands</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/2025/washington-post-opinion-chief-quits-as-bezos-makes-new-editorial</link>
      <description> 
                 
 [Brad Reed at RawStory]  This is incredibly disappointing to see:   &quot;David Shipley, who has spent the last two-and-a-half years running the Washington Post's editorial page, has stepped down from his position over new demands being made by Post owner Jeff Bezos.  In a letter sent out to staff members obtained by New York Times media reporter Ben Mullin, Bezos said that Shipley </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 15:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-26T15:59:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics for software engineers</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/robotics</link>
      <description>What does it take to build and program robots? A look into the exciting, increasingly popular field of robotics. Guest post by humanoid robot expert, Sandor Felber</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T16:12:34+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatkontrolle: EU-Bürgerbeauftragte kritisiert Drehtürwechsel von Europol-Beamten zu Chatkontrolle-Lobbyist Thorn</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/chatkontrolle-eu-buergerbeauftragte-kritisiert-drehtuerwechsel-von-europol-beamten-zu-chatkontrolle-lobbyist-thorn/</link>
      <description> Die scheidende EU-Bürgerbeauftragte Emily O’Reilly hat es auf die Beschwerde des ehemaligen Europaabgeordneten der Piratenpartei Patrick Breyer als “Missstand” bewertet, dass ein Europol-Beamter trotz potenzieller Interessenskonflikte ohne jegliche Auflagen zum … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T12:20:30+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with a Hybrid Heat Pump Water Heater</title>
      <link>https://altmode.org/2025/02/24/my-experience-with-a-hybrid-heat-pump-water-heater/</link>
      <description>In October 2023, my wife emerged from the bathroom one morning to report that we had no hot water. I found that our gas-fired, on-demand water heater had failed and was leaking a small amount. I called our plumber, who confirmed we needed a new water heater. We immediately faced the following decision: Should we […]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 01:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-25T01:16:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are political &amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers?</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/how-are-political-economic-uncertainty-impacting-real-estate-consumers/</link>
      <description> Writing that he knows “a bunch of people who held their nose and voted for Trump,” the president of HousingWire media issued this challenge on… 
The post How are political &amp;amp; economic uncertainty impacting real estate consumers? first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 16:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T16:14:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use client assertions in OpenID Connect and ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/24/use-client-assertions-in-openid-connect-and-asp-net-core/</link>
      <description>Client assertions is a method of client authentication which can be used in OpenID Connect. This provides an alternative to client secrets. This approach enhances security by using signed tokens (JWTs) to authenticate clients during the token request process or the OAuth PAR request. In ASP.NET Core, client assertions is not supported per default, a […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-24T06:43:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPIとVerifiable Credentialsに関するイベントをやります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/fapiverifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  3月頭はFintech Weekということもあり、あちこちでFintech系のイベントが開催されますね。そのうちの一つである4F（Future Frontier Fes by FINOLAB）の一コマをいただきAuthlete川崎さんと一緒にFAPIとVerifiable Credentialsの話をします。  こちらのイベントですね。  https://4f-otmcbldg.tokyo/2025-jp/       このうち、3/4の午前中のセッションです。    セッションの詳細と申し込みはこちらからしていただけます。  https://fapi-vc.peatix.com/        &amp;nbsp;私は慶應の鈴木先生と一緒に先日発行したデジタルクレデンシャルの管理要件に関するディスカッションペーパーの中身の話を解説させていただきます。みなさん色々とデジ</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-23T02:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Visit To Tulsa With Microtuble Symbolic Communication + Thoughts on DOGE Against A UPenn “Quaker Kabbalah” Backdrop</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/19/a-visit-to-tulsa-with-microtuble-symbolic-communication-thoughts-on-doge-against-a-upenn-quaker-kabbalah-backdrop/</link>
      <description>Posting this late, so I won’t be writing an introduction. As is the case for me lately, the offering is a somewhat rambling discussion that surfaces quiet a few nuggets for you to chew on.&amp;nbsp; Life in this absurdist improvisational theater might easier if we can practice the Tao of Pooh. Smile. Here’s a link [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 04:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-20T04:55:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer productivity with Dr. Nicole Forsgren (creator of DORA, co-creator of SPACE)</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/developer-productivity-with-dr-nicole</link>
      <description>Nicole is one of the foremost experts in developer productivity, and author of the book Accelerate. She details how to think about, measure &amp;amp; improve developer productivity</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T17:01:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signing Off from Uniken: Thank You for the Adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/signing-off-from-uniken-thank-you-for-the-adventure.html</link>
      <description>It’s the end of an era: after eight incredible years, it felt like the right time to close the chapter on my story at Uniken. When I joined as CTO, Uniken was an ambitious startup with a unique core technology and a vision to make a global impact. What made the ensuing journey so rewarding […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-19T15:11:43+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of the startup and scaleup hiring markets – as seen by recruiters</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/startup-market-in-2025</link>
      <description>More startups and scaleups are hiring engineers and engineering leaders. Advice for tech professionals on how to get noticed by specialist recruitment companies – from two specialist recruiters</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-18T16:45:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing a single client sign-in using parameters in Duende IdentityServer</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/17/customizing-a-single-client-sign-in-using-parameters-in-duende-identityserver/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. In the previous post, the UI was customized per […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T06:34:33+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>３月６日 FIN/SUMシンポジウムパネル「デジタル認証、デジタルIDが目指す未来の暮らし、仕事、社会」でモデレータをやります</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6674/</link>
      <description>毎年のことですが、今年もFIN/SUMに出ます。錚々たるパネリストの方々をモデレートさせていただきます。日経主催のFIN/SUMシンポジウムパネルです。 17:40-18:30 パネル デジタル認証、デジタル ID が目指す未来の暮らし、仕事、社会 セッション概要 日時 ３月６日…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March</title>
      <link>https://realestatecafe.com/multiply-tiny-house-love-story-with-million-backyard-march/</link>
      <description> After a post about a college that’s teaching students how to build their own tiny houses for just $5,000 drew a lot of attention, decided… 
The post Multiply Tiny House Love Story with Million Backyard March first appeared on Real Estate Cafe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-14T21:49:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #124: Software engineering job openings at five-year low?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-124</link>
      <description>Data from Indeed shows software developer job openings have seen the biggest decline in five years across the US. What’s the cause, and what’s next? Also: OpenAI responds to DeepSeek, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T17:37:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2月27日【緊急対談】ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 – AIメタバース時代のアイデンティティ【Digital Space Conference 2025】</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6669/</link>
      <description>「ねむ ✕ 崎村夏彦 – AIメタバース時代のアイデンティティ」 2月27日、Digital Space Conference 2025 のサイドイベントで、昨年「今年最も輝いたVTuberベスト10 【MoguLive VTuber Award 2024】で、儒烏風…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-13T06:30:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live streaming at world-record scale with Ashutosh Agrawal</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/live-streaming-at-world-record-scale</link>
      <description>In May 2023, a live streaming world record was set with 32 million concurrent viewers watching the finale of the Indian Premier League cricket finale. A chat with the architect behind this system</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T19:00:49+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Components</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/02/12/web-components/</link>
      <description>The JavaScript industrial complex won’t crumble anytime soon. But the stage is set for a return to an ecosystem of reusable components accessible to business developers, only this time based on the universal web platform and its core standards. How To Build Web Components Using ChatGPT LLM series at The New Stack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-12T12:43:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business Case for Dynamic Authorization</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/the-business-case-for-dynamic-authorization</link>
      <description>Authorization isn't just about security.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T18:31:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Science</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/02/11/bitcoin-science/</link>
      <description>  

 Bitcoin failed.  J.P. Koning notes in The end of El Salvador’s bitcoin payments experiment: 

  But here was a government that was going to champion the stuff, nullifying all of the headwinds against bitcoin in one stroke! The government meddling hypothesis would be put to test.

The Salvadoran government used a combination of sticks and carrots to kick-start adoption. First, let's list the ca</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T17:28:01+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Big Tech becoming more cutthroat?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/is-big-tech-becoming-more-cutthroat</link>
      <description>Is it the end of a golden age of Big Tech, when jobs at leading companies offered high-impact work, top compensation, and good work-life balance? More signs suggest harsh perf management is the norm</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 16:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-11T16:54:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2月26日 PwC Digital Identity Forum 2025に出演します〜「オープンファイナンスの未来とデジタルアイデンティティの重要性」</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6664/</link>
      <description>2月26日、FIN/SUM 2025の皮切りになる「PwC Digital Identity Forum 2025」に出演します。 開催日時 2025年2月26日（水）15:00～19:00（受付開始14:45） 申し込み締め切り 2025年2月25日（火）12:00 場所 東京…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 09:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T09:51:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core delegated OAuth Token Exchange access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/10/asp-net-core-delegated-oauth-token-exchange-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This blog shows how to implement a delegated OAuth 2.0 Token Exchange RFC 8693 flow in ASP.NET Core, and has a focus on access token management. It looks at how the OAuth Token Exchange can be implemented and how an application can request delegated access tokens on behalf of a user and another application, providing […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 06:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-10T06:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal For A Spring Break From Mind Viruses – March 13 to the Summer Solstice: Ground, Gather Energy, Reflect, Renew 5 Years Later</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/07/proposal-for-a-spring-break-from-mind-viruses-march-13-to-the-summer-solstice-ground-gather-energy-reflect-renew-5-years-later/</link>
      <description>I made a video today reflecting on how we manage (or don’t) our energy and how our engagement with digital information complicates our lives. I’m proposing that people consider dialing back their social media consumption to spend time reflecting on their thinking, what we have learned over the past five years, and how we can [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 02:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-08T02:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>個人情報保護委員会、「本人関与に係る規律の在り方」の部分について具体的な制度設計の方向性提示</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/02/6660/</link>
      <description>2月5日の個人情報保護委員会において、1月22日資料で事務局ヒアリング結果を踏まえ特に新たに追加した部分の多い「本人関与に係る規律の在り方」の部分(同意規制の在り方、漏えい発生時の本人通知の在り方、子供の個人情報)について具体的な制度設計の方向性を示されました。 https://…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 06:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-07T06:58:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #123: Big Tech using its distribution advantage to win in AI?</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-123</link>
      <description>Big Tech companies seem to have learned the lesson on how they became dominant in the past. So most of them are giving away AI functionality for free – even if this could be at loss for them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 17:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-06T17:15:41+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>そういえばEUDIW Architecture Reference Framework 1.5.0が出てますね</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/02/eudiw-architecture-reference-framework.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    そういえば2月4日にEUDIW ARFの1.5.0が出てますね。  https://eu-digital-identity-wallet.github.io/eudi-doc-architecture-and-reference-framework/latest/architecture-and-reference-framework-main/           GithubのCHANGELOGを見ると     The ARF is aligned with the adopted Implementing Acts, covering articles 5a and 5c of the eIDAS Regulation.&amp;nbsp;  The ARF also includes changes in response to comments provid</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T23:32:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Engineering with Chip Huyen</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/ai-engineering-with-chip-huyen</link>
      <description>On today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by Chip Huyen, a computer scientist, author of the freshly published O’Reilly book AI Engineering, and an expert in applied machine learning.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 17:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T17:06:23+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Up On Quantum Realism In Connection With Gordon Pask’s Mechanical Theatricality – Plus A “Diamond Age” Excerpt Read Aloud</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/05/follow-up-on-quantum-realism-in-connection-with-gordon-pasks-mechanical-theatricality-plus-a-diamond-age-excerpt-read-aloud/</link>
      <description>This is a follow up to yesterday’s video reiterating my thoughts about Live Action Role Play with encoded artefacts as an example of extended mind and possible future inter-dimensional information processing system. The talk goes along with two earlier talks Jason and I did on the work of Michael Mateas here. The feature image is [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:37:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.webistemology.com/growing-democracy/</link>
      <description>There is a place, little noticed and even less understood by most Canadians, where democracy is growing stronger despite a history of violence and exploitation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T14:20:47+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Candidate Recommendation for Controlled Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2612</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group has published a Snapshot Candidate Recommendation of the Controlled Identifiers specification. This follows the five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group in December 2024. Two of these specifications, including Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE, depend upon the Controlled Identifiers spec. The planned update</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 06:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-05T06:30:13+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-platform mobile development with Expo</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/expo</link>
      <description>Expo has quietly become one of the most popular tools for cross-platform development. Why is this, and how does Expo work? A deepdive with the Expo engineering team</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T17:33:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halbguter neuer polnischer Vorschlag zur Chatkontrolle wird am Mittwoch diskutiert</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/halbguter-neuer-polnischer-vorschlag-zur-chatkontrolle-wird-am-mittwoch-diskutiert/</link>
      <description> Polen, das derzeit den Vorsitz im EU-Rat innehat, schlägt eine wichtige Änderung des viel kritisierten EU-Vorschlags zur Chatkontrolle vor: Anstatt die generelle Durchsuchung privater Chats anzuordnen soll die Chatkontrolle wie … </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-04T10:52:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison Reflects on Joseph Gonzalez’s Theory of Quantum Realism – A Hopeful Participatory Universe Built On Love!</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/02/03/alison-reflects-on-joseph-gonzalezs-theory-of-quantum-realism-a-hopeful-participatory-universe-built-on-love/</link>
      <description>Below are Joseph Gonzalez’s responses to questions I posed about his theory of quantum realism. You can find out more at his blog bantamjoe.com. I discuss these questions in the video below starting at timestamp 20 minutes. Select links from Bantamjoe.com: The Self-Aware Circle of Consciousness: Here A Holographic Reality Designed By Consciousness, Designed For [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 23:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T23:05:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is About To Come From Inside The House</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2025/02/the-call-is-about-to-come-from-inside-the-house.html</link>
      <description>You would have to be living under a rock to have missed all the talk about Agentic AI, and how it is going to revolutionize the way we live and work. AI-powered agents will be anything and everything – from personal shopper to travel concierge, executive assistant to inventory manager, medical diagnostician to customer service […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T21:45:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple client sign-in customizations using Duende identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/02/03/multiple-client-sign-in-customizations-using-duende-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at customizing the sign-in UI and the sign-in options in an ASP.NET Core application using Duende IdentityServer and ASP.NET Core Identity. There are multiple ways of changing the look and feel of the UI for different OpenID Connect clients or different client flows. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/duende-multi-tenant Blogs in the series Setup The solution […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 06:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T06:55:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Years of Digital Identity!</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2607</link>
      <description>Kim Cameron first told me what Digital Identity is on February 1, 2005. He said that the Internet was created without an identity layer. He encouraged me “You should come help build it with me.” I’ve been at it ever since! What I wrote about digital identity a decade ago remains as true today: An […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 02:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-03T02:46:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want you to do these four things right now</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/i-want-you-to-do-these-four-things-right-now-3ea064583460?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Some simple steps to keep yourself safe.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-02-01T21:04:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>世界のデジタルIDと認証技術のトレンド：1月31日版</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/01/6651/</link>
      <description>イギリス: AIによる年齢確認 アメリカ: フィンテックでの企業買収 グローバル: デジタルトラベルクレデンシャル(DTC)の進展 アゼルバイジャン: デジタル開発コンセプト ヨーロッパ: ソーシャルメディアとデジタルIDの連携 デジタルID市場の成長 マレーシア: ブロックチェ…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 07:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-31T07:38:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pulse #122: DeepSeek rocks the tech industry</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-122-deepseek-rocks-the</link>
      <description>Almost unknown Chinese lab releases AI model that’s open, free, and as good as ChatGPT’s best models. Oh, and it’s also cheaper to operate. This has sent shockwaves through the AI sector</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T17:40:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win Stupid Prizes</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/30/win-stupid-prizes/</link>
      <description>

 Deadly D.C. Plane Crash Comes Months After Congress Ignored Warning About Traffic at Reagan Airport 

 As the new administration is playing stupid games, yesterday morning, prior to yesterday’s aviation disaster, professor Thomas Schaller cautioned:
 

 
   An FAA employee I know confirms agency already lacks sufficient air traffic controllers. The so-called “buyouts” and other attacks on federa</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-30T14:44:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a best-selling game with a tiny team – with Jonas Tyroller</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/thronefall</link>
      <description>In today’s episode of The Pragmatic Engineer, I’m joined by Jonas Tyroller, one of the developers behind Thronefall, a minimalist indie strategy game that blends tower defense and kingdom-building.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 16:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T16:50:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take 1... Solid Pods and Dids</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/take-1-solid-pods-and-dids.html</link>
      <description> My first attempt at building a decentralized app in this day and age will use Solid Pods and DIDs. The goal? A super simple “BooksWeLike” app—a place where I can review books and see what my friends are reading and enjoying.     What makes this app different is how it handles data. Unlike traditional apps where data lives in a centralized database, my app will let users store their own data in Sol</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-29T00:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking on Google search: Perplexity and Kagi</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/perplexity-and-kagi</link>
      <description>Google’s dominance of web search is being challenged by innovative, fast-moving startups. A deepdive into two promising contenders: Perplexity and Kagi</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 17:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-28T17:35:42+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1月28日(火)はPrivacy by Design Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.sakimura.org/2025/01/6641/</link>
      <description>Privacy by Design Conferenceとは Privacy by Design Conferenceは、Data Privacy Day (1月28日)頃に開催する国際カンファレンスです。 プライバシーに関わる、文化、法律、テクノロジー、ビジネス、オペレーション…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 07:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-27T07:18:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust, Least Privilege, and Just-in-Time Access</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/zero-trust-least-privilege-and-just</link>
      <description>Security professionals have long taught that organizations should limit the access individuals have in computer systems to just those privileges necessary to perform their job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-22T13:55:21+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andreessen and Horowitz’s Debrief On Their Fairshake PAC and Sunny Days Ahead For “Little Tech” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/20/andreessen-and-horowitzs-debrief-on-their-fairshake-pac-and-sunny-days-ahead-for-little-tech-under-trump/</link>
      <description>I took notes on Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz’s post-election discussion of their Fairshake pro-crypto Pac and the coming Trump presidency about two months ago, but set them aside and other topics took precedence. Given the rising craziness in the crypto space around the inauguration, I thought it was a good time to put them [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-21T03:58:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user application access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/20/asp-net-core-user-application-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>This article looks at management application access tokens in an ASP.NET Core web application. Any application with or without a user can use application access tokens as long as the application can persist the tokens in a safe way. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/token-mgmt-ui-application Blogs in this series Setup The ASP.NET Core web application authenticates using OpenID Connect […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-20T07:34:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Dance, Oscillation, And Going “Inside”</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/18/trump-dance-oscillation-and-going-inside/</link>
      <description>In this morning’s video I somehow missed the fact that the inauguration coincides with MLK Day, which is an interesting sync with the “melanin as optical material” lens. I’m going to drop a few links to old blog posts that touch on the YMCA and “out of school time learning” as as well as my [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-18T17:06:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestalt, Quakers and Carbon Trading – Do You See Faces Or A Vase?</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/17/gestalt-quakers-and-carbon-trading-do-you-see-faces-or-a-vase/</link>
      <description>In this video I draw connections between Gestalt theory and organizational development as applied to digital groupthink in the context of Christiana Figueres, a leader in the development of carbon trading, who trained at the Gestalt Institute of Cleveland. As a young woman, she attended Swarthmore College, a Quaker institution. The first wife of her [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-17T06:06:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core user delegated access token management</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2025/01/15/asp-net-core-user-delegated-access-token-management/</link>
      <description>The article looks at managing user delegated access tokens for a downstream API in an ASP.NET Core web application. There are many ways of implementing this, all with advantages and disadvantages. The tokens are requested from an OpenID Connect server using the recommended standards. In this blog, the UI access token from the application authentication […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-15T08:18:51+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Configuration Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2025/01/14/the-configuration-crisis/</link>
      <description>Perhaps, even though they are not themselves explainable, AIs can help us engineer explainable systems. But I’m not optimistic. It feels like we’re on a path to keep making systems harder for humans to configure, and we keep expanding our reliance on superhuman intelligence to do that for us. The Configuration Crisis and Developer Dependency … Continue reading The Configuration Crisis</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:23:12+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day An Evangelical Christian Convinced ChatGPT I Was A Hippy, Schwab-Aligned Sociopathic Magician</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/14/the-day-an-evangelical-christian-convinced-chatgpt-i-was-a-hippy-schwab-aligned-sociopathic-magician/</link>
      <description>What will come of large language models when they mirror unsettled psyches defined by religious hero complexes into the cloud? We do ourselves and future generations a profound disservice when we choose not to make time to comprehend and interrogate how emerging technologies and narrative flows are being deployed to steer psychological states individually and [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-14T19:00:52+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Verifiable Credentials and Open Badges 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.dcconsortium.org/explaining-verifiable-credentials-and-open-badges-3-0-34ae898b98b2?source=rss-eccb4b25c339------2</link>
      <description> Part 2: Issuing&amp;nbsp;Badges  In part one of this series, we discussed how the trust model of Open Badges 3.0 differs from earlier versions. Credentials issued as Open Badges 3.0 are based on the W3C Verifiable Credentials data model which describes how claims made online can be&amp;nbsp;proven.  To explore this trust model, let’s explore the story of Olivia who has been taking classes at a local commu</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-13T15:28:45+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is anybody out there?</title>
      <link>http://xditao.blogspot.com/2025/01/is-anybody-out-there.html</link>
      <description> Is blogging still a thing?  If you’re reading this, please comment or like it so I know.     I am, at heart, still the XDI Guy. My passion for robust, secure, and scalable distributed data management hasn’t waned. Building one of the first XDI implementations (shout-out to Markus Sabadello, who might have built the only other one), I learned a lot about the challenges and opportunities of distribu</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T16:20:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECDSAに対応したゼロ知識証明の論文がGoogleから出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/ecdsagoogle.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  AAMVAのモバイル運転免許証のガイドラインでも触れましたが、mdocやSD-JWTのリンク可能性へ対応するためには今後ゼロ知識証明が大切になります。  年末にGoogleの研究者が  Anonymous credentials from ECDSA  というタイトルでペーパーを出しています。  https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/2010    AIでイラスト生成すると色々とおかしなことになって面白いですねw    アブストラクトの中からポイントを抜粋すると、従来のBBS+では暗号スイートへの対応に関する要件が厳しかったのでレガシーで対応できるようにECDSAでもできるようにしたよ、ということのようですね。   Part of the difficulty arises because schemes in the literature,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-12T00:23:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an open web that protects us from harm</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/building-an-open-web-that-protects-us-from-harm-40a95da1d82f?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s not enough to be neutral. We must be allies.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T15:58:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI RAG with LlamaIndex, Local Embedding, and Ollama Llama 3.1 8b</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/ai-rag-with-llamaindex-local-embedding-and-ollama-llama-3-1-8b-b0620116a715?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> In this post, I cover using LlamaIndex LlamaParse in auto mode to parse a PDF page containing a table, using a Hugging Face local embedding model, and using local Llama 3.1 8b via Ollama to perform naive Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). That’s a mouthful. I won’t go into how to setup Ollama and Llama 3.1 8b; this post assumes it is&amp;nbsp;running.  First off, you can find the code for this in m</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-11T14:31:06+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gregg Braden Led Me To Share My Thoughts on Quantum Coherence, Collective Computing, and Tokenized Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://wrenchinthegears.com/2025/01/10/how-gregg-braden-led-me-to-share-my-thoughts-on-quantum-coherence-collective-computing-and-tokenized-spirituality/</link>
      <description>This is a video I posted yesterday. And a follow up to clarify certain points. Sorry, I guess the youtube AI choose the “hands up” screenshot for the preview image. I do talk a lot with my hands. Here is a link to Joseph Gonzalez’s blog post on emergent information communication systems. Here are two [...]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-10T06:34:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorization Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/authorization-matters</link>
      <description>In 2013, poor authorization practices led to one of the largest data breaches in history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T19:36:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sqitch 1.5.0</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/sqitch-1.5.0/</link>
      <description>Sqitch v1.5.0: out now in all the usual places!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-09T02:30:18+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hockey Trivia</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2025/01/08/hockey-trivia/</link>
      <description>  

 As I just registered for a new season of beer league hockey starting this weekend, I thought about an episode of C’est comme ça que je t’aime I recently watched which is set in 1974 Sainte-Foy, Quebec City.  Nearly all the 1974 Quebec cultural references are new to me and in this episode, there is an adventure in a hockey arena and you can pause the video in a few places and see signage in the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T16:03:05+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OYO AI</title>
      <link>http://www.moxytongue.com/2025/01/oyo-ai.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;With over 1000 AI communities deployed in 2024, the next AI cohort begins..                                   Coding, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence, Entrepreneurial Skill Development, Teacher PD,&amp;nbsp;  With mentor support of all learners, students and teachers. Unlimited learning by design: (own root)&amp;nbsp;  OYO®&amp;nbsp; AI&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;by kidOYO®&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;at OYOclass.com, Educati</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-08T12:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 books</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/46-books-5f8c47016bb2?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Every book is a portal out of here.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-07T23:29:09+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/using-llamaindex-part-1-openai-e96b3efa699a?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> Using LlamaIndex Part 1 — OpenAI  I have started to experiment with LlamaIndex for use in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) document parsing and indexing. My results were mixed on the simple page provided. This is part 1, where I make a short post on LlamaIndex with OpenAI as the LLM component. I expect part 2 to be LlamaIndex with Ollama and Llama3–8b as the LLM components.  This is a very sho</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-04T21:15:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Second Candidate Recommendation for Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2603</link>
      <description>The W3C Verifiable Credentials Working Group published the Snapshot Second Candidate Recommendation of the Securing Verifiable Credentials using JOSE and COSE specification just before the holidays. This was one of five Candidate Recommendation Snapshots published by the working group at the same time, including for the Verifiable Credentials Data Model 2.0, which I’m also an […]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-03T04:57:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should URI::mysql Switch to DBD::MariaDB?</title>
      <link>https://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=11163487</link>
      <description>Should Sqitch and URI::mysql use DBD::MariaDB instead of DBD::mysql? If so,
what are the implications for Sqitch deployment and usage?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T22:47:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New JSONPath Feature: SelectLocated</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2025/01/jsonpath-located/</link>
      <description>New in the jsonpath Go package and Playground: “Located” results that pair
selected values with normalized paths to their locations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T20:43:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intention Economyその後</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2025/01/intention-economy.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    年末にDoc SearlsがIntention Economyについて「The Real Intention Economy」というポストをしています。かなり重要なポストだと思うので読んでおいた方が良さそうです。     https://doc.searls.com/2024/12/30/the-real-intention-economy/     彼の著書は日本語にも翻訳されていますね。  https://amzn.to/3C2PX9n        さて、今回のDocのポストに戻ると、彼がIntention Economyの考え方を発表してからもう直ぐ20年が経とうとしている現在、生成AIの文脈も相まって、Intention Economy自体が脅威となりつつある、という話です。     Intention Economyで検索すると結構ヤバ目の結果が返</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2025-01-01T03:06:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL/JSON Path Playground Update</title>
      <link>https://theory.github.io/sqljson/</link>
      <description>The Go SQL/JSON Playground has been updated with a fresh design and PostgreSQL
17 compatibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T20:40:32+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tintin and the fascists</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/tintin-and-the-fascists-90241c93b3c6?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    The boy reporter has a fascist origin. But something new is possible.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T16:46:24+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for tech, 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/predictions-for-tech-2025-4046a6331cb9?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It’s going to be a hard year.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-31T15:26:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>366/366 !!!</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/366366.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  ついにこの日が来ました。           去年の正月休みに某猫とのチキンレースが始まってしまったので収まりがつかなくなって惰性で描き続けていましたが気がついたら本当に1年経ってしまいました。  ↓某猫のポスト 
  ふじえさん、やっぱりやっとるな！ 毎日記事を書く366チャレンジや！ これ絶対やっとるぞ！ — 👹秋田の猫🐱 (@ritou) January 4, 2024  
    最初のうちは割と実装してみよう！的なポストが多かったのですが、中盤〜後半は忙しくなりすぎたこともあり読んでみようシリーズが大半を占めてしまったのは反省です。  ということで振り返ってみましょう。  1月のポストはこんな感じです。     この頃は結構作ってますね。まぁ、冬休みが暇だったので実装し始めたのがきっかけだったので。  あとは1月はOpenID Summit Tokyo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T23:11:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soll ich der elektronischen Patientenakte widersprechen und wie geht das?</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/soll-ich-der-elektronischen-patientenakte-widersprechen-und-wie-geht-das/</link>
      <description> Wenn du gesetzlich krankenversichert bist, wird deine Krankenkasse bis 15. Januar 2025 eine elektronische Patientenakte für dich einrichten – es sei denn, du widersprichst. Das gilt auch für private Krankenversicherungen, die … </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-30T10:32:16+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑧</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01040135091.html</link>
      <description> &amp;nbsp;こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだまだプライバシーの章が続きます。  4.5.&amp;nbsp;DELETING MDL INFORMATION FROM A DEVICE   An mDL holder must have the capability to delete the mDL holder’s mDL from the mDL holder’s device. Such deletion:      Must delete all mDL information, log information, and any metadata (e.g. settings) that could impart information </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-29T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑦</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_02108542609.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     引き続き4章のプライバシーの部分を読んでいきます。  4.3.&amp;nbsp;PROTECTING DATA   It is up to Issuing Authorities to ensure that all mDL data stored on the mDL holder’s device is adequately protected. As standards in this respect are still under development, each Issuing Authority should take great care to ensure that the design of its</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-28T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑥</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_28.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        ようやく4章の「PRIVACY AND SECURITY」に入ります。4章も結構長いんですよね。。。ただ、結構重要な章なので細かくみていきたいと思います。     4.1.&amp;nbsp;INTRODUCTION   The privacy of an mDL holder has been paramount in the mDL design process from the start. Care was and is being taken in all the work to ensure that methods and means are available to protect mDL h</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T21:57:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a framework for living well</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/creating-a-framework-for-living-well-4aafe427c74b?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Drawing upa North Star for building my life  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-27T17:06:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 Foundation: SDO Accreditation</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/26/web-7-0-foundation-sdo-accreditation/</link>
      <description>The Web 7.0 Foundation is a relatively new organization, incorporated in Canada on May 1, 2023². It focuses on developing specifications and standards for a unified software and hardware ecosystem aimed at building resilient, trusted, and decentralized systems¹³. Source: Conversation … Continue reading →</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T23:05:15+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む⑤</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0938402867.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     まだ３章が続きますが今回で３章は終わりです。     3.6.&amp;nbsp;IACA ROOT CERTIFICATE   In Table B.1 of ISO/IEC 18013-5, on the table row for the “ISSUER” certificate component, replace:     stateOrProvinceName is optional. If this element is present, the element shall also be present in the end-entity certificates and hold the same va</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-26T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む④</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_01062834414.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。        引き続き３章を読んでいきます。  3-3.&amp;nbsp;PORTRAIT IMAGE   The portrait image is the primary means by which an mDL is matched to the person presenting the mDL in an attended transaction. The portrait image therefore needs to be of suitable quality for this purpose. ISO/IEC 18013-5 requires the portrait to comply with Ann</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-25T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む③</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_0833807043.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は３章のISO/IEC 18013-5 QUALIFICATIONSです。  3.1. INTRODUCTION   Issuing authorities electing to follow the guidance in this document must adhere to ISO/IEC 18013-5, including as qualified in this document.    本文書のガイダンスに従うことを選択した発行局は、本文書で修飾されている場合を含め、ISO/IEC 18013-5 を遵守しなければならない。   3.2.&amp;nbsp;AAMVA MDL DATA ELEMEN</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-24T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む②</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license_24.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  引き続きAAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいきます。     今回は２章のmDL Solution Overviewを見ていきます。   An mDL can be described as leveraging a mobile device to transfer (or cause to be transferred) driver’s license information to an mDL verifier, who cryptographically authenticates the information using the Issuing
Authority’s public key. A visual rendering of a DL on a mo</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-23T22:52:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AAMVAのMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelinesを読む①</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/aamvamobile-drivers-license.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日、用語を見たついでにAAMVAが出しているMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelines 1.4を読んでいこうと思います。          こちらが原文です。     まずはIntroductionから。   The AAMVA Joint Mobile Driver’s License (mDL) Working Group (WG) has been active around mobile identification since 2012. As the mDL evolves, the mDL WG continues to identify and address topics on which guidance to Issuing Authorities can be helpful. T</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSONTree Module and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/12/jsontree/</link>
      <description>I’m happy to announce the release of the JSONTree Go module and Wasm-powered
in-browser playground.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 21:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T21:33:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Sovereign Identity: Over before it started?</title>
      <link>https://ggreve.medium.com/self-sovereign-identity-over-before-it-started-661b4b0dbdc6?source=rss-f390f7bc98b4------2</link>
      <description>Web security, symbolized Monty Pythons parrot sketch is an all time classic because it plays on a very human experience of being defenseless when someone is just blatantly refusing to acknowledge the obvious. Shared reality is a matter of perception, not objective observation. Supported also by various mental biases, including the sunk cost fallacy, and the desire to agree with people we perceive a</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T19:13:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID for Verifiable Credentials IssuanceのPublic Review期間が始まりました</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/openid-for-verifiable-credentials.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日のOpenID for Verifiable Presentationにつづき、いよいよ始まりました。ついにOpenID for Verifiable Credential Issuanceも2nd Implementer's Draftです。        https://openid.net/public-review-period-for-proposed-second-implementers-draft-of-openid-for-verifiable-credential-issuance/  こんなスケジュールです。    Implementer's Draft public review period: Friday, December 20, 2024 to Sunday, February 2, 2025 (45 days)  Imple</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-22T01:04:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ついに発売へ。デジタルアイデンティティのすべて</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post_21.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    週末に家に帰ったら先行して届いていました。12月27日に発売になる「デジタルアイデンティティのすべて」です。  原著と比べると少しだけ大きいですね。        こちらから予約注文できますのでどうぞ。  https://amzn.to/3P9KS2e        ついでにSoftware Designの最新号も届いていましたし、年末年始はアイデンティティとパスキーざんまいですね！        1月末には「パスキーのすべて」も発売されますので、体（頭）をあっためておきましょう。  https://amzn.to/3ZHQohg    </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-21T09:58:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Water is Death</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/12/20/no-water-is-death/</link>
      <description>

 “Extermination &amp;amp; Acts of Genocide”: Human Rights Watch on Israel Deliberately Depriving Gaza of Water 

 AMY GOODMAN: So, can I ask you, Bill Van Esveld, is this the first time that Human Rights Watch is accusing Israel of genocide in Gaza? 

 BILL VAN ESVELD: This is the first time that we’ve made a finding of genocidal acts in Gaza. It is not an accusation that we level lightly. We have no</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-20T15:06:17+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>モバイル運転免許証に関する用語を見ていきます</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/blog-post.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    こちらにも書いた通り、11月にAAMVAからMobile Drivers License Implementation Guidelineの1.4がでました。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/mobile-drivers-licensemdl.html          読んでいてそういえば一般的じゃない言葉ばっかり使ってるよなぁ、と思うのでまずはTerminologyを見ておきましょう。         そもそも論のAAMVAです。    American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators   の略ですね。米国自動車管理者協会と訳されるようです。この辺の資料によると。&amp;nbsp;     EDL。enhanced driver licenseの略ですね。日本語だと</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-19T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>デジタルIDに関するグローバルの動向</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/id.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    OpenID FoundationのブログでElizabethが各国のデジタルIDに関する最近のトピックスを取り上げていますので紹介したいと思います。もちろん日本も含まれています。  https://openid.net/digital-identity-news-round-up-13-dec-2024/             キプロス   デジタル・シチズンとして知られるモバイル・デジタルIDアプリを開始した。  このアプリでは、バイオメトリクスIDカード、運転免許証、自動車の路上使用適格性証明書などのデジタル文書をモバイルで保持することができる。また、QRコードを使ってデジタル認証することもできる  https://www.biometricupdate.com/202412/cyprus-launches-digital-citizen-mobile</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAPI2.0の最終化に向けたPublic Reviewが始まります</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/fapi20public-review.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  FAPI2.0のSecurity Profile and Attacker Modelに関する仕様の最終化に関するPublic Review期間が始まっていますね。  https://openid.net/public-review-for-proposed-final-fapi-2-0-specifications/        今後はこんなスケジュールで進むようです。    Final Specification public review period: Monday, December 9, 2024 to Friday, February 7, 2025 (60 days)  Final Specification vote announcement: Saturday, January 25, 2025  Final Specification e</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-18T00:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumでの登壇内容を紹介します</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/taiwan-digital-identity-wallet.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先週はTaiwan Digital Identity Wallet International Forumで登壇してきましたので、キーノートとしてお話した内容をメモしておきたいと思います。  イベントについてはこちら  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/11/taiwan-digital-wallet-international.html          自己紹介は置いておいて、テーマは相互運用性でした。    As you know, the Digital Identity Wallet has recently become an emerging topic in the digital identity space. For example, the European Committee has started im</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph from Wikipedia in Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/building-a-knowledge-graph-from-wikipedia-in-neo4j/</link>
      <description>https://guides.neo4j.com/wiki https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/cats.csv?raw=true https://github.com/jbarrasa/datasets/blob/master/wikipedia/data/rels.csv?raw=true</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T18:06:59+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Songwriter/Performer Use Case: DID Method Candidates</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/12/16/toronto-songwriter-performer-use-case-did-method-candidates/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 10:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-16T10:02:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>年明けはデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WG：活動報告会から</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/wg.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     年明け1/14はデジタルアイデンティティ人材育成推進WGの活動報告会があります。  https://openid.connpass.com/event/339259/       例の本が年末に販売されることもあり、翻訳を担当したメンバーから苦労話など聞ける良い機会になると思いますのでぜひご来場ください。    </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-15T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>今年もKim Cameronアワードのノミネートが始まっています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/kim-cameron.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  これまで何度かポストした、Kim CameronアワードやVittorio Bertocciアワードですが、今年もKim Cameronアワードのノミネートが始まりました。  https://digitalidadvancement.org/awards-and-grants/kim/2025-kca/           今後のスケジュールはこんな感じなので、我こそは！という方は申請してみてはいかがでしょうか？    December 11: Call for Applications Opens  January 21: Call for Applications Closes  January 31: Awardees Notified  February 7: Awardee Confirmation of Acceptance Due  30 Days</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-14T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth Security Workshopの参加登録が始まっています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/oauth-security-workshop.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    先日お知らせした通り次回のOAuth Security Workshopはアイスランドで開催です。  https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/09/oauth-security-workshop.html     ということで参加登録が開始されていますので申し込みましょう！  https://oauth.secworkshop.events/osw2025     なお、11月後半にレイキャビクの近くで火山の噴火があったようです。Danielに聞いたら大丈夫、との話でしたが様子を見つつ参加することになりそうですね。  一応大使館のページをみると12/9に収束した、という宣言は出ていますし。  https://www.is.emb-japan.go.jp/itpr_ja/volcano.html             </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-13T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The open social web is the future of the internet. Here’s why I’m excited.</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/the-open-social-web-is-the-future-of-the-internet-heres-why-i-m-excited-e03e3d96ad3c?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    It gives you back control.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 03:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-13T03:26:39+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Googleが公開している「４分でパスキーを理解する」動画が素晴らしい件</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/google.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。     昨日はFIDO東京セミナーでしたね。私は台北にいたので参加できませんでしたが・・・  ということで悔しいので #fido でXを追いかけていましたが、えーじさんのパート（だと思う）で触れられていたっぽい「４分でパスキーを理解する」動画が素晴らしくわかりやすいかったのでメモしておこうというポストです。     ざっくりシナリオはこんな感じでした。    長らくパスワードを使ってきたけど、難しいパスワードは覚えられないし、同じパスワードの使い回しが起きるので危ないよね  そんなあなたにGoogleはパスワードマネージャを提供しているよ！  デバイスを跨いで同期されるのでとっても便利！  でも全員がパスワードマネージャに頼っているわけじゃないよね  その前にそもそもパスワードってセキュアじゃないよ  2段階認証はセキュリティ強度を上げるけど面倒だしなぁ  そんな</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-12T20:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIDI HubワシントンD.Cサミットのレポートが出ています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/sidi-hubdc.html</link>
      <description> こんにちは、富士榮です。  先日、東京サミットのレポートが出た、という話を書いた段階ではまだワシントンDCレポートが出ていなかったので順番が逆になっちゃたなぁ、みたいなことを思っていたのですが、ポストを公開した直後にワシントンDCのレポートも公開されました。     他のレポートと同じく、こちらのページからダウンロードできますので、おいおい読んでいこうと思います。  https://sidi-hub.community/summits/    </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-11T23:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSFの相互運用イベントがGartnerサミットと並列で行われています</title>
      <link>https://idmlab.eidentity.jp/2024/12/ssfgartner.html</link>
      <description>こんにちは、富士榮です。    今週私は台湾にいるわけですが、USではGartnerサミットが開催されています。  その場でShare Signals Frameworkの相互運用検証に関するイベント（実際に実装を持ち寄って繋いでみる）が行われています。        https://openid.net/oidf-returns-to-gartner-to-showcase-shared-signals-interoperability/     過去にも何度か実施されており、非常に良い結果が出ていますので、今回も色々な実装を繋いだ結果が出てくることを楽しみにしています。  特にSSFのような仕組みは複数の事業者の実装が相互に接続できないと何の意味もないものなので、良い取り組みだと思います。     そういえば、Identity Dance Advent Calendarの中でGoogle</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-10T22:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra External ID with an Auth0 OpenID Connect identity provider</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/12/09/using-entra-external-id-with-an-auth0-openid-connect-identity-provider/</link>
      <description>This post looks at implementing an Open ID Connect identity provider in Microsoft Entra External ID. Auth0 is used as the identity provider and an ASP.NET Core application is used to test the authentication. Microsoft Entra External ID federates to Auth0. Client code: https://github.com/damienbod/EntraExternalIdCiam Microsoft Entra External ID supports federation using OpenID Connect and was […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-09T05:39:40+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrity Properties for Federations</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2597</link>
      <description>I’m writing to highly recommend the article “How to link an application protocol to an OpenID Federation 1.0 trust layer” by Vladimir Dzhuvinov. In it, he defines two kinds of integrity for Federations, and describes how to achieve them: Federation Integrity, which is defined as: This ensures mutual trust between two entities is established always […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 02:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-07T02:08:28+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using ASP.NET Core with Azure Key Vault</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/12/02/using-asp-net-core-with-azure-key-vault/</link>
      <description>This article looks at setting up an ASP.NET Core application to use Azure Key Vault. When deployed to Azure, it works like in the Azure documentation but when working on development PCs, some changes are required for a smooth developer experience. Code: https://github.com/damienbod/UsingAzureKeyVaultInDevelopment I develop using Visual Studio and manage multiple accounts and test environments. […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-02T06:34:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My OKRs for 2025</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/my-okrs-for-2025-aa6e286ef038?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    Using Objectives and Key Results to get through a difficult year  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T23:07:10+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three New Specs Enhancing OpenID Federation and New Contributors</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2592</link>
      <description>The OpenID Connect working group recently adopted three new specifications that build upon and provide new capabilities to OpenID Federation. But I’m not only happy about these because of the engineering benefits they bring. I’m particularly happy because they bring new active contributors to the work, specifically Michael Fraser and Łukasz Jaromin, as well as […]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 06:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-12-01T06:50:36+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Austin Indieweb at Radio Coffee</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/30/austin-indieweb-at-radio-coffee/</link>
      <description> On Wednesday 12/04 at 7pm, the Austin Indieweb Meetup returns to Radio Coffee and Beer.  Count me in. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 13:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-30T13:19:50+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 37. Multi-dimensional Overton Olive (MuDOO) as an ADKAR-enabled Change Management Framework (MuDOO-ADKAR)</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/29/model-37-multi-dimensional-overton-olive-mudoo-as-anadkar-enabled-change-management-framework-mudoo-adkar/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Also Checkout:</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T13:21:35+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 36. Overton Visual Taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/28/model-36-overton-visual-taxonomy/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Model 36. Overton Visual Taxonomy Additional Information:</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-29T01:18:53+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model 35. Overton Olive Digital Twin (#OvertonOlive #DigitalTwin)</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/27/overton-olive-overtonolive/</link>
      <description>Copyright © 2024 Michael Herman (Bindloss, Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License Model 35. #OvertonOlive #DigitalTwin (click the diagram to enlarge it) Progressive Improvement through Continuous Transformation For more background on the #OvertonOlive:</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T21:51:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadening the Definition of Identity Practitioner</title>
      <link>https://blog.talkingidentity.com/2024/11/broadening-the-definition-of-identity-practitioner.html</link>
      <description>One of the wonderful, yet also daunting, aspects of being in the Identity industry is realizing just how far-reaching and all-encompassing its scope and boundaries are. It’s why we need more than just technologists and standards wonks engaged in driving the future of this industry. I’ve been on stage at Identiverse and other conferences for […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-27T15:49:57+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RFC: Extension Packaging &amp;amp; Lookup</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/rfc-extension-packaging-lookup/</link>
      <description>A proposal to modify the PostgreSQL core so that all files required for an
extension live in a directory named for the extension, along with a search
path to find extension directories.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-25T19:14:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The social cost of mediated experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/11/24/the-social-cost-of-mediated-experience/</link>
      <description>The first time I heard a critique of mediated experience, the critic was my dad. He was an avid photographer who, during our family’s year in India, when I was a young child, used his 35mm Exacta to capture thousands of photos that became carousels of color slides we viewed for many years thereafter. It … Continue reading The social cost of mediated experience</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 04:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-25T04:25:31+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Toni Price</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/23/rip-toni-price/</link>
      <description>

 We made a roadtrip one last time to Wimberly to see her perform at the Devil’s Backbone Tavern in August 2023. 

 There was no one like Toni Price. </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 16:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-23T16:59:55+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core BFF using OpenID Connect and Vue.js</title>
      <link>https://damienbod.com/2024/11/18/asp-net-core-bff-using-openid-connect-and-vue-js/</link>
      <description>This article shows how to implement a secure web application using Vue.js and ASP.NET Core. The web application implements the backend for frontend security architecture (BFF) and deploys both technical stacks as one web application. HTTP only secure cookies are used to persist the session. OpenIddict is used as the identity provider and the token […]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-18T07:07:02+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I want from Mozilla</title>
      <link>https://benwerd.medium.com/what-i-want-from-mozilla-703cf5ce06fb?source=rss-3b16402f5b9d------2</link>
      <description>    A people-first, safe, independent web.  Continue reading on Medium »  </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 18:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-15T18:49:44+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye Twitter</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/bye-twitter/</link>
      <description>I finally deleted all my Twitter accounts, notably @theory. If you see that
username, it’s not me.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 23:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-14T23:47:29+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ein Jahr Absage an die Chatkontrolle</title>
      <link>https://www.patrick-breyer.de/ein-jahr-absage-an-die-chatkontrolle/</link>
      <description> Heute vor einem Jahr haben wir im Ausschuss für bürgerliche Freiheiten, Justiz und Inneres (LIBE) des EU-Parlaments eine fraktionsübergreifende Position gegen anlasslose Chatkontrolle beschlossen. Damit haben wir den wahnwitzigen Überwachungsplänen … </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-14T20:02:37+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 7.0 / TDW Decentralized Identifier (DID Method) Clusters Model 0.1: Specification Development Framework</title>
      <link>https://hyperonomy.com/2024/11/11/catergories-of-decentralized-identifiers-dids/</link>
      <description>Copyright (c) 2018-2024 Michael Herman (Alberta, Canada) – Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public Licensehttps://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode To learn how to join the did-methods DIF Working Group, click https://github.com/decentralized-identity/did-methods. 0. Prime Objective/Directive #Chickens, #Eggs, and #Roosters: A #NorthStar for the Global Decent</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 22:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-11T22:47:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webfinger in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/08/webfinger-in-the-wild/</link>
      <description> Today, a post in my feed included a mention and its webfinger verification threw a WebFinger::BadRequest exception: 

  Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  WebFinger::BadRequest (Bad Request):
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM 
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:79:in `fetch_and_create_mastodon_account'
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:367:in `block in create_status!'
Nov 08 09:18:49 AM  app/models/account.rb:36</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-08T15:50:26+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Identity Workshop XXXIX Report</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/internet-identity-workshop-xxxix</link>
      <description>The 39th edition of the Internet Identity Workshop wrapped up last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-08T14:39:54+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indieweb Meetup Austin today</title>
      <link>https://herestomwiththeweather.com/2024/11/06/indieweb-meetup-austin-today/</link>
      <description> After some time off IndieWeb Meetup Austin is back at Mozart’s Coffee tonight at 7pm.  I guess a few things have transpired since the last meeting so I’m looking forward to learning about what’s going on again. </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 11:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-06T11:41:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing RFC 9535 Go JSONPath and Playground</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/go-jsonpath-playground/</link>
      <description>I’ve made a RFC 9535 JSONPath JSONPath Go package, and compiled it into Wasm to
build an in-browser playground for it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T18:23:07+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYTimes Tech Guild on Strike</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/11/nytimes-tech-guild-on-strike/</link>
      <description>My former colleagues in the New York Times Tech Guild have gone on strike in response to a number of unfair labor practice violations and management’s inability to bargain in good faith.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T16:20:14+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agents Craft Hackathon and Inspiration Block</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/agents-craft-hackathon-and-inspiration-block-88c1481d3043?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description> When you want to do a hackathon but am missing the perfect&amp;nbsp;idea. Compliments of Flux.1&amp;nbsp;Schnell You likely know the saying, “Don’t let the perfect be the enemy of the good/done.” Sometimes, I have a hard time living that, and an existing effort is one example. I have registered for an AI agent hackathon, Agents Craft Hackathon. I don’t plan to be competitive but I doubt that is the goal o</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T13:18:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My IETF 121 Agenda</title>
      <link>https://aaronparecki.com/2024/11/04/7/ietf-121</link>
      <description>Here's where you can find me at IETF 121 in Dublin!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 09:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-04T09:18:03+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Create Software Diagrams With ChatGPT and Claude</title>
      <link>https://blog.jonudell.net/2024/11/02/how-to-create-software-diagrams-with-chatgpt-and-claude/</link>
      <description>Earlier efforts to diagram software with LLM assistance weren’t fruitful, but this time around things went really well. I ended up with exactly what I needed to explain the architecture of a browser extension, and along the way I learned a lot about a couple of formats — Mermaid and Graphviz — as well as … Continue reading How To Create Software Diagrams With ChatGPT and Claude</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-02T15:18:20+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VSCode and Debugging Python in Virtual Environments</title>
      <link>https://m-ruminer.medium.com/vscode-and-debugging-python-in-virtual-environments-d975125b455c?source=rss-7e85224c0a32------2</link>
      <description>AI generated image of a&amp;nbsp;beetle This post is really for me more than anyone else. I will be able to come back here and find it. If it helps you as well, then&amp;nbsp;great.  I have historically not been a Python programmer. Additionally, I have historically used Visual Studio versus VSCode. Lately, I have been doing Python in VSCode. I need to learn my way&amp;nbsp;around.  I recently found how to deb</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-11-01T12:40:46+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenID Presentations at October 2024 OpenID Workshop and IIW plus New Specifications</title>
      <link>https://self-issued.info/?p=2584</link>
      <description>I gave the following presentation on work in the OpenID Connect working group at the Monday, October 28, 2024 OpenID Workshop at Microsoft: OpenID Connect Working Group Update (PowerPoint) (PDF) I also gave this invited “101” session presentation at the Internet Identity Workshop (IIW) on Tuesday, October 29, 2024: Introduction to OpenID Connect (PowerPoint) (PDF) […]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 05:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-30T05:25:08+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGConf &amp;amp; Extension Ecosystem Summit EU 2024</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/10/pgconf-extension-summit-eu/</link>
      <description>Notes and links from the Extension Ecosystem Summit EU 2024 and my first time
at PGConf EU. Plus thoughts and photos from ancient sites and archeological
museums I visited.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 22:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-29T22:04:22+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Voting Secure?</title>
      <link>https://www.technometria.com/p/is-voting-secure</link>
      <description>I'm fairly certain that what I write here won't change the minds that need changing. But I feel like I need to make a statement anyway: your vote is secure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-10-28T21:41:58+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch: Postgres ABI and API Guidance</title>
      <link>https://justatheory.com/2024/06/abi-api-guidance/</link>
      <description>Dear Postgres extension developers: Please review and give feedback on the
proposed patch adding ABI and API guidance to the C language documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2024-06-27T18:05:04+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>